{
    "en": [
        {
            "idx": "139",
            "question": "Which U.S. national park is famed for having a supervolcano?",
            "answer": "Yellowstone National Park"
        },
        {
            "idx": "5",
            "question": "What is the traditional Southern U.S. beverage made from bourbon?",
            "answer": "Mint julep"
        },
        {
            "idx": "34",
            "question": "What major event in 1666 devastated large parts of London?",
            "answer": "The Great Fire of London"
        },
        {
            "idx": "182",
            "question": "What is the traditional Scottish dish made from sheep's stomach?",
            "answer": "Haggis"
        },
        {
            "idx": "33",
            "question": "What is the main theme of the novel 'To Kill a Mockingbird' by Harper Lee?",
            "answer": "Racial injustice and moral growth"
        },
        {
            "idx": "252",
            "question": "Which U.S. President is associated with the New Deal?",
            "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "179",
            "question": "Which U.S. amendment provides for the right to bear arms?",
            "answer": "The 2nd Amendment"
        },
        {
            "idx": "186",
            "question": "Which U.S. city is famous for its Mardi Gras celebration?",
            "answer": "New Orleans, Louisiana"
        },
        {
            "idx": "168",
            "question": "What is the traditional American dessert served at Thanksgiving?",
            "answer": "Pumpkin pie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "271",
            "question": "Which British city is known for the invention of the steam locomotive?",
            "answer": "Newcastle"
        },
        {
            "idx": "180",
            "question": "Which British city is known for its Roman-built baths?",
            "answer": "Bath"
        },
        {
            "idx": "45",
            "question": "In which U.S. state is Mount Rushmore located?",
            "answer": "South Dakota"
        },
        {
            "idx": "285",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous speech given by Abraham Lincoln during the American Civil War?",
            "answer": "The Gettysburg Address"
        },
        {
            "idx": "221",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous British ship that carried the Pilgrims to America in 1620?",
            "answer": "The Mayflower"
        },
        {
            "idx": "209",
            "question": "What is the traditional British dish made with fish and deep-fried batter?",
            "answer": "Fish and Chips"
        },
        {
            "idx": "166",
            "question": "What is the tallest mountain in the contiguous United States?",
            "answer": "Mount Whitney, California"
        },
        {
            "idx": "214",
            "question": "Which British city is known for creating the Titanic?",
            "answer": "Belfast"
        },
        {
            "idx": "48",
            "question": "What U.S. state is known as the 'Pine Tree State'?",
            "answer": "Maine"
        },
        {
            "idx": "59",
            "question": "Which British scientist is known for his law of gravitation?",
            "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton"
        },
        {
            "idx": "54",
            "question": "What is the term used to describe the U.S. government's policy of favoring family reunification for immigrants?",
            "answer": "Chain migration"
        },
        {
            "idx": "103",
            "question": "What is the nickname of Seattle due to its coffee culture?",
            "answer": "Coffee Capital"
        },
        {
            "idx": "190",
            "question": "Who was the U.S. president during the first moon landing in 1969?",
            "answer": "Richard Nixon"
        },
        {
            "idx": "278",
            "question": "Who was the primary author of the U.S. Constitution?",
            "answer": "James Madison"
        },
        {
            "idx": "240",
            "question": "What U.S. state has the most electoral votes?",
            "answer": "California"
        },
        {
            "idx": "61",
            "question": "What U.S. state is known as 'The Land of Enchantment'?",
            "answer": "New Mexico"
        },
        {
            "idx": "62",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous British battle in which Admiral Lord Nelson died?",
            "answer": "The Battle of Trafalgar"
        },
        {
            "idx": "102",
            "question": "Which London market is famous for antiques and vintage items?",
            "answer": "Portobello Road Market"
        },
        {
            "idx": "175",
            "question": "What is the name of the region known for being the birthplace of Silicon Valley?",
            "answer": "Santa Clara Valley"
        },
        {
            "idx": "1",
            "question": "What is the name of the U.S. doctrine that opposed European colonialism in the Americas?",
            "answer": "The Monroe Doctrine"
        },
        {
            "idx": "269",
            "question": "Which U.S. city was the site of the 1963 'March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom'?",
            "answer": "Washington D.C."
        },
        {
            "idx": "151",
            "question": "Which U.S. city was the first capital under the U.S. Constitution?",
            "answer": "New York City"
        },
        {
            "idx": "93",
            "question": "Which U.S. state was the center of the gold rush in 1849?",
            "answer": "California"
        },
        {
            "idx": "23",
            "question": "Which U.S. state is known for its significant Native American population and history?",
            "answer": "Oklahoma"
        },
        {
            "idx": "116",
            "question": "Which British city is known for the invention of the steam engine?",
            "answer": "Birmingham"
        },
        {
            "idx": "245",
            "question": "Who was the American inventor known for developing the electric light bulb?",
            "answer": "Thomas Edison"
        },
        {
            "idx": "196",
            "question": "What is the name of the British law enforcement official known as a 'Bobby'?",
            "answer": "Police Officer"
        },
        {
            "idx": "80",
            "question": "Who was the first American astronaut to orbit the Earth?",
            "answer": "John Glenn"
        },
        {
            "idx": "97",
            "question": "Which British scientist is credited with inventing the World Wide Web?",
            "answer": "Sir Tim Berners-Lee"
        },
        {
            "idx": "148",
            "question": "Which London park contains Speakers' Corner?",
            "answer": "Hyde Park"
        },
        {
            "idx": "158",
            "question": "Who was the British monarch during the Crimean War?",
            "answer": "Queen Victoria"
        },
        {
            "idx": "210",
            "question": "Who was the American author known for his works about the Jazz Age?",
            "answer": "F. Scott Fitzgerald"
        },
        {
            "idx": "146",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous music festival held annually in Tennessee?",
            "answer": "Bonnaroo"
        },
        {
            "idx": "164",
            "question": "What is the name of the highest court in the United Kingdom?",
            "answer": "The Supreme Court of the United Kingdom"
        },
        {
            "idx": "104",
            "question": "Which London street is famous for medical practices?",
            "answer": "Harley Street"
        },
        {
            "idx": "15",
            "question": "Which UK city is famous for its Roman baths?",
            "answer": "Bath"
        },
        {
            "idx": "11",
            "question": "Which U.S. president introduced the policy known as 'Big Stick Diplomacy'?",
            "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "14",
            "question": "Who was the first female Prime Minister of the United Kingdom?",
            "answer": "Margaret Thatcher"
        },
        {
            "idx": "39",
            "question": "Which U.S. state is known as the 'Land of 10,000 Lakes'?",
            "answer": "Minnesota"
        },
        {
            "idx": "41",
            "question": "Which U.S. state is known for its significant Quaker population?",
            "answer": "Pennsylvania"
        },
        {
            "idx": "44",
            "question": "Which British explorer is known for his circumnavigation of the globe in the 16th century?",
            "answer": "Sir Francis Drake"
        },
        {
            "idx": "124",
            "question": "What U.S. state has the nickname 'The Last Frontier'?",
            "answer": "Alaska"
        },
        {
            "idx": "149",
            "question": "Which treaty recognized the independence of the American colonies from Britain?",
            "answer": "The Treaty of Paris, 1783"
        },
        {
            "idx": "188",
            "question": "Which U.S. city is known for its significant tech industry, often called 'Silicon Valley'?",
            "answer": "San Jose, California"
        },
        {
            "idx": "228",
            "question": "What is the nickname of Detroit due to its automotive industry?",
            "answer": "Motor City"
        },
        {
            "idx": "284",
            "question": "Which British monarch succeeded Queen Elizabeth I and was the first of the Stuart line?",
            "answer": "King James I"
        },
        {
            "idx": "100",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous American landmark also known as 'Liberty Enlightening the World'?",
            "answer": "The Statue of Liberty"
        },
        {
            "idx": "279",
            "question": "Which British political figure is known as the 'Iron Lady'?",
            "answer": "Margaret Thatcher"
        },
        {
            "idx": "25",
            "question": "Which American holiday is celebrated on the fourth Thursday of November?",
            "answer": "Thanksgiving"
        },
        {
            "idx": "184",
            "question": "Which Scottish lake is famous for its mythical monster?",
            "answer": "Loch Ness"
        },
        {
            "idx": "242",
            "question": "Which two houses make up the UK Parliament?",
            "answer": "The House of Commons and the House of Lords"
        },
        {
            "idx": "170",
            "question": "Which amendment to the U.S. Constitution granted women the right to vote?",
            "answer": "19th Amendment"
        },
        {
            "idx": "275",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous British sports car brand known for its luxury vehicles?",
            "answer": "Aston Martin"
        },
        {
            "idx": "277",
            "question": "What major British political event occurred in 2016?",
            "answer": "Brexit referendum"
        },
        {
            "idx": "3",
            "question": "What is the nickname of Philadelphia?",
            "answer": "The City of Brotherly Love"
        },
        {
            "idx": "21",
            "question": "What is the traditional American bread served in the South?",
            "answer": "Cornbread"
        },
        {
            "idx": "263",
            "question": "What is the name of the treaty that ended the Mexican-American War?",
            "answer": "The Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo"
        },
        {
            "idx": "30",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous American monument carved into Mount Rushmore?",
            "answer": "Mount Rushmore National Memorial"
        },
        {
            "idx": "173",
            "question": "Who is the patron saint of England and what day is celebrated in his honor?",
            "answer": "Saint George; St. George's Day is celebrated on April 23"
        },
        {
            "idx": "107",
            "question": "What is the traditional English dessert involving fruit and sponge cake soaked in sherry?",
            "answer": "Trifle"
        },
        {
            "idx": "192",
            "question": "What British city is known for its two famous football clubs, Manchester United and Manchester City?",
            "answer": "Manchester"
        },
        {
            "idx": "233",
            "question": "What was the main economic activity in the Southern colonies during the colonial era?",
            "answer": "Agriculture (particularly tobacco and cotton)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "78",
            "question": "What is the highest mountain in the British Isles?",
            "answer": "Ben Nevis"
        },
        {
            "idx": "243",
            "question": "Who was the British monarch during World War I?",
            "answer": "King George V"
        },
        {
            "idx": "273",
            "question": "Which U.S. state was the last to join the Union?",
            "answer": "Hawaii"
        },
        {
            "idx": "82",
            "question": "Who was the first female Supreme Court Justice in the United States?",
            "answer": "Sandra Day O'Connor"
        },
        {
            "idx": "37",
            "question": "Who was the longest-serving U.S. Supreme Court Justice?",
            "answer": "William O. Douglas"
        },
        {
            "idx": "144",
            "question": "What is the nickname of Las Vegas?",
            "answer": "Sin City"
        },
        {
            "idx": "207",
            "question": "Who was the first African American woman elected to the U.S. Congress?",
            "answer": "Shirley Chisholm"
        },
        {
            "idx": "191",
            "question": "Which British king abdicated the throne in 1936 to marry an American divorcée?",
            "answer": "King Edward VIII"
        },
        {
            "idx": "229",
            "question": "Which war was fought by the North and South regions in the United States?",
            "answer": "The Civil War"
        },
        {
            "idx": "32",
            "question": "What is the largest protected area in the United States?",
            "answer": "Wrangell-St. Elias National Park and Preserve, Alaska"
        },
        {
            "idx": "250",
            "question": "What is the main subject of the famous speech 'I Have a Dream' by Martin Luther King Jr.?",
            "answer": "Civil rights and racial equality"
        },
        {
            "idx": "132",
            "question": "Which U.S. state was purchased from Russia in 1867?",
            "answer": "Alaska"
        },
        {
            "idx": "244",
            "question": "What major U.S. event took place on July 20, 1969?",
            "answer": "The Apollo 11 moon landing"
        },
        {
            "idx": "259",
            "question": "In which city was the first successful airplane flight by the Wright Brothers made?",
            "answer": "Kitty Hawk, North Carolina"
        },
        {
            "idx": "232",
            "question": "What U.S. state has the most national parks?",
            "answer": "California"
        },
        {
            "idx": "117",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous U.S. military academy established in 1802?",
            "answer": "West Point (United States Military Academy)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "46",
            "question": "What is the name of the process by which the British territories gained their independence?",
            "answer": "Decolonization"
        },
        {
            "idx": "69",
            "question": "Which British explorer is known for his voyages to the Pacific Ocean?",
            "answer": "Captain James Cook"
        },
        {
            "idx": "75",
            "question": "What is the name of the river that flows through Liverpool?",
            "answer": "The River Mersey"
        },
        {
            "idx": "81",
            "question": "Which U.S. President signed the Civil Rights Act of 1964?",
            "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "60",
            "question": "What is the largest island in the contiguous United States?",
            "answer": "Long Island, New York"
        },
        {
            "idx": "147",
            "question": "What is the name of the historic agreement signed between the British government and Irish nationalists in 1998?",
            "answer": "The Good Friday Agreement"
        },
        {
            "idx": "159",
            "question": "What U.S. state is known for its Bourbon production?",
            "answer": "Kentucky"
        },
        {
            "idx": "205",
            "question": "Who is known for making the first telephone call?",
            "answer": "Alexander Graham Bell"
        },
        {
            "idx": "235",
            "question": "Who wrote the Declaration of Independence?",
            "answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "130",
            "question": "Which treaty ended the American Revolutionary War?",
            "answer": "The Treaty of Paris, 1783"
        },
        {
            "idx": "153",
            "question": "What is the name of the U.S. Supreme Court case that legalized abortion in 1973?",
            "answer": "Roe v. Wade"
        },
        {
            "idx": "215",
            "question": "Which act of Parliament established Protestantism in England?",
            "answer": "The Act of Supremacy, 1534"
        },
        {
            "idx": "36",
            "question": "What is the capital city of the United States?",
            "answer": "Washington D.C."
        },
        {
            "idx": "171",
            "question": "Which UK cathedral has the tallest spire in Britain?",
            "answer": "Salisbury Cathedral"
        },
        {
            "idx": "7",
            "question": "What is the name of the largest island in the United States?",
            "answer": "Hawaii (Big Island)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "226",
            "question": "What is the name of the sea that separates Great Britain from continental Europe?",
            "answer": "The English Channel"
        },
        {
            "idx": "220",
            "question": "What landmark legislation was passed in 1965 to outlaw racial discrimination in voting?",
            "answer": "The Voting Rights Act of 1965"
        },
        {
            "idx": "140",
            "question": "Who was the U.S. president during the majority of World War II?",
            "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "224",
            "question": "What is the largest national park in England?",
            "answer": "The Lake District National Park"
        },
        {
            "idx": "42",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous American landmark that is a symbol of freedom and democracy?",
            "answer": "The Liberty Bell"
        },
        {
            "idx": "8",
            "question": "Which U.S. president signed the Civil Rights Act of 1964 into law?",
            "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "90",
            "question": "What is the name of the British royal residence located in Berkshire?",
            "answer": "Windsor Castle"
        },
        {
            "idx": "211",
            "question": "What is the name of the Queen's official London residence?",
            "answer": "Buckingham Palace"
        },
        {
            "idx": "239",
            "question": "What major event did the Wall Street Crash of 1929 lead to?",
            "answer": "The Great Depression"
        },
        {
            "idx": "51",
            "question": "What is the name of the British series of awards for excellence in film and television?",
            "answer": "The BAFTA Awards"
        },
        {
            "idx": "162",
            "question": "Which U.S. city is known as the home of the blues music?",
            "answer": "Memphis, Tennessee"
        },
        {
            "idx": "137",
            "question": "What is the name of the British television series based on the reign of Queen Elizabeth II?",
            "answer": "The Crown"
        },
        {
            "idx": "83",
            "question": "Who was the British monarch during the signing of the Magna Carta?",
            "answer": "King John"
        },
        {
            "idx": "58",
            "question": "Which U.S. city is known for its pivotal role in the American Revolution?",
            "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts"
        },
        {
            "idx": "286",
            "question": "What is the busiest airport in the United States?",
            "answer": "Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta International Airport"
        },
        {
            "idx": "123",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous British art gallery located on the River Thames?",
            "answer": "Tate Modern"
        },
        {
            "idx": "202",
            "question": "Which U.S. president served four terms in office?",
            "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "19",
            "question": "Which U.S. city is known as the 'City of Brotherly Love'?",
            "answer": "Philadelphia, Pennsylvania"
        },
        {
            "idx": "206",
            "question": "Which U.S. holiday celebrates the end of slavery?",
            "answer": "Juneteenth"
        },
        {
            "idx": "165",
            "question": "Which U.S. city is known for the historic event of the Boston Tea Party?",
            "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts"
        },
        {
            "idx": "108",
            "question": "Which U.S. president is known for the 'Square Deal'?",
            "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "16",
            "question": "Which British author wrote 'Pride and Prejudice'?",
            "answer": "Jane Austen"
        },
        {
            "idx": "185",
            "question": "What is the largest U.S. state by area?",
            "answer": "Alaska"
        },
        {
            "idx": "43",
            "question": "Which British city is known for its historic shipyards and as the birthplace of Charles Dickens?",
            "answer": "Portsmouth"
        },
        {
            "idx": "289",
            "question": "What is the line of longitude that passes through the Royal Observatory in Greenwich?",
            "answer": "The Prime Meridian"
        },
        {
            "idx": "183",
            "question": "Which UK national park contains the highest mountain in England?",
            "answer": "Lake District"
        },
        {
            "idx": "135",
            "question": "Which London borough is home to Wimbledon tennis championships?",
            "answer": "Merton"
        },
        {
            "idx": "255",
            "question": "What is the name of the U.S. naval base that is the headquarters of the U.S. Pacific Fleet?",
            "answer": "Pearl Harbor"
        },
        {
            "idx": "257",
            "question": "What is the name of the deepest lake in the United States?",
            "answer": "Crater Lake"
        },
        {
            "idx": "267",
            "question": "Which U.S. president established the Peace Corps?",
            "answer": "John F. Kennedy"
        },
        {
            "idx": "264",
            "question": "Which British dish consists of sausages in Yorkshire pudding batter?",
            "answer": "Toad in the Hole"
        },
        {
            "idx": "113",
            "question": "What is the name of the underground railway system in London?",
            "answer": "The London Underground or The Tube"
        },
        {
            "idx": "280",
            "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to be born in a hospital?",
            "answer": "Jimmy Carter"
        },
        {
            "idx": "13",
            "question": "Which British author created the fictional detective Sherlock Holmes?",
            "answer": "Sir Arthur Conan Doyle"
        },
        {
            "idx": "73",
            "question": "What is the longest-running Broadway show in American history?",
            "answer": "The Phantom of the Opera"
        },
        {
            "idx": "96",
            "question": "What is the oldest university in the United Kingdom?",
            "answer": "The University of Oxford"
        },
        {
            "idx": "238",
            "question": "Which U.S. state was originally known as the 'Province of New Jersey'?",
            "answer": "New Jersey"
        },
        {
            "idx": "133",
            "question": "Which UK city is home to the National Railway Museum?",
            "answer": "York"
        },
        {
            "idx": "27",
            "question": "Who was the U.S. president during the purchase of Alaska from Russia?",
            "answer": "Andrew Johnson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "115",
            "question": "Who was the legendary outlaw associated with Sherwood Forest?",
            "answer": "Robin Hood"
        },
        {
            "idx": "290",
            "question": "What is the main function of the U.S. Electoral College?",
            "answer": "To elect the President and Vice President"
        },
        {
            "idx": "197",
            "question": "Which U.S. city is famous for its deep-dish pizza?",
            "answer": "Chicago, Illinois"
        },
        {
            "idx": "236",
            "question": "Which British monarch established the Church of England?",
            "answer": "Henry VIII"
        },
        {
            "idx": "142",
            "question": "Which U.S. state is the leading producer of blueberries in the nation?",
            "answer": "Maine"
        },
        {
            "idx": "227",
            "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to resign from office?",
            "answer": "Richard Nixon"
        },
        {
            "idx": "241",
            "question": "What is the name of the British law that granted self-government to Canada, Australia, New Zealand, and South Africa?",
            "answer": "Statute of Westminster"
        },
        {
            "idx": "110",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous prehistoric monument located in Wiltshire, England?",
            "answer": "Stonehenge"
        },
        {
            "idx": "20",
            "question": "What was the first spacecraft to land on Mars?",
            "answer": "Viking 1"
        },
        {
            "idx": "223",
            "question": "What is the name of the British architect who designed St. Paul's Cathedral?",
            "answer": "Sir Christopher Wren"
        },
        {
            "idx": "125",
            "question": "What annual sporting event takes place between Oxford and Cambridge Universities?",
            "answer": "The Boat Race"
        },
        {
            "idx": "9",
            "question": "What is the oldest university in the United States?",
            "answer": "Harvard University"
        },
        {
            "idx": "203",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous suspension bridge in San Francisco?",
            "answer": "Golden Gate Bridge"
        },
        {
            "idx": "79",
            "question": "What is the name of the longest-reigning current British monarch?",
            "answer": "Queen Elizabeth II"
        },
        {
            "idx": "98",
            "question": "Who was the first woman to run for the U.S. presidency with a major political party?",
            "answer": "Hillary Clinton"
        },
        {
            "idx": "127",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous American ivy league university in Massachusetts?",
            "answer": "Harvard University"
        },
        {
            "idx": "141",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous British luxury car manufacturer known for its iconic grille and Spirit of Ecstasy mascot?",
            "answer": "Rolls-Royce"
        },
        {
            "idx": "225",
            "question": "What British city is known for its association with the legend of Robin Hood?",
            "answer": "Nottingham"
        },
        {
            "idx": "38",
            "question": "What year did the United States declare independence from Britain?",
            "answer": "1776"
        },
        {
            "idx": "219",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous wax museum in London?",
            "answer": "Madame Tussauds"
        },
        {
            "idx": "247",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous American music awards held annually in Los Angeles?",
            "answer": "Grammy Awards"
        },
        {
            "idx": "256",
            "question": "Which English city is known as the 'City of Dreaming Spires'?",
            "answer": "Oxford"
        },
        {
            "idx": "198",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous British comedy group known for their surreal sketch shows?",
            "answer": "Monty Python"
        },
        {
            "idx": "131",
            "question": "What is the name of the river that flows through London?",
            "answer": "The River Thames"
        },
        {
            "idx": "29",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous British music festival held annually in Somerset?",
            "answer": "Glastonbury Festival"
        },
        {
            "idx": "26",
            "question": "Who was the British Prime Minister at the start of the 21st century?",
            "answer": "Tony Blair"
        },
        {
            "idx": "85",
            "question": "What was the main issue addressed by the Supreme Court in the landmark case Brown v. Board of Education?",
            "answer": "School segregation"
        },
        {
            "idx": "195",
            "question": "What is the highest military decoration awarded by the United States government?",
            "answer": "The Medal of Honor"
        },
        {
            "idx": "200",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous clock tower located at the north end of the Palace of Westminster in London?",
            "answer": "Big Ben"
        },
        {
            "idx": "65",
            "question": "What is the oldest public university in the United States?",
            "answer": "The University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill"
        },
        {
            "idx": "222",
            "question": "Who was the British monarch during the establishment of the British East India Company?",
            "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I"
        },
        {
            "idx": "274",
            "question": "Which British monarch reigned during the Victorian Era?",
            "answer": "Queen Victoria"
        },
        {
            "idx": "268",
            "question": "Who was the U.S. president during the establishment of the Environmental Protection Agency?",
            "answer": "Richard Nixon"
        },
        {
            "idx": "71",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous American road that runs from Chicago to Los Angeles?",
            "answer": "Route 66"
        },
        {
            "idx": "143",
            "question": "What is the most populous city in the United States?",
            "answer": "New York City"
        },
        {
            "idx": "17",
            "question": "Which British author wrote '1984' and 'Animal Farm'?",
            "answer": "George Orwell"
        },
        {
            "idx": "50",
            "question": "Which UK university is the oldest in the English-speaking world?",
            "answer": "Oxford University"
        },
        {
            "idx": "237",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous arts festival held annually in Edinburgh?",
            "answer": "The Edinburgh Festival Fringe"
        },
        {
            "idx": "193",
            "question": "Which document, signed in 1215, is known as the first written constitution in European history?",
            "answer": "The Magna Carta"
        },
        {
            "idx": "40",
            "question": "What is the longest river in the United States?",
            "answer": "Missouri River"
        },
        {
            "idx": "122",
            "question": "What is the name of the British spy character created by Ian Fleming?",
            "answer": "James Bond"
        },
        {
            "idx": "216",
            "question": "Which UK county is known as 'God's Own Country'?",
            "answer": "Yorkshire"
        },
        {
            "idx": "234",
            "question": "Who was the legendary American folk hero known for planting apple trees?",
            "answer": "Johnny Appleseed"
        },
        {
            "idx": "64",
            "question": "Who was the British Prime Minister during the majority of World War II?",
            "answer": "Winston Churchill"
        },
        {
            "idx": "266",
            "question": "What American festival is known for showcasing independent films?",
            "answer": "Sundance Film Festival"
        },
        {
            "idx": "272",
            "question": "What is the traditional Southern U.S. New Year's Day dish for good luck?",
            "answer": "Black-eyed peas"
        },
        {
            "idx": "167",
            "question": "What is the only U.S. state to have a royal palace?",
            "answer": "Hawaii (ʻIolani Palace)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "231",
            "question": "Which U.S. state is the Grand Canyon located in?",
            "answer": "Arizona"
        },
        {
            "idx": "2",
            "question": "What is the traditional dish of England involving ground meat and mashed potatoes?",
            "answer": "Shepherd's Pie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "262",
            "question": "Which amendment abolished Prohibition in the United States?",
            "answer": "The 21st Amendment"
        },
        {
            "idx": "99",
            "question": "What is the largest freshwater lake in the USA?",
            "answer": "Lake Superior"
        },
        {
            "idx": "276",
            "question": "Which U.S. president was known as the 'Great Communicator'?",
            "answer": "Ronald Reagan"
        },
        {
            "idx": "204",
            "question": "Which British monarch established the Church of England?",
            "answer": "King Henry VIII"
        },
        {
            "idx": "181",
            "question": "Which U.S. state is known as the 'First State'?",
            "answer": "Delaware"
        },
        {
            "idx": "72",
            "question": "Who was the U.S. president during the signing of the NAFTA agreement?",
            "answer": "Bill Clinton"
        },
        {
            "idx": "119",
            "question": "Who was the U.S. president during the Iran hostage crisis?",
            "answer": "Jimmy Carter"
        },
        {
            "idx": "106",
            "question": "What is the name of the largest river system in the United States?",
            "answer": "The Mississippi River System"
        },
        {
            "idx": "101",
            "question": "Which UK city is home to the Beatles?",
            "answer": "Liverpool"
        },
        {
            "idx": "49",
            "question": "What is the name of the U.S. military cemetery in Virginia?",
            "answer": "Arlington National Cemetery"
        },
        {
            "idx": "169",
            "question": "What is the name of the British ceremony that marks the official birthday of the British sovereign?",
            "answer": "Trooping the Colour"
        },
        {
            "idx": "89",
            "question": "Which battle in 1066 led to the Norman conquest of England?",
            "answer": "The Battle of Hastings"
        },
        {
            "idx": "118",
            "question": "Which British author wrote the 'Harry Potter' series?",
            "answer": "J.K. Rowling"
        },
        {
            "idx": "63",
            "question": "What landmark decision did the U.S. Supreme Court make in Brown v. Board of Education?",
            "answer": "It declared state laws establishing separate public schools for black and white students to be unconstitutional"
        },
        {
            "idx": "95",
            "question": "Which British city is known for its pivotal role in the English Civil War?",
            "answer": "York"
        },
        {
            "idx": "249",
            "question": "Which U.S. President was known for his role in the Cuban Missile Crisis?",
            "answer": "John F. Kennedy"
        },
        {
            "idx": "253",
            "question": "What is the name of the highest court of appeal in the UK for civil cases, and for criminal cases from England, Wales, and Northern Ireland?",
            "answer": "The Supreme Court of the United Kingdom"
        },
        {
            "idx": "212",
            "question": "Which British city is known as the 'City of Dreaming Spires'?",
            "answer": "Oxford"
        },
        {
            "idx": "145",
            "question": "What famous landmark was a gift to the United States from France?",
            "answer": "The Statue of Liberty"
        },
        {
            "idx": "176",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous American canyon in Arizona?",
            "answer": "Grand Canyon"
        },
        {
            "idx": "287",
            "question": "Which British dessert is traditionally served with custard?",
            "answer": "Spotted dick"
        },
        {
            "idx": "52",
            "question": "Which London bridge is often mistakenly called London Bridge by tourists?",
            "answer": "Tower Bridge"
        },
        {
            "idx": "261",
            "question": "What is the name of the U.S. naval base attacked in 1941, leading to American involvement in World War II?",
            "answer": "Pearl Harbor"
        },
        {
            "idx": "194",
            "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to appoint a woman to the Supreme Court?",
            "answer": "Ronald Reagan (Sandra Day O'Connor)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "160",
            "question": "What was the significant battle of the American Revolution fought in 1775?",
            "answer": "The Battle of Bunker Hill"
        },
        {
            "idx": "47",
            "question": "What is the name of the national anthem of the United States?",
            "answer": "The Star-Spangled Banner"
        },
        {
            "idx": "230",
            "question": "What is the name of the largest desert in the United States?",
            "answer": "The Mojave Desert"
        },
        {
            "idx": "201",
            "question": "Who was the Queen of England during the establishment of the English colonies in America?",
            "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I"
        },
        {
            "idx": "114",
            "question": "Which U.S. state was the first to legalize same-sex marriage?",
            "answer": "Massachusetts"
        },
        {
            "idx": "70",
            "question": "Which U.S. state was the first to ratify the Constitution?",
            "answer": "Delaware"
        },
        {
            "idx": "187",
            "question": "Which president is credited with the Emancipation Proclamation?",
            "answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
        },
        {
            "idx": "251",
            "question": "What is the traditional British dish made from pig's blood, oatmeal, and spices?",
            "answer": "Black pudding"
        },
        {
            "idx": "111",
            "question": "Which English king was defeated at the Battle of Hastings?",
            "answer": "King Harold II"
        },
        {
            "idx": "282",
            "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to live in the White House?",
            "answer": "John Adams"
        },
        {
            "idx": "18",
            "question": "What is the name of the treaty that ended the American Revolutionary War?",
            "answer": "The Treaty of Paris, 1783"
        },
        {
            "idx": "53",
            "question": "Which U.S. monument honors four U.S. presidents carved into a mountain?",
            "answer": "Mount Rushmore"
        },
        {
            "idx": "109",
            "question": "What is the largest state in the USA by area?",
            "answer": "Alaska"
        },
        {
            "idx": "174",
            "question": "What is the name of the traditional British pie filled with minced meat and mashed potatoes?",
            "answer": "Cottage Pie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "128",
            "question": "What major global event did the United States enter in 1941?",
            "answer": "World War II"
        },
        {
            "idx": "150",
            "question": "What is the name of the first American colony to declare independence from Britain?",
            "answer": "Rhode Island"
        },
        {
            "idx": "161",
            "question": "Which U.S. state is known as the birthplace of aviation?",
            "answer": "Ohio"
        },
        {
            "idx": "178",
            "question": "Which U.S. city is famous for its historic cable cars?",
            "answer": "San Francisco, California"
        },
        {
            "idx": "208",
            "question": "What U.S. state is known for its large Amish population?",
            "answer": "Pennsylvania"
        },
        {
            "idx": "68",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous American national park with geysers in Wyoming?",
            "answer": "Yellowstone National Park"
        },
        {
            "idx": "138",
            "question": "What is the tallest building in the United States?",
            "answer": "One World Trade Center"
        },
        {
            "idx": "55",
            "question": "Which U.S. city is famous for its deep-dish pizza?",
            "answer": "Chicago"
        },
        {
            "idx": "87",
            "question": "What is the name of the residence of the British Prime Minister?",
            "answer": "10 Downing Street"
        },
        {
            "idx": "248",
            "question": "What American city is known as the birthplace of the United States Navy?",
            "answer": "Philadelphia, Pennsylvania"
        },
        {
            "idx": "288",
            "question": "What is the longest river in the United Kingdom?",
            "answer": "The River Severn"
        },
        {
            "idx": "12",
            "question": "Which U.S. city is known for its significant role in the American automotive industry?",
            "answer": "Detroit, Michigan"
        },
        {
            "idx": "31",
            "question": "Which U.S. landmark is known as 'America's Fortress'?",
            "answer": "Fort Knox"
        },
        {
            "idx": "154",
            "question": "Which British cheese is traditionally used in a ploughman's lunch?",
            "answer": "Cheddar"
        },
        {
            "idx": "213",
            "question": "Which British city was famously bombed during the Blitz in World War II?",
            "answer": "London"
        },
        {
            "idx": "134",
            "question": "What is the name of the British tradition of drinking tea in the late afternoon, typically accompanied by sandwiches or pastries?",
            "answer": "Afternoon Tea"
        },
        {
            "idx": "189",
            "question": "Which U.S. president is associated with the phrase 'The only thing we have to fear is fear itself'?",
            "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "129",
            "question": "Which U.S. state is known for its dairy production and is often called 'America’s Dairyland'?",
            "answer": "Wisconsin"
        },
        {
            "idx": "35",
            "question": "Who was the U.S. President during the Louisiana Purchase?",
            "answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "86",
            "question": "Which British monarch is associated with the Golden Age of English history?",
            "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I"
        },
        {
            "idx": "105",
            "question": "What is the name of the British naval flag officer known for his victories against Napoleon during the Napoleonic Wars?",
            "answer": "Admiral Lord Nelson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "84",
            "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to be impeached?",
            "answer": "Andrew Johnson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "88",
            "question": "Which U.S. state is known as the 'Sunshine State'?",
            "answer": "Florida"
        },
        {
            "idx": "91",
            "question": "Which British band led the British Invasion of the US music charts in the 1960s?",
            "answer": "The Beatles"
        },
        {
            "idx": "218",
            "question": "Who was the American civil rights leader assassinated in 1968?",
            "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
        },
        {
            "idx": "281",
            "question": "What is the capital of Texas?",
            "answer": "Austin"
        },
        {
            "idx": "283",
            "question": "Which U.S. city was the first to use a subway system?",
            "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts"
        },
        {
            "idx": "56",
            "question": "What is the nickname of New York City?",
            "answer": "The Big Apple"
        },
        {
            "idx": "74",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous route known as the 'Mother Road'?",
            "answer": "Route 66"
        },
        {
            "idx": "199",
            "question": "What was the first permanent English settlement in North America?",
            "answer": "Jamestown, Virginia"
        },
        {
            "idx": "172",
            "question": "Who was the British monarch during the Falklands War?",
            "answer": "Queen Elizabeth II"
        },
        {
            "idx": "260",
            "question": "What was the major cause of the American Civil War?",
            "answer": "Slavery and states' rights"
        },
        {
            "idx": "136",
            "question": "Which U.S. landmark is inscribed with the words 'Give me your tired, your poor, your huddled masses yearning to breathe free'?",
            "answer": "The Statue of Liberty"
        },
        {
            "idx": "155",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous American civil rights leader who gave the 'I Have a Dream' speech?",
            "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
        },
        {
            "idx": "120",
            "question": "Which British city is historically known for its shipbuilding industry?",
            "answer": "Glasgow"
        },
        {
            "idx": "217",
            "question": "What document officially ended slavery in the United States?",
            "answer": "The 13th Amendment"
        },
        {
            "idx": "6",
            "question": "Which British city is known for its historic university and as the location of the Radcliffe Camera?",
            "answer": "Oxford"
        },
        {
            "idx": "10",
            "question": "What U.S. state is known for its potatoes?",
            "answer": "Idaho"
        },
        {
            "idx": "22",
            "question": "Who is known as the 'Father of the National Parks' in America?",
            "answer": "John Muir"
        },
        {
            "idx": "258",
            "question": "Which British coin features a thistle, leek, and shamrock?",
            "answer": "One pound coin"
        },
        {
            "idx": "126",
            "question": "Who was the first African American to serve as U.S. Secretary of State?",
            "answer": "Colin Powell"
        },
        {
            "idx": "270",
            "question": "What is the name of the famous American stock exchange in New York?",
            "answer": "New York Stock Exchange (NYSE)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "77",
            "question": "What is the smallest U.S. state by area?",
            "answer": "Rhode Island"
        },
        {
            "idx": "112",
            "question": "Which UK city is famous for its steel production?",
            "answer": "Sheffield"
        },
        {
            "idx": "156",
            "question": "What U.S. state is known for its significant Native American history and culture?",
            "answer": "New Mexico"
        },
        {
            "idx": "66",
            "question": "What U.S. city is known as the Windy City?",
            "answer": "Chicago, Illinois"
        },
        {
            "idx": "67",
            "question": "Which British city is known for its pivotal role in the Industrial Revolution?",
            "answer": "Manchester"
        },
        {
            "idx": "254",
            "question": "What is the name of the spacecraft that first landed humans on the Moon?",
            "answer": "Apollo 11"
        },
        {
            "idx": "121",
            "question": "What is the largest lake in England?",
            "answer": "Windermere"
        },
        {
            "idx": "246",
            "question": "Who was the second President of the United States?",
            "answer": "John Adams"
        },
        {
            "idx": "94",
            "question": "Which British monarch had the longest reign before Queen Elizabeth II?",
            "answer": "Queen Victoria"
        },
        {
            "idx": "265",
            "question": "Which U.S. president initiated the project that led to the creation of the internet?",
            "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower"
        },
        {
            "idx": "152",
            "question": "Which U.S. state is known for its volcanic islands?",
            "answer": "Hawaii"
        },
        {
            "idx": "76",
            "question": "Which U.S. city was the first capital of the United States?",
            "answer": "Philadelphia, Pennsylvania"
        },
        {
            "idx": "157",
            "question": "Who was the first female British astronaut?",
            "answer": "Helen Sharman"
        },
        {
            "idx": "163",
            "question": "Which British monarch succeeded Queen Victoria?",
            "answer": "King Edward VII"
        },
        {
            "idx": "24",
            "question": "Which U.S. city is known as the birthplace of jazz music?",
            "answer": "New Orleans"
        },
        {
            "idx": "57",
            "question": "Which U.S. state is known for producing the most corn?",
            "answer": "Iowa"
        },
        {
            "idx": "28",
            "question": "Which British scientist developed the theory of evolution?",
            "answer": "Charles Darwin"
        },
        {
            "idx": "92",
            "question": "What is the official London residence of the Queen?",
            "answer": "Buckingham Palace"
        },
        {
            "idx": "177",
            "question": "Which U.S. city hosted the 1984 Summer Olympics?",
            "answer": "Los Angeles, California"
        },
        {
            "idx": "4",
            "question": "Which British physicist is known for his work on black holes?",
            "answer": "Stephen Hawking"
        }
    ],
    "zh": [
        {
            "idx": "139",
            "question": "哪个美国国家公园以拥有超级火山而闻名？",
            "answer": "黄石国家公园"
        },
        {
            "idx": "5",
            "question": "用波旁威士忌制作的传统美国南方饮料是什么？",
            "answer": "薄荷朱利酒"
        },
        {
            "idx": "34",
            "question": "1666年发生的什么重大事件摧毁了伦敦的大部分地区？",
            "answer": "伦敦大火"
        },
        {
            "idx": "182",
            "question": "用羊胃制作的传统苏格兰菜是什么？",
            "answer": "哈吉斯"
        },
        {
            "idx": "33",
            "question": "哈珀·李的小说《杀死一只知更鸟》的主题是什么？",
            "answer": "种族不公和道德成长"
        },
        {
            "idx": "252",
            "question": "哪位美国总统与新政有关？",
            "answer": "富兰克林·D·罗斯福"
        },
        {
            "idx": "179",
            "question": "美国宪法哪项修正案规定了持有武器的权利？",
            "answer": "第二修正案"
        },
        {
            "idx": "186",
            "question": "哪个美国城市以狂欢节庆祝活动而闻名？",
            "answer": "路易斯安那州新奥尔良"
        },
        {
            "idx": "168",
            "question": "感恩节供应的传统美国甜点是什么？",
            "answer": "南瓜派"
        },
        {
            "idx": "271",
            "question": "哪个英国城市以发明蒸汽机车而闻名？",
            "answer": "纽卡斯尔"
        },
        {
            "idx": "180",
            "question": "哪个英国城市以其罗马建造的浴场而闻名？",
            "answer": "巴斯"
        },
        {
            "idx": "45",
            "question": "拉什莫尔山位于美国哪个州？",
            "answer": "南达科他州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "285",
            "question": "亚伯拉罕·林肯在美国内战期间发表的著名演讲叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "葛底斯堡演说"
        },
        {
            "idx": "221",
            "question": "1620年载着朝圣者前往美国的著名英国船只叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "五月花号"
        },
        {
            "idx": "209",
            "question": "用鱼和油炸面糊制作的传统英国菜是什么？",
            "answer": "炸鱼薯条"
        },
        {
            "idx": "166",
            "question": "美国本土48州最高的山是什么？",
            "answer": "加利福尼亚州惠特尼山"
        },
        {
            "idx": "214",
            "question": "哪个英国城市以建造泰坦尼克号而闻名？",
            "answer": "贝尔法斯特"
        },
        {
            "idx": "48",
            "question": "哪个美国州被称为‘松树州’？",
            "answer": "缅因州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "59",
            "question": "哪位英国科学家以万有引力定律而闻名？",
            "answer": "艾萨克·牛顿爵士"
        },
        {
            "idx": "54",
            "question": "用来描述美国政府偏向家庭团聚移民政策的术语是什么？",
            "answer": "链式移民"
        },
        {
            "idx": "103",
            "question": "西雅图因其咖啡文化而获得的昵称是什么？",
            "answer": "咖啡之都"
        },
        {
            "idx": "190",
            "question": "1969年首次登月时的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "理查德·尼克松"
        },
        {
            "idx": "278",
            "question": "美国宪法的主要起草者是谁？",
            "answer": "詹姆斯·麦迪逊"
        },
        {
            "idx": "240",
            "question": "哪个美国州拥有最多的选举人票？",
            "answer": "加利福尼亚州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "61",
            "question": "哪个美国州被称为‘魅力之地’？",
            "answer": "新墨西哥州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "62",
            "question": "纳尔逊勋爵海军上将牺牲的著名英国战役叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "特拉法尔加海战"
        },
        {
            "idx": "102",
            "question": "伦敦哪个市场以古董和复古物品而闻名？",
            "answer": "波多贝罗路市场"
        },
        {
            "idx": "175",
            "question": "被称为硅谷发源地的地区叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "圣克拉拉谷"
        },
        {
            "idx": "1",
            "question": "反对欧洲在美洲殖民主义的美国学说叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "门罗主义"
        },
        {
            "idx": "269",
            "question": "哪个美国城市是1963年‘争取工作和自由华盛顿大游行’的举办地？",
            "answer": "华盛顿特区"
        },
        {
            "idx": "151",
            "question": "哪个美国城市是美国宪法下的第一个首都？",
            "answer": "纽约市"
        },
        {
            "idx": "93",
            "question": "哪个美国州是1849年淘金热的中心？",
            "answer": "加利福尼亚州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "23",
            "question": "哪个美国州以其重要的美洲原住民人口和历史而闻名？",
            "answer": "俄克拉荷马州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "116",
            "question": "哪个英国城市以发明蒸汽机而闻名？",
            "answer": "伯明翰"
        },
        {
            "idx": "245",
            "question": "以发明电灯泡而闻名的美国发明家是谁？",
            "answer": "托马斯·爱迪生"
        },
        {
            "idx": "196",
            "question": "被称为‘Bobby’的英国执法官员叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "警察"
        },
        {
            "idx": "80",
            "question": "第一个绕地球轨道飞行的美国宇航员是谁？",
            "answer": "约翰·格伦"
        },
        {
            "idx": "97",
            "question": "哪位英国科学家被认为发明了万维网？",
            "answer": "蒂姆·伯纳斯-李爵士"
        },
        {
            "idx": "148",
            "question": "伦敦哪个公园包含演讲者角落？",
            "answer": "海德公园"
        },
        {
            "idx": "158",
            "question": "克里米亚战争期间的英国君主是谁？",
            "answer": "维多利亚女王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "210",
            "question": "以描写爵士时代作品而闻名的美国作家是谁？",
            "answer": "F·斯科特·菲茨杰拉德"
        },
        {
            "idx": "146",
            "question": "在田纳西州每年举办的著名音乐节叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "邦纳鲁音乐节"
        },
        {
            "idx": "164",
            "question": "英国最高法院叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "英国最高法院"
        },
        {
            "idx": "104",
            "question": "伦敦哪条街以医疗诊所而闻名？",
            "answer": "哈利街"
        },
        {
            "idx": "15",
            "question": "英国哪个城市以其罗马浴场而闻名？",
            "answer": "巴斯"
        },
        {
            "idx": "11",
            "question": "哪位美国总统提出了被称为‘大棒外交’的政策？",
            "answer": "西奥多·罗斯福"
        },
        {
            "idx": "14",
            "question": "英国第一位女首相是谁？",
            "answer": "玛格丽特·撒切尔"
        },
        {
            "idx": "39",
            "question": "哪个美国州被称为‘万湖之州’？",
            "answer": "明尼苏达州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "41",
            "question": "哪个美国州以其重要的贵格会人口而闻名？",
            "answer": "宾夕法尼亚州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "44",
            "question": "哪位英国探险家以16世纪环球航行而闻名？",
            "answer": "弗朗西斯·德雷克爵士"
        },
        {
            "idx": "124",
            "question": "哪个美国州的昵称是‘最后的边疆’？",
            "answer": "阿拉斯加州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "149",
            "question": "哪个条约承认了美国殖民地从英国独立？",
            "answer": "1783年巴黎条约"
        },
        {
            "idx": "188",
            "question": "哪个美国城市以其重要的科技产业而闻名，通常被称为‘硅谷’？",
            "answer": "加利福尼亚州圣何塞"
        },
        {
            "idx": "228",
            "question": "底特律因其汽车工业而获得的昵称是什么？",
            "answer": "汽车城"
        },
        {
            "idx": "284",
            "question": "哪位英国君主继承了伊丽莎白一世女王，是斯图亚特王朝的第一位？",
            "answer": "詹姆斯一世国王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "100",
            "question": "也被称为‘自由照耀世界’的著名美国地标叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "自由女神像"
        },
        {
            "idx": "279",
            "question": "哪位英国政治人物被称为‘铁娘子’？",
            "answer": "玛格丽特·撒切尔"
        },
        {
            "idx": "25",
            "question": "哪个美国节日在十一月的第四个星期四庆祝？",
            "answer": "感恩节"
        },
        {
            "idx": "184",
            "question": "哪个苏格兰湖以其神话怪兽而闻名？",
            "answer": "尼斯湖"
        },
        {
            "idx": "242",
            "question": "组成英国议会的两院是什么？",
            "answer": "下议院和上议院"
        },
        {
            "idx": "170",
            "question": "美国宪法哪项修正案赋予了妇女选举权？",
            "answer": "第19修正案"
        },
        {
            "idx": "275",
            "question": "以豪华车辆而闻名的著名英国跑车品牌叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "阿斯顿·马丁"
        },
        {
            "idx": "277",
            "question": "2016年发生的重大英国政治事件是什么？",
            "answer": "脱欧公投"
        },
        {
            "idx": "3",
            "question": "费城的昵称是什么？",
            "answer": "兄弟之爱之城"
        },
        {
            "idx": "21",
            "question": "美国南方供应的传统美国面包是什么？",
            "answer": "玉米面包"
        },
        {
            "idx": "263",
            "question": "结束美墨战争的条约叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "瓜达卢佩-伊达尔戈条约"
        },
        {
            "idx": "30",
            "question": "雕刻在拉什莫尔山上的著名美国纪念碑叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "拉什莫尔山国家纪念碑"
        },
        {
            "idx": "173",
            "question": "英格兰的守护神是谁，以他的名义庆祝的是哪一天？",
            "answer": "圣乔治；圣乔治节在4月23日庆祝"
        },
        {
            "idx": "107",
            "question": "涉及水果和浸泡在雪利酒中的海绵蛋糕的传统英国甜点是什么？",
            "answer": "三层蛋糕"
        },
        {
            "idx": "192",
            "question": "哪个英国城市以其两个著名足球俱乐部曼联和曼城而闻名？",
            "answer": "曼彻斯特"
        },
        {
            "idx": "233",
            "question": "殖民时期南方殖民地的主要经济活动是什么？",
            "answer": "农业（特别是烟草和棉花）"
        },
        {
            "idx": "78",
            "question": "不列颠群岛最高的山是什么？",
            "answer": "本·尼维斯山"
        },
        {
            "idx": "243",
            "question": "第一次世界大战期间的英国君主是谁？",
            "answer": "乔治五世国王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "273",
            "question": "哪个美国州是最后一个加入联邦的？",
            "answer": "夏威夷州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "82",
            "question": "美国第一位女性最高法院大法官是谁？",
            "answer": "桑德拉·戴·奥康纳"
        },
        {
            "idx": "37",
            "question": "任职时间最长的美国最高法院大法官是谁？",
            "answer": "威廉·O·道格拉斯"
        },
        {
            "idx": "144",
            "question": "拉斯维加斯的昵称是什么？",
            "answer": "罪恶之城"
        },
        {
            "idx": "207",
            "question": "第一位当选美国国会的非裔美国女性是谁？",
            "answer": "雪莉·奇泽姆"
        },
        {
            "idx": "191",
            "question": "哪位英国国王在1936年退位以娶一位美国离婚女子？",
            "answer": "爱德华八世国王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "229",
            "question": "美国南北地区之间进行的战争是什么？",
            "answer": "内战"
        },
        {
            "idx": "32",
            "question": "美国最大的保护区是什么？",
            "answer": "阿拉斯加州兰格尔-圣伊莱亚斯国家公园和保护区"
        },
        {
            "idx": "250",
            "question": "马丁·路德·金博士著名演讲《我有一个梦想》的主要内容是什么？",
            "answer": "民权和种族平等"
        },
        {
            "idx": "132",
            "question": "哪个美国州是1867年从俄国购买的？",
            "answer": "阿拉斯加州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "244",
            "question": "1969年7月20日发生的美国重大事件是什么？",
            "answer": "阿波罗11号登月"
        },
        {
            "idx": "259",
            "question": "莱特兄弟首次成功飞行是在哪个城市？",
            "answer": "北卡罗来纳州基蒂霍克"
        },
        {
            "idx": "232",
            "question": "哪个美国州拥有最多的国家公园？",
            "answer": "加利福尼亚州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "117",
            "question": "1802年建立的著名美国军事学院叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "西点军校（美国军事学院）"
        },
        {
            "idx": "46",
            "question": "英国领土获得独立的过程叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "非殖民化"
        },
        {
            "idx": "69",
            "question": "哪位英国探险家以其太平洋航行而闻名？",
            "answer": "詹姆斯·库克船长"
        },
        {
            "idx": "75",
            "question": "流经利物浦的河流叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "默西河"
        },
        {
            "idx": "81",
            "question": "哪位美国总统签署了1964年民权法案？",
            "answer": "林登·B·约翰逊"
        },
        {
            "idx": "60",
            "question": "美国本土48州最大的岛屿是什么？",
            "answer": "纽约州长岛"
        },
        {
            "idx": "147",
            "question": "1998年英国政府与爱尔兰民族主义者签署的历史性协议叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "耶稣受难日协议"
        },
        {
            "idx": "159",
            "question": "哪个美国州以波旁威士忌生产而闻名？",
            "answer": "肯塔基州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "205",
            "question": "谁以打第一个电话而闻名？",
            "answer": "亚历山大·格雷厄姆·贝尔"
        },
        {
            "idx": "235",
            "question": "谁起草了《独立宣言》？",
            "answer": "托马斯·杰斐逊"
        },
        {
            "idx": "130",
            "question": "哪个条约结束了美国独立战争？",
            "answer": "1783年巴黎条约"
        },
        {
            "idx": "153",
            "question": "1973年使堕胎合法化的美国最高法院案件叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "罗伊诉韦德案"
        },
        {
            "idx": "215",
            "question": "哪项议会法案在英格兰确立了新教？",
            "answer": "1534年至上法案"
        },
        {
            "idx": "36",
            "question": "美国的首都是什么？",
            "answer": "华盛顿特区"
        },
        {
            "idx": "171",
            "question": "英国哪座大教堂拥有英国最高的尖塔？",
            "answer": "索尔兹伯里大教堂"
        },
        {
            "idx": "7",
            "question": "美国最大的岛屿叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "夏威夷（大岛）"
        },
        {
            "idx": "226",
            "question": "将大不列颠与欧洲大陆分开的海叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "英吉利海峡"
        },
        {
            "idx": "220",
            "question": "1965年通过的禁止投票中种族歧视的里程碑式立法叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "1965年投票权法案"
        },
        {
            "idx": "140",
            "question": "第二次世界大战大部分时间的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "富兰克林·D·罗斯福"
        },
        {
            "idx": "224",
            "question": "英格兰最大的国家公园是什么？",
            "answer": "湖区国家公园"
        },
        {
            "idx": "42",
            "question": "作为自由和民主象征的著名美国地标叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "自由钟"
        },
        {
            "idx": "8",
            "question": "哪位美国总统将1964年民权法案签署成法？",
            "answer": "林登·B·约翰逊"
        },
        {
            "idx": "90",
            "question": "位于伯克郡的英国皇室住所叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "温莎城堡"
        },
        {
            "idx": "211",
            "question": "女王在伦敦的官方住所叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "白金汉宫"
        },
        {
            "idx": "239",
            "question": "1929年华尔街股灾导致了什么重大事件？",
            "answer": "大萧条"
        },
        {
            "idx": "51",
            "question": "英国电影和电视卓越奖项系列叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "英国电影学院奖"
        },
        {
            "idx": "162",
            "question": "哪个美国城市被称为蓝调音乐的家乡？",
            "answer": "田纳西州孟菲斯"
        },
        {
            "idx": "137",
            "question": "基于伊丽莎白二世女王统治的英国电视剧叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "王冠"
        },
        {
            "idx": "83",
            "question": "签署大宪章时的英国君主是谁？",
            "answer": "约翰国王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "58",
            "question": "哪个美国城市以其在美国独立战争中的关键作用而闻名？",
            "answer": "马萨诸塞州波士顿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "286",
            "question": "美国最繁忙的机场是什么？",
            "answer": "亚特兰大哈兹菲尔德-杰克逊国际机场"
        },
        {
            "idx": "123",
            "question": "位于泰晤士河畔的著名英国艺术画廊叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "泰特现代美术馆"
        },
        {
            "idx": "202",
            "question": "哪位美国总统任职四届？",
            "answer": "富兰克林·D·罗斯福"
        },
        {
            "idx": "19",
            "question": "哪个美国城市被称为‘兄弟之爱之城’？",
            "answer": "宾夕法尼亚州费城"
        },
        {
            "idx": "206",
            "question": "哪个美国节日庆祝奴隶制的结束？",
            "answer": "六月节"
        },
        {
            "idx": "165",
            "question": "哪个美国城市以波士顿茶党历史事件而闻名？",
            "answer": "马萨诸塞州波士顿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "108",
            "question": "哪位美国总统以‘公平交易’而闻名？",
            "answer": "西奥多·罗斯福"
        },
        {
            "idx": "16",
            "question": "哪位英国作家写了《傲慢与偏见》？",
            "answer": "简·奥斯汀"
        },
        {
            "idx": "185",
            "question": "按面积计算美国最大的州是什么？",
            "answer": "阿拉斯加州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "43",
            "question": "哪个英国城市以其历史悠久的造船厂和作为查尔斯·狄更斯的出生地而闻名？",
            "answer": "朴茨茅斯"
        },
        {
            "idx": "289",
            "question": "穿过格林威治皇家天文台的经线是什么？",
            "answer": "本初子午线"
        },
        {
            "idx": "183",
            "question": "英国哪个国家公园包含英格兰最高的山？",
            "answer": "湖区"
        },
        {
            "idx": "135",
            "question": "伦敦哪个区是温布尔登网球锦标赛的举办地？",
            "answer": "默顿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "255",
            "question": "作为美国太平洋舰队总部的美国海军基地叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "珍珠港"
        },
        {
            "idx": "257",
            "question": "美国最深的湖叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "火山口湖"
        },
        {
            "idx": "267",
            "question": "哪位美国总统建立了和平队？",
            "answer": "约翰·F·肯尼迪"
        },
        {
            "idx": "264",
            "question": "哪道英国菜由约克郡布丁面糊中的香肠组成？",
            "answer": "洞中蟾蜍"
        },
        {
            "idx": "113",
            "question": "伦敦的地下铁路系统叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "伦敦地铁或地铁"
        },
        {
            "idx": "280",
            "question": "第一位在医院出生的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "吉米·卡特"
        },
        {
            "idx": "13",
            "question": "哪位英国作家创造了虚构侦探夏洛克·福尔摩斯？",
            "answer": "阿瑟·柯南·道尔爵士"
        },
        {
            "idx": "73",
            "question": "美国历史上演出时间最长的百老汇演出是什么？",
            "answer": "歌剧魅影"
        },
        {
            "idx": "96",
            "question": "英国最古老的大学是什么？",
            "answer": "牛津大学"
        },
        {
            "idx": "238",
            "question": "哪个美国州最初被称为‘新泽西省’？",
            "answer": "新泽西州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "133",
            "question": "英国哪个城市是国家铁路博物馆的所在地？",
            "answer": "约克"
        },
        {
            "idx": "27",
            "question": "从俄国购买阿拉斯加时的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "安德鲁·约翰逊"
        },
        {
            "idx": "115",
            "question": "与舍伍德森林相关的传奇亡命之徒是谁？",
            "answer": "罗宾汉"
        },
        {
            "idx": "290",
            "question": "美国选举人团的主要功能是什么？",
            "answer": "选举总统和副总统"
        },
        {
            "idx": "197",
            "question": "哪个美国城市以深盘披萨而闻名？",
            "answer": "伊利诺伊州芝加哥"
        },
        {
            "idx": "236",
            "question": "哪位英国君主建立了英格兰教会？",
            "answer": "亨利八世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "142",
            "question": "哪个美国州是全国蓝莓的主要产地？",
            "answer": "缅因州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "227",
            "question": "第一位辞职的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "理查德·尼克松"
        },
        {
            "idx": "241",
            "question": "给予加拿大、澳大利亚、新西兰和南非自治权的英国法律叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "威斯敏斯特法令"
        },
        {
            "idx": "110",
            "question": "位于英格兰威尔特郡的著名史前纪念碑叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "巨石阵"
        },
        {
            "idx": "20",
            "question": "第一个登陆火星的航天器是什么？",
            "answer": "海盗1号"
        },
        {
            "idx": "223",
            "question": "设计圣保罗大教堂的英国建筑师叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "克里斯托弗·雷恩爵士"
        },
        {
            "idx": "125",
            "question": "牛津大学和剑桥大学之间举行的年度体育赛事是什么？",
            "answer": "赛艇比赛"
        },
        {
            "idx": "9",
            "question": "美国最古老的大学是什么？",
            "answer": "哈佛大学"
        },
        {
            "idx": "203",
            "question": "旧金山著名的悬索桥叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "金门大桥"
        },
        {
            "idx": "79",
            "question": "在位时间最长的现任英国君主叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "伊丽莎白二世女王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "98",
            "question": "第一位代表主要政党竞选美国总统的女性是谁？",
            "answer": "希拉里·克林顿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "127",
            "question": "马萨诸塞州著名的美国常春藤盟校叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "哈佛大学"
        },
        {
            "idx": "141",
            "question": "以其标志性格栅和飞翔女神吉祥物而闻名的著名英国豪华汽车制造商叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "劳斯莱斯"
        },
        {
            "idx": "225",
            "question": "哪个英国城市以与罗宾汉传说的联系而闻名？",
            "answer": "诺丁汉"
        },
        {
            "idx": "38",
            "question": "美国哪一年宣布从英国独立？",
            "answer": "1776年"
        },
        {
            "idx": "219",
            "question": "伦敦著名的蜡像馆叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "杜莎夫人蜡像馆"
        },
        {
            "idx": "247",
            "question": "每年在洛杉矶举办的著名美国音乐奖项叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "格莱美奖"
        },
        {
            "idx": "256",
            "question": "哪个英国城市被称为‘梦想尖塔之城’？",
            "answer": "牛津"
        },
        {
            "idx": "198",
            "question": "以超现实主义小品节目而闻名的著名英国喜剧团体叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "巨蟒剧团"
        },
        {
            "idx": "131",
            "question": "流经伦敦的河流叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "泰晤士河"
        },
        {
            "idx": "29",
            "question": "每年在萨默塞特举办的著名英国音乐节叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "格拉斯顿伯里音乐节"
        },
        {
            "idx": "26",
            "question": "21世纪初的英国首相是谁？",
            "answer": "托尼·布莱尔"
        },
        {
            "idx": "85",
            "question": "最高法院在布朗诉教育委员会里程碑案件中解决的主要问题是什么？",
            "answer": "学校种族隔离"
        },
        {
            "idx": "195",
            "question": "美国政府颁发的最高军事荣誉是什么？",
            "answer": "荣誉勋章"
        },
        {
            "idx": "200",
            "question": "位于伦敦威斯敏斯特宫北端的著名钟楼叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "大本钟"
        },
        {
            "idx": "65",
            "question": "美国最古老的公立大学是什么？",
            "answer": "北卡罗来纳大学教堂山分校"
        },
        {
            "idx": "222",
            "question": "英国东印度公司成立时的英国君主是谁？",
            "answer": "伊丽莎白一世女王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "274",
            "question": "哪位英国君主在维多利亚时代统治？",
            "answer": "维多利亚女王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "268",
            "question": "环境保护署成立时的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "理查德·尼克松"
        },
        {
            "idx": "71",
            "question": "从芝加哥通往洛杉矶的著名美国公路叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "66号公路"
        },
        {
            "idx": "143",
            "question": "美国人口最多的城市是什么？",
            "answer": "纽约市"
        },
        {
            "idx": "17",
            "question": "哪位英国作家写了《1984》和《动物农场》？",
            "answer": "乔治·奥威尔"
        },
        {
            "idx": "50",
            "question": "英语世界最古老的英国大学是哪所？",
            "answer": "牛津大学"
        },
        {
            "idx": "237",
            "question": "每年在爱丁堡举办的著名艺术节叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "爱丁堡艺穗节"
        },
        {
            "idx": "193",
            "question": "1215年签署的哪份文件被称为欧洲历史上第一部成文宪法？",
            "answer": "大宪章"
        },
        {
            "idx": "40",
            "question": "美国最长的河流是什么？",
            "answer": "密苏里河"
        },
        {
            "idx": "122",
            "question": "伊恩·弗莱明创造的英国间谍角色叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "詹姆斯·邦德"
        },
        {
            "idx": "216",
            "question": "英国哪个郡被称为‘上帝的故乡’？",
            "answer": "约克郡"
        },
        {
            "idx": "234",
            "question": "以种植苹果树而闻名的传奇美国民间英雄是谁？",
            "answer": "约翰尼·苹果籽"
        },
        {
            "idx": "64",
            "question": "第二次世界大战大部分时间的英国首相是谁？",
            "answer": "温斯顿·丘吉尔"
        },
        {
            "idx": "266",
            "question": "以展示独立电影而闻名的美国电影节是什么？",
            "answer": "圣丹斯电影节"
        },
        {
            "idx": "272",
            "question": "美国南方传统的新年祈求好运菜肴是什么？",
            "answer": "黑眼豆"
        },
        {
            "idx": "167",
            "question": "美国唯一拥有皇宫的州是什么？",
            "answer": "夏威夷州（伊奥拉尼宫）"
        },
        {
            "idx": "231",
            "question": "大峡谷位于美国哪个州？",
            "answer": "亚利桑那州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "2",
            "question": "涉及碎肉和土豆泥的英格兰传统菜肴是什么？",
            "answer": "牧羊人派"
        },
        {
            "idx": "262",
            "question": "美国哪项修正案废除了禁酒令？",
            "answer": "第21修正案"
        },
        {
            "idx": "99",
            "question": "美国最大的淡水湖是什么？",
            "answer": "苏必利尔湖"
        },
        {
            "idx": "276",
            "question": "哪位美国总统被称为‘伟大的沟通者’？",
            "answer": "罗纳德·里根"
        },
        {
            "idx": "204",
            "question": "哪位英国君主建立了英格兰教会？",
            "answer": "亨利八世国王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "181",
            "question": "哪个美国州被称为‘第一州’？",
            "answer": "特拉华州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "72",
            "question": "签署北美自由贸易协定时的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "比尔·克林顿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "119",
            "question": "伊朗人质危机期间的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "吉米·卡特"
        },
        {
            "idx": "106",
            "question": "美国最大的河流系统叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "密西西比河系统"
        },
        {
            "idx": "101",
            "question": "英国哪个城市是披头士乐队的故乡？",
            "answer": "利物浦"
        },
        {
            "idx": "49",
            "question": "弗吉尼亚州的美国军事公墓叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "阿灵顿国家公墓"
        },
        {
            "idx": "169",
            "question": "标志着英国君主官方生日的英国仪式叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "军旗敬礼分列式"
        },
        {
            "idx": "89",
            "question": "1066年导致诺曼征服英格兰的战役是什么？",
            "answer": "黑斯廷斯战役"
        },
        {
            "idx": "118",
            "question": "哪位英国作家写了《哈利·波特》系列？",
            "answer": "J·K·罗琳"
        },
        {
            "idx": "63",
            "question": "美国最高法院在布朗诉教育委员会案中做出了什么里程碑式的决定？",
            "answer": "宣布为黑人和白人学生建立独立公立学校的州法律违宪"
        },
        {
            "idx": "95",
            "question": "哪个英国城市以其在英国内战中的关键作用而闻名？",
            "answer": "约克"
        },
        {
            "idx": "249",
            "question": "哪位美国总统以其在古巴导弹危机中的作用而闻名？",
            "answer": "约翰·F·肯尼迪"
        },
        {
            "idx": "253",
            "question": "英国民事案件以及来自英格兰、威尔士和北爱尔兰刑事案件的最高上诉法院叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "英国最高法院"
        },
        {
            "idx": "212",
            "question": "哪个英国城市被称为‘梦想尖塔之城’？",
            "answer": "牛津"
        },
        {
            "idx": "145",
            "question": "法国赠送给美国的著名地标是什么？",
            "answer": "自由女神像"
        },
        {
            "idx": "176",
            "question": "亚利桑那州著名的美国峡谷叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "大峡谷"
        },
        {
            "idx": "287",
            "question": "哪种英国甜点传统上配蛋奶沙司？",
            "answer": "斑点迪克"
        },
        {
            "idx": "52",
            "question": "哪座伦敦桥经常被游客误称为伦敦桥？",
            "answer": "塔桥"
        },
        {
            "idx": "261",
            "question": "1941年遭到袭击、导致美国卷入第二次世界大战的美国海军基地叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "珍珠港"
        },
        {
            "idx": "194",
            "question": "第一位任命女性担任最高法院大法官的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "罗纳德·里根（桑德拉·戴·奥康纳）"
        },
        {
            "idx": "160",
            "question": "1775年进行的美国独立战争的重要战役是什么？",
            "answer": "邦克山战役"
        },
        {
            "idx": "47",
            "question": "美国国歌叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "星条旗"
        },
        {
            "idx": "230",
            "question": "美国最大的沙漠叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "莫哈韦沙漠"
        },
        {
            "idx": "201",
            "question": "美国殖民地建立时的英格兰女王是谁？",
            "answer": "伊丽莎白一世女王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "114",
            "question": "哪个美国州是第一个将同性婚姻合法化的？",
            "answer": "马萨诸塞州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "70",
            "question": "哪个美国州是第一个批准宪法的？",
            "answer": "特拉华州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "187",
            "question": "哪位总统被认为发布了《解放奴隶宣言》？",
            "answer": "亚伯拉罕·林肯"
        },
        {
            "idx": "251",
            "question": "用猪血、燕麦和香料制作的传统英国菜是什么？",
            "answer": "血肠"
        },
        {
            "idx": "111",
            "question": "哪位英格兰国王在黑斯廷斯战役中被击败？",
            "answer": "哈罗德二世国王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "282",
            "question": "第一位住在白宫的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "约翰·亚当斯"
        },
        {
            "idx": "18",
            "question": "结束美国独立战争的条约叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "1783年巴黎条约"
        },
        {
            "idx": "53",
            "question": "哪个美国纪念碑纪念雕刻在山上的四位美国总统？",
            "answer": "拉什莫尔山"
        },
        {
            "idx": "109",
            "question": "按面积计算美国最大的州是什么？",
            "answer": "阿拉斯加州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "174",
            "question": "填充碎肉和土豆泥的传统英国派叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "农舍派"
        },
        {
            "idx": "128",
            "question": "美国在1941年参与的重大全球事件是什么？",
            "answer": "第二次世界大战"
        },
        {
            "idx": "150",
            "question": "第一个宣布从英国独立的美国殖民地叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "罗德岛"
        },
        {
            "idx": "161",
            "question": "哪个美国州被称为航空的发源地？",
            "answer": "俄亥俄州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "178",
            "question": "哪个美国城市以其历史悠久的缆车而闻名？",
            "answer": "加利福尼亚州旧金山"
        },
        {
            "idx": "208",
            "question": "哪个美国州以其大量阿米什人口而闻名？",
            "answer": "宾夕法尼亚州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "68",
            "question": "怀俄明州有间歇泉的著名美国国家公园叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "黄石国家公园"
        },
        {
            "idx": "138",
            "question": "美国最高的建筑是什么？",
            "answer": "世界贸易中心一号楼"
        },
        {
            "idx": "55",
            "question": "哪个美国城市以深盘披萨而闻名？",
            "answer": "芝加哥"
        },
        {
            "idx": "87",
            "question": "英国首相的住所叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "唐宁街10号"
        },
        {
            "idx": "248",
            "question": "哪个美国城市被称为美国海军的发源地？",
            "answer": "宾夕法尼亚州费城"
        },
        {
            "idx": "288",
            "question": "英国最长的河流是什么？",
            "answer": "塞文河"
        },
        {
            "idx": "12",
            "question": "哪个美国城市以其在美国汽车工业中的重要作用而闻名？",
            "answer": "密歇根州底特律"
        },
        {
            "idx": "31",
            "question": "哪个美国地标被称为‘美国堡垒’？",
            "answer": "诺克斯堡"
        },
        {
            "idx": "154",
            "question": "哪种英国奶酪传统上用于农夫午餐？",
            "answer": "切达干酪"
        },
        {
            "idx": "213",
            "question": "哪个英国城市在第二次世界大战期间的闪电战中遭到著名轰炸？",
            "answer": "伦敦"
        },
        {
            "idx": "134",
            "question": "下午晚些时候喝茶的英国传统叫什么名字，通常配三明治或糕点？",
            "answer": "下午茶"
        },
        {
            "idx": "189",
            "question": "哪位美国总统与‘我们唯一需要恐惧的就是恐惧本身’这句话有关？",
            "answer": "富兰克林·D·罗斯福"
        },
        {
            "idx": "129",
            "question": "哪个美国州以乳制品生产而闻名，通常被称为‘美国乳品之乡’？",
            "answer": "威斯康星州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "35",
            "question": "路易斯安那购地时的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "托马斯·杰斐逊"
        },
        {
            "idx": "86",
            "question": "哪位英国君主与英国历史的黄金时代有关？",
            "answer": "伊丽莎白一世女王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "105",
            "question": "在拿破仑战争期间以战胜拿破仑而闻名的英国海军旗官叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "纳尔逊勋爵海军上将"
        },
        {
            "idx": "84",
            "question": "第一位被弹劾的美国总统是谁？",
            "answer": "安德鲁·约翰逊"
        },
        {
            "idx": "88",
            "question": "哪个美国州被称为‘阳光州’？",
            "answer": "佛罗里达州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "91",
            "question": "哪个英国乐队在1960年代领导了美国音乐排行榜的英国入侵？",
            "answer": "披头士乐队"
        },
        {
            "idx": "218",
            "question": "1968年遇刺的美国民权领袖是谁？",
            "answer": "马丁·路德·金博士"
        },
        {
            "idx": "281",
            "question": "德克萨斯州的首府是什么？",
            "answer": "奥斯汀"
        },
        {
            "idx": "283",
            "question": "哪个美国城市是第一个使用地铁系统的？",
            "answer": "马萨诸塞州波士顿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "56",
            "question": "纽约市的昵称是什么？",
            "answer": "大苹果"
        },
        {
            "idx": "74",
            "question": "被称为'母亲之路'的著名路线叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "66号公路"
        },
        {
            "idx": "199",
            "question": "北美第一个永久性英国定居点是什么？",
            "answer": "弗吉尼亚州詹姆斯敦"
        },
        {
            "idx": "172",
            "question": "福克兰群岛战争期间的英国君主是谁？",
            "answer": "伊丽莎白二世女王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "260",
            "question": "美国内战的主要原因是什么？",
            "answer": "奴隶制和州权"
        },
        {
            "idx": "136",
            "question": "哪个美国地标刻有'给我你疲惫的、贫穷的、渴望自由呼吸的蜷缩大众'这些话？",
            "answer": "自由女神像"
        },
        {
            "idx": "155",
            "question": "发表'我有一个梦想'演讲的著名美国民权领袖叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "马丁·路德·金博士"
        },
        {
            "idx": "120",
            "question": "哪个英国城市历史上以造船业而闻名？",
            "answer": "格拉斯哥"
        },
        {
            "idx": "217",
            "question": "哪份文件正式结束了美国的奴隶制？",
            "answer": "第13修正案"
        },
        {
            "idx": "6",
            "question": "哪个英国城市以其历史悠久的大学和拉德克利夫摄影棚的所在地而闻名？",
            "answer": "牛津"
        },
        {
            "idx": "10",
            "question": "哪个美国州以土豆而闻名？",
            "answer": "爱达荷州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "22",
            "question": "谁被称为美国‘国家公园之父'？",
            "answer": "约翰·缪尔"
        },
        {
            "idx": "258",
            "question": "哪种英国硬币上有蓟花、韭葱和三叶草？",
            "answer": "一英镑硬币"
        },
        {
            "idx": "126",
            "question": "第一位担任美国国务卿的非裔美国人是谁？",
            "answer": "科林·鲍威尔"
        },
        {
            "idx": "270",
            "question": "纽约著名的美国证券交易所叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "纽约证券交易所"
        },
        {
            "idx": "77",
            "question": "按面积计算美国最小的州是什么？",
            "answer": "罗德岛州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "112",
            "question": "英国哪个城市以钢铁生产而闻名？",
            "answer": "谢菲尔德"
        },
        {
            "idx": "156",
            "question": "哪个美国州以其重要的美洲原住民历史和文化而闻名？",
            "answer": "新墨西哥州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "66",
            "question": "哪个美国城市被称为风城？",
            "answer": "伊利诺伊州芝加哥"
        },
        {
            "idx": "67",
            "question": "哪个英国城市以其在工业革命中的关键作用而闻名？",
            "answer": "曼彻斯特"
        },
        {
            "idx": "254",
            "question": "第一次将人类送上月球的航天器叫什么名字？",
            "answer": "阿波罗11号"
        },
        {
            "idx": "121",
            "question": "英格兰最大的湖是什么？",
            "answer": "温德米尔湖"
        },
        {
            "idx": "246",
            "question": "美国第二任总统是谁？",
            "answer": "约翰·亚当斯"
        },
        {
            "idx": "94",
            "question": "在伊丽莎白二世女王之前统治时间最长的英国君主是谁？",
            "answer": "维多利亚女王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "265",
            "question": "哪位美国总统启动了导致互联网创建的项目？",
            "answer": "德怀特·D·艾森豪威尔"
        },
        {
            "idx": "152",
            "question": "哪个美国州以其火山岛而闻名？",
            "answer": "夏威夷州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "76",
            "question": "哪个美国城市是美国的第一个首都？",
            "answer": "宾夕法尼亚州费城"
        },
        {
            "idx": "157",
            "question": "第一位英国女宇航员是谁？",
            "answer": "海伦·沙曼"
        },
        {
            "idx": "163",
            "question": "哪位英国君主继承了维多利亚女王？",
            "answer": "爱德华七世国王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "24",
            "question": "哪个美国城市被称为爵士乐的发源地？",
            "answer": "新奥尔良"
        },
        {
            "idx": "57",
            "question": "哪个美国州以生产最多玉米而闻名？",
            "answer": "爱荷华州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "28",
            "question": "哪位英国科学家发展了进化论？",
            "answer": "查尔斯·达尔文"
        },
        {
            "idx": "92",
            "question": "女王在伦敦的官方住所是什么？",
            "answer": "白金汉宫"
        },
        {
            "idx": "177",
            "question": "哪个美国城市举办了1984年夏季奥运会？",
            "answer": "加利福尼亚州洛杉矶"
        },
        {
            "idx": "4",
            "question": "哪位英国物理学家以其黑洞研究而闻名？",
            "answer": "斯蒂芬·霍金"
        }
    ],
    "ja": [
        {
            "idx": "139",
            "question": "どのアメリカの国立公園が超火山で有名ですか？",
            "answer": "イエローストーン国立公園"
        },
        {
            "idx": "5",
            "question": "バーボンから作られる伝統的な南部アメリカの飲み物は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ミントジュレップ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "34",
            "question": "1666年にロンドンの大部分を破壊した主要な出来事は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ロンドン大火"
        },
        {
            "idx": "182",
            "question": "羊の胃袋から作られる伝統的なスコットランド料理は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ハギス"
        },
        {
            "idx": "33",
            "question": "ハーパー・リーの小説『アラバマ物語』の主要テーマは何ですか？",
            "answer": "人種的不正義と道徳的成長"
        },
        {
            "idx": "252",
            "question": "ニューディール政策と関連するアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "フランクリン・D・ルーズベルト"
        },
        {
            "idx": "179",
            "question": "武器を持つ権利を規定するアメリカの修正条項はどれですか？",
            "answer": "修正第2条"
        },
        {
            "idx": "186",
            "question": "マルディグラの祭典で有名なアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ルイジアナ州ニューオーリンズ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "168",
            "question": "感謝祭で提供される伝統的なアメリカのデザートは何ですか？",
            "answer": "パンプキンパイ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "271",
            "question": "蒸気機関車の発明で知られるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ニューカッスル"
        },
        {
            "idx": "180",
            "question": "ローマ時代に建設された浴場で知られるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "バース"
        },
        {
            "idx": "45",
            "question": "ラシュモア山はアメリカのどの州にありますか？",
            "answer": "サウスダコタ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "285",
            "question": "南北戦争中にエイブラハム・リンカーンが行った有名な演説の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ゲティスバーグ演説"
        },
        {
            "idx": "221",
            "question": "1620年に巡礼者をアメリカに運んだ有名なイギリス船の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "メイフラワー号"
        },
        {
            "idx": "209",
            "question": "魚と揚げた衣で作られる伝統的なイギリス料理は何ですか？",
            "answer": "フィッシュアンドチップス"
        },
        {
            "idx": "166",
            "question": "アメリカ本土で最も高い山は何ですか？",
            "answer": "カリフォルニア州のマウント・ホイットニー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "214",
            "question": "タイタニック号の建造で知られるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ベルファスト"
        },
        {
            "idx": "48",
            "question": "「松の木の州」として知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "メイン州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "59",
            "question": "重力の法則で知られるイギリスの科学者は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "アイザック・ニュートン卿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "54",
            "question": "移民の家族再統合を優遇するアメリカ政府の政策を表す用語は何ですか？",
            "answer": "チェーン移民"
        },
        {
            "idx": "103",
            "question": "コーヒー文化によるシアトルのニックネームは何ですか？",
            "answer": "コーヒーの首都"
        },
        {
            "idx": "190",
            "question": "1969年の初回月面着陸時のアメリカ大統領は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "リチャード・ニクソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "278",
            "question": "アメリカ憲法の主要な起草者は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジェームズ・マディソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "240",
            "question": "最も多くの選挙人票を持つアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "カリフォルニア州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "61",
            "question": "「魔法の土地」として知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ニューメキシコ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "62",
            "question": "ネルソン提督が戦死した有名なイギリスの海戦の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "トラファルガーの海戦"
        },
        {
            "idx": "102",
            "question": "アンティークやヴィンテージ品で有名なロンドンの市場はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ポートベロー・ロード・マーケット"
        },
        {
            "idx": "175",
            "question": "シリコンバレーの発祥地として知られる地域の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "サンタクララ・バレー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "1",
            "question": "アメリカ大陸でのヨーロッパの植民地主義に反対したアメリカの政策の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "モンロー主義"
        },
        {
            "idx": "269",
            "question": "1963年の「雇用と自由のためのワシントン大行進」が行われたアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ワシントンD.C."
        },
        {
            "idx": "151",
            "question": "アメリカ憲法下で最初の首都となったアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ニューヨーク市"
        },
        {
            "idx": "93",
            "question": "1849年のゴールドラッシュの中心となったアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "カリフォルニア州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "23",
            "question": "重要なネイティブアメリカンの人口と歴史で知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "オクラホマ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "116",
            "question": "蒸気機関の発明で知られるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "バーミンガム"
        },
        {
            "idx": "245",
            "question": "電球の開発で知られるアメリカの発明家は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "トーマス・エジソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "196",
            "question": "「ボビー」として知られるイギリスの法執行官の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "警察官"
        },
        {
            "idx": "80",
            "question": "地球を周回した最初のアメリカ人宇宙飛行士は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジョン・グレン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "97",
            "question": "ワールドワイドウェブの発明で知られるイギリスの科学者は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ティム・バーナーズ＝リー卿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "148",
            "question": "スピーカーズ・コーナーがあるロンドンの公園はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ハイドパーク"
        },
        {
            "idx": "158",
            "question": "クリミア戦争中のイギリス君主は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "ヴィクトリア女王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "210",
            "question": "ジャズエイジについての作品で知られるアメリカの作家は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "F・スコット・フィッツジェラルド"
        },
        {
            "idx": "146",
            "question": "テネシー州で毎年開催される有名な音楽祭の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ボナルー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "164",
            "question": "イギリスの最高裁判所の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "イギリス最高裁判所"
        },
        {
            "idx": "104",
            "question": "医療診療で有名なロンドンの通りはどこですか？",
            "answer": "ハーレー街"
        },
        {
            "idx": "15",
            "question": "ローマ浴場で有名なイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "バース"
        },
        {
            "idx": "11",
            "question": "「棍棒外交」として知られる政策を導入したアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "セオドア・ルーズベルト"
        },
        {
            "idx": "14",
            "question": "イギリス初の女性首相は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "マーガレット・サッチャー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "39",
            "question": "「1万の湖の土地」として知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ミネソタ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "41",
            "question": "重要なクエーカー教徒の人口で知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ペンシルベニア州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "44",
            "question": "16世紀に世界一周で知られるイギリスの探検家は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "フランシス・ドレーク卿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "124",
            "question": "「最後のフロンティア」というニックネームを持つアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "アラスカ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "149",
            "question": "イギリスからのアメリカ植民地の独立を認めた条約は何ですか？",
            "answer": "1783年のパリ条約"
        },
        {
            "idx": "188",
            "question": "「シリコンバレー」と呼ばれることが多い重要な技術産業で知られるアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "カリフォルニア州サンノゼ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "228",
            "question": "自動車産業によるデトロイトのニックネームは何ですか？",
            "answer": "モーターシティ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "284",
            "question": "エリザベス1世の後を継ぎ、スチュアート朝の最初の君主となったイギリス君主は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジェームズ1世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "100",
            "question": "「世界を照らす自由」としても知られる有名なアメリカのランドマークの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "自由の女神"
        },
        {
            "idx": "279",
            "question": "「鉄の女」として知られるイギリスの政治家は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "マーガレット・サッチャー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "25",
            "question": "11月の第4木曜日に祝われるアメリカの祝日は何ですか？",
            "answer": "感謝祭"
        },
        {
            "idx": "184",
            "question": "神話の怪物で有名なスコットランドの湖はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ネス湖"
        },
        {
            "idx": "242",
            "question": "イギリス議会を構成する2つの院は何ですか？",
            "answer": "庶民院と貴族院"
        },
        {
            "idx": "170",
            "question": "女性に選挙権を与えたアメリカ憲法修正条項はどれですか？",
            "answer": "修正第19条"
        },
        {
            "idx": "275",
            "question": "高級車で知られる有名なイギリスのスポーツカーブランドの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "アストンマーティン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "277",
            "question": "2016年に起こった主要なイギリスの政治的出来事は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ブレグジット国民投票"
        },
        {
            "idx": "3",
            "question": "フィラデルフィアのニックネームは何ですか？",
            "answer": "兄弟愛の街"
        },
        {
            "idx": "21",
            "question": "南部で提供される伝統的なアメリカのパンは何ですか？",
            "answer": "コーンブレッド"
        },
        {
            "idx": "263",
            "question": "米墨戦争を終結させた条約の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "グアダルーペ・イダルゴ条約"
        },
        {
            "idx": "30",
            "question": "ラシュモア山に彫られた有名なアメリカの記念碑の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ラシュモア山国立記念碑"
        },
        {
            "idx": "173",
            "question": "イングランドの守護聖人は誰で、何日に祝われますか？",
            "answer": "聖ジョージ；聖ジョージの日は4月23日に祝われる"
        },
        {
            "idx": "107",
            "question": "果物とシェリー酒に浸したスポンジケーキを使った伝統的なイギリスのデザートは何ですか？",
            "answer": "トライフル"
        },
        {
            "idx": "192",
            "question": "マンチェスター・ユナイテッドとマンチェスター・シティという2つの有名なサッカークラブで知られるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "マンチェスター"
        },
        {
            "idx": "233",
            "question": "植民地時代の南部植民地の主要な経済活動は何でしたか？",
            "answer": "農業（特にタバコと綿花）"
        },
        {
            "idx": "78",
            "question": "ブリテン諸島で最も高い山は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ベン・ネビス"
        },
        {
            "idx": "243",
            "question": "第一次世界大戦中のイギリス君主は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "ジョージ5世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "273",
            "question": "連邦に最後に加入したアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ハワイ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "82",
            "question": "アメリカ初の女性最高裁判事は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "サンドラ・デイ・オコナー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "37",
            "question": "アメリカ最高裁判所で最も長く務めた判事は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ウィリアム・O・ダグラス"
        },
        {
            "idx": "144",
            "question": "ラスベガスのニックネームは何ですか？",
            "answer": "罪の街"
        },
        {
            "idx": "207",
            "question": "アメリカ議会に選出された最初のアフリカ系アメリカ人女性は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "シャーリー・チザム"
        },
        {
            "idx": "191",
            "question": "1936年にアメリカ人の離婚女性と結婚するために王位を放棄したイギリス王は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "エドワード8世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "229",
            "question": "アメリカの北部と南部地域によって戦われた戦争は何ですか？",
            "answer": "南北戦争"
        },
        {
            "idx": "32",
            "question": "アメリカで最大の保護区域は何ですか？",
            "answer": "アラスカ州のランゲル・セントエライアス国立公園・保護区"
        },
        {
            "idx": "250",
            "question": "マーティン・ルーサー・キング・ジュニアの有名な演説「私には夢がある」の主な主題は何ですか？",
            "answer": "公民権と人種平等"
        },
        {
            "idx": "132",
            "question": "1867年にロシアから購入されたアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "アラスカ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "244",
            "question": "1969年7月20日に起こった主要なアメリカの出来事は何ですか？",
            "answer": "アポロ11号の月面着陸"
        },
        {
            "idx": "259",
            "question": "ライト兄弟による最初の成功した飛行機の飛行が行われた都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ノースカロライナ州キティホーク"
        },
        {
            "idx": "232",
            "question": "最も多くの国立公園を持つアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "カリフォルニア州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "117",
            "question": "1802年に設立された有名なアメリカの陸軍士官学校の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ウェストポイント（アメリカ陸軍士官学校）"
        },
        {
            "idx": "46",
            "question": "イギリスの領土が独立を獲得する過程の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "脱植民地化"
        },
        {
            "idx": "69",
            "question": "太平洋への航海で知られるイギリスの探検家は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジェームズ・クック船長"
        },
        {
            "idx": "75",
            "question": "リバプールを流れる川の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "マージー川"
        },
        {
            "idx": "81",
            "question": "1964年の公民権法に署名したアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "リンドン・B・ジョンソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "60",
            "question": "アメリカ本土で最大の島は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ニューヨーク州ロングアイランド"
        },
        {
            "idx": "147",
            "question": "1998年にイギリス政府とアイルランド民族主義者の間で署名された歴史的合意の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "聖金曜日合意"
        },
        {
            "idx": "159",
            "question": "バーボンの生産で知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ケンタッキー州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "205",
            "question": "最初の電話をかけたことで知られるのは誰ですか？",
            "answer": "アレクサンダー・グラハム・ベル"
        },
        {
            "idx": "235",
            "question": "独立宣言を書いたのは誰ですか？",
            "answer": "トーマス・ジェファーソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "130",
            "question": "アメリカ独立戦争を終結させた条約は何ですか？",
            "answer": "1783年のパリ条約"
        },
        {
            "idx": "153",
            "question": "1973年に中絶を合法化したアメリカ最高裁判所の判例の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ロー対ウェイド事件"
        },
        {
            "idx": "215",
            "question": "イングランドにプロテスタント主義を確立した議会法は何ですか？",
            "answer": "1534年の首長令"
        },
        {
            "idx": "36",
            "question": "アメリカ合衆国の首都はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ワシントンD.C."
        },
        {
            "idx": "171",
            "question": "イギリスで最も高い尖塔を持つイギリスの大聖堂はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ソールズベリー大聖堂"
        },
        {
            "idx": "7",
            "question": "アメリカ合衆国で最大の島の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ハワイ島（ビッグアイランド）"
        },
        {
            "idx": "226",
            "question": "グレートブリテン島とヨーロッパ大陸を隔てる海の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "イギリス海峡"
        },
        {
            "idx": "220",
            "question": "1965年に可決され、選挙における人種差別を禁止した画期的な法律は何ですか？",
            "answer": "1965年の選挙権法"
        },
        {
            "idx": "140",
            "question": "第二次世界大戦の大部分の期間中のアメリカ大統領は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "フランクリン・D・ルーズベルト"
        },
        {
            "idx": "224",
            "question": "イングランドで最大の国立公園は何ですか？",
            "answer": "湖水地方国立公園"
        },
        {
            "idx": "42",
            "question": "自由と民主主義の象徴である有名なアメリカのランドマークの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "自由の鐘"
        },
        {
            "idx": "8",
            "question": "1964年の公民権法に署名したアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "リンドン・B・ジョンソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "90",
            "question": "バークシャーにあるイギリス王室の居住地の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ウィンザー城"
        },
        {
            "idx": "211",
            "question": "女王の公式ロンドン居住地の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "バッキンガム宮殿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "239",
            "question": "1929年のウォール街大暴落が導いた主要な出来事は何ですか？",
            "answer": "大恐慌"
        },
        {
            "idx": "51",
            "question": "映画とテレビの優秀性に対するイギリスの賞シリーズの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "BAFTA賞"
        },
        {
            "idx": "162",
            "question": "ブルース音楽の本場として知られるアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "テネシー州メンフィス"
        },
        {
            "idx": "137",
            "question": "エリザベス2世の治世を基にしたイギリスのテレビシリーズの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ザ・クラウン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "83",
            "question": "マグナカルタの署名時のイギリス君主は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "ジョン王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "58",
            "question": "アメリカ独立戦争で重要な役割を果たしたアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "マサチューセッツ州ボストン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "286",
            "question": "アメリカで最も忙しい空港はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ハーツフィールド・ジャクソン・アトランタ国際空港"
        },
        {
            "idx": "123",
            "question": "テムズ川沿いにある有名なイギリスの美術館の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "テート・モダン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "202",
            "question": "4期務めたアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "フランクリン・D・ルーズベルト"
        },
        {
            "idx": "19",
            "question": "「兄弟愛の街」として知られるアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ペンシルベニア州フィラデルフィア"
        },
        {
            "idx": "206",
            "question": "奴隷制の終了を祝うアメリカの祝日は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ジューンティーンス"
        },
        {
            "idx": "165",
            "question": "ボストン茶会事件の歴史的出来事で知られるアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "マサチューセッツ州ボストン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "108",
            "question": "「スクエア・ディール」で知られるアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "セオドア・ルーズベルト"
        },
        {
            "idx": "16",
            "question": "『高慢と偏見』を書いたイギリスの作家は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジェーン・オースティン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "185",
            "question": "面積で最大のアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "アラスカ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "43",
            "question": "歴史的な造船所とチャールズ・ディケンズの生誕地として知られるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ポーツマス"
        },
        {
            "idx": "289",
            "question": "グリニッジ王立天文台を通る経度線は何ですか？",
            "answer": "本初子午線"
        },
        {
            "idx": "183",
            "question": "イングランドで最も高い山を含むイギリスの国立公園はどこですか？",
            "answer": "湖水地方"
        },
        {
            "idx": "135",
            "question": "ウィンブルドンテニス選手権の開催地であるロンドンの区はどこですか？",
            "answer": "マートン区"
        },
        {
            "idx": "255",
            "question": "アメリカ太平洋艦隊の司令部であるアメリカ海軍基地の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "真珠湾"
        },
        {
            "idx": "257",
            "question": "アメリカで最も深い湖の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "クレーター湖"
        },
        {
            "idx": "267",
            "question": "平和部隊を設立したアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジョン・F・ケネディ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "264",
            "question": "ヨークシャープディングの生地にソーセージを入れたイギリス料理は何ですか？",
            "answer": "トード・イン・ザ・ホール"
        },
        {
            "idx": "113",
            "question": "ロンドンの地下鉄システムの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ロンドン地下鉄またはザ・チューブ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "280",
            "question": "病院で生まれた最初のアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジミー・カーター"
        },
        {
            "idx": "13",
            "question": "架空の探偵シャーロック・ホームズを創造したイギリスの作家は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "アーサー・コナン・ドイル卿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "73",
            "question": "アメリカ史上最も長く上演されているブロードウェイショーは何ですか？",
            "answer": "オペラ座の怪人"
        },
        {
            "idx": "96",
            "question": "イギリスで最も古い大学はどこですか？",
            "answer": "オックスフォード大学"
        },
        {
            "idx": "238",
            "question": "元々「ニュージャージー州」として知られていたアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ニュージャージー州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "133",
            "question": "国立鉄道博物館があるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ヨーク"
        },
        {
            "idx": "27",
            "question": "ロシアからアラスカを購入した時のアメリカ大統領は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "アンドリュー・ジョンソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "115",
            "question": "シャーウッドの森と関連する伝説的な無法者は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ロビン・フッド"
        },
        {
            "idx": "290",
            "question": "アメリカ選挙人団の主な機能は何ですか？",
            "answer": "大統領と副大統領を選出すること"
        },
        {
            "idx": "197",
            "question": "ディープディッシュピザで有名なアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "イリノイ州シカゴ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "236",
            "question": "イングランド国教会を設立したイギリス君主は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ヘンリー8世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "142",
            "question": "全国でブルーベリーの主要生産州であるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "メイン州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "227",
            "question": "職を辞任した最初のアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "リチャード・ニクソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "241",
            "question": "カナダ、オーストラリア、ニュージーランド、南アフリカに自治権を与えたイギリスの法律の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ウェストミンスター憲章"
        },
        {
            "idx": "110",
            "question": "イングランドのウィルトシャーにある有名な先史時代の記念碑の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ストーンヘンジ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "20",
            "question": "火星に着陸した最初の宇宙船は何ですか？",
            "answer": "バイキング1号"
        },
        {
            "idx": "223",
            "question": "セント・ポール大聖堂を設計したイギリスの建築家の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "クリストファー・レン卿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "125",
            "question": "オックスフォード大学とケンブリッジ大学の間で行われる年次スポーツイベントは何ですか？",
            "answer": "ボートレース"
        },
        {
            "idx": "9",
            "question": "アメリカで最も古い大学はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ハーバード大学"
        },
        {
            "idx": "203",
            "question": "サンフランシスコの有名な吊り橋の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ゴールデンゲートブリッジ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "79",
            "question": "現在最も長く在位しているイギリス君主の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "エリザベス2世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "98",
            "question": "主要政党でアメリカ大統領選に出馬した最初の女性は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ヒラリー・クリントン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "127",
            "question": "マサチューセッツ州にある有名なアメリカのアイビーリーグ大学の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ハーバード大学"
        },
        {
            "idx": "141",
            "question": "象徴的なグリルとスピリット・オブ・エクスタシーのマスコットで知られる有名なイギリスの高級車メーカーの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ロールス・ロイス"
        },
        {
            "idx": "225",
            "question": "ロビン・フッドの伝説と関連するイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ノッティンガム"
        },
        {
            "idx": "38",
            "question": "アメリカがイギリスからの独立を宣言したのは何年ですか？",
            "answer": "1776年"
        },
        {
            "idx": "219",
            "question": "ロンドンの有名な蝋人形館の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "マダム・タッソー館"
        },
        {
            "idx": "247",
            "question": "ロサンゼルスで毎年開催される有名なアメリカの音楽賞の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "グラミー賞"
        },
        {
            "idx": "256",
            "question": "「夢見る尖塔の街」として知られるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "オックスフォード"
        },
        {
            "idx": "198",
            "question": "シュールなスケッチショーで知られる有名なイギリスのコメディグループの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "モンティ・パイソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "131",
            "question": "ロンドンを流れる川の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "テムズ川"
        },
        {
            "idx": "29",
            "question": "サマセットで毎年開催される有名なイギリスの音楽祭の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "グラストンベリー・フェスティバル"
        },
        {
            "idx": "26",
            "question": "21世紀の始まりにイギリス首相だったのは誰ですか？",
            "answer": "トニー・ブレア"
        },
        {
            "idx": "85",
            "question": "画期的な判例ブラウン対教育委員会事件で最高裁判所が扱った主要な問題は何でしたか？",
            "answer": "学校の人種隔離"
        },
        {
            "idx": "195",
            "question": "アメリカ政府が授与する最高の軍事勲章は何ですか？",
            "answer": "名誉勲章"
        },
        {
            "idx": "200",
            "question": "ロンドンのウェストミンスター宮殿の北端にある有名な時計塔の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ビッグベン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "65",
            "question": "アメリカで最も古い公立大学はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ノースカロライナ大学チャペルヒル校"
        },
        {
            "idx": "222",
            "question": "イギリス東インド会社の設立時のイギリス君主は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "エリザベス1世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "274",
            "question": "ヴィクトリア朝時代に統治したイギリス君主は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ヴィクトリア女王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "268",
            "question": "環境保護庁の設立時のアメリカ大統領は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "リチャード・ニクソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "71",
            "question": "シカゴからロサンゼルスまで走る有名なアメリカの道路の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ルート66"
        },
        {
            "idx": "143",
            "question": "アメリカで最も人口の多い都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ニューヨーク市"
        },
        {
            "idx": "17",
            "question": "『1984年』と『動物農場』を書いたイギリスの作家は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジョージ・オーウェル"
        },
        {
            "idx": "50",
            "question": "英語圏で最も古いイギリスの大学はどこですか？",
            "answer": "オックスフォード大学"
        },
        {
            "idx": "237",
            "question": "エディンバラで毎年開催される有名な芸術祭の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "エディンバラ・フェスティバル・フリンジ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "193",
            "question": "1215年に署名され、ヨーロッパ史上最初の成文憲法として知られる文書は何ですか？",
            "answer": "マグナカルタ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "40",
            "question": "アメリカで最も長い川は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ミズーリ川"
        },
        {
            "idx": "122",
            "question": "イアン・フレミングが創造したイギリスのスパイキャラクターの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ジェームズ・ボンド"
        },
        {
            "idx": "216",
            "question": "「神の国」として知られるイギリスの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ヨークシャー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "234",
            "question": "りんごの木を植えることで知られる伝説的なアメリカの民話の英雄は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジョニー・アップルシード"
        },
        {
            "idx": "64",
            "question": "第二次世界大戦の大部分の期間中のイギリス首相は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "ウィンストン・チャーチル"
        },
        {
            "idx": "266",
            "question": "インディペンデント映画を紹介することで知られるアメリカの映画祭は何ですか？",
            "answer": "サンダンス映画祭"
        },
        {
            "idx": "272",
            "question": "幸運のために食べる伝統的な南部アメリカの元日料理は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ブラックアイドピー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "167",
            "question": "王宮を持つ唯一のアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ハワイ州（イオラニ宮殿）"
        },
        {
            "idx": "231",
            "question": "グランドキャニオンがあるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "アリゾナ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "2",
            "question": "ひき肉とマッシュポテトを使ったイングランドの伝統料理は何ですか？",
            "answer": "シェパーズパイ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "262",
            "question": "アメリカで禁酒法を廃止した修正条項はどれですか？",
            "answer": "修正第21条"
        },
        {
            "idx": "99",
            "question": "アメリカで最大の淡水湖は何ですか？",
            "answer": "スペリオル湖"
        },
        {
            "idx": "276",
            "question": "「偉大なコミュニケーター」として知られるアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ロナルド・レーガン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "204",
            "question": "イングランド国教会を設立したイギリス君主は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ヘンリー8世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "181",
            "question": "「最初の州」として知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "デラウェア州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "72",
            "question": "NAFTA協定の署名時のアメリカ大統領は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "ビル・クリントン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "119",
            "question": "イラン人質事件時のアメリカ大統領は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "ジミー・カーター"
        },
        {
            "idx": "106",
            "question": "アメリカで最大の河川システムの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ミシシッピ川水系"
        },
        {
            "idx": "101",
            "question": "ビートルズの故郷であるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "リバプール"
        },
        {
            "idx": "49",
            "question": "バージニア州にあるアメリカの軍事墓地の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "アーリントン国立墓地"
        },
        {
            "idx": "169",
            "question": "イギリス君主の公式誕生日を記念するイギリスの儀式の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "軍旗分列行進式"
        },
        {
            "idx": "89",
            "question": "1066年のノルマン征服につながった戦いは何ですか？",
            "answer": "ヘイスティングスの戦い"
        },
        {
            "idx": "118",
            "question": "『ハリー・ポッター』シリーズを書いたイギリスの作家は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "J.K.ローリング"
        },
        {
            "idx": "63",
            "question": "ブラウン対教育委員会事件でアメリカ最高裁判所が下した画期的な決定は何でしたか？",
            "answer": "黒人と白人の生徒のための別々の公立学校を設立する州法は違憲であると宣言した"
        },
        {
            "idx": "95",
            "question": "イングランド内戦で重要な役割を果たしたイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ヨーク"
        },
        {
            "idx": "249",
            "question": "キューバ危機での役割で知られるアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジョン・F・ケネディ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "253",
            "question": "イギリスで民事事件、およびイングランド、ウェールズ、北アイルランドからの刑事事件の最高上訴裁判所の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "イギリス最高裁判所"
        },
        {
            "idx": "212",
            "question": "「夢見る尖塔の街」として知られるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "オックスフォード"
        },
        {
            "idx": "145",
            "question": "フランスからアメリカへの贈り物だった有名なランドマークは何ですか？",
            "answer": "自由の女神"
        },
        {
            "idx": "176",
            "question": "アリゾナ州にある有名なアメリカの峡谷の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "グランドキャニオン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "287",
            "question": "伝統的にカスタードと一緒に提供されるイギリスのデザートは何ですか？",
            "answer": "スポッテッドディック"
        },
        {
            "idx": "52",
            "question": "観光客によってロンドンブリッジと間違えられることが多いロンドンの橋はどれですか？",
            "answer": "タワーブリッジ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "261",
            "question": "1941年に攻撃され、アメリカの第二次世界大戦参戦につながったアメリカ海軍基地の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "真珠湾"
        },
        {
            "idx": "194",
            "question": "最高裁判所に女性を任命した最初のアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ロナルド・レーガン（サンドラ・デイ・オコナー）"
        },
        {
            "idx": "160",
            "question": "1775年に戦われたアメリカ独立戦争の重要な戦いは何でしたか？",
            "answer": "バンカーヒルの戦い"
        },
        {
            "idx": "47",
            "question": "アメリカ合衆国の国歌の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "星条旗"
        },
        {
            "idx": "230",
            "question": "アメリカで最大の砂漠の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "モハーベ砂漠"
        },
        {
            "idx": "201",
            "question": "アメリカにイギリス植民地が設立された時のイングランド女王は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "エリザベス1世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "114",
            "question": "同性婚を最初に合法化したアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "マサチューセッツ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "70",
            "question": "憲法を最初に批准したアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "デラウェア州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "187",
            "question": "奴隷解放宣言で知られる大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "エイブラハム・リンカーン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "251",
            "question": "豚の血、オートミール、香辛料から作られる伝統的なイギリス料理は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ブラックプディング"
        },
        {
            "idx": "111",
            "question": "ヘイスティングスの戦いで敗北したイングランド王は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ハロルド2世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "282",
            "question": "ホワイトハウスに住んだ最初のアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジョン・アダムズ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "18",
            "question": "アメリカ独立戦争を終結させた条約の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "1783年のパリ条約"
        },
        {
            "idx": "53",
            "question": "山に彫られた4人のアメリカ大統領を称えるアメリカの記念碑は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ラシュモア山"
        },
        {
            "idx": "109",
            "question": "面積でアメリカ最大の州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "アラスカ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "174",
            "question": "ひき肉とマッシュポテトで満たされた伝統的なイギリスのパイの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "コテージパイ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "128",
            "question": "アメリカが1941年に参戦した主要な世界的出来事は何ですか？",
            "answer": "第二次世界大戦"
        },
        {
            "idx": "150",
            "question": "イギリスからの独立を最初に宣言したアメリカの植民地の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ロードアイランド"
        },
        {
            "idx": "161",
            "question": "航空の発祥地として知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "オハイオ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "178",
            "question": "歴史的なケーブルカーで有名なアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "カリフォルニア州サンフランシスコ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "208",
            "question": "大きなアーミッシュ人口で知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ペンシルベニア州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "68",
            "question": "ワイオミング州にある間欠泉で有名なアメリカの国立公園の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "イエローストーン国立公園"
        },
        {
            "idx": "138",
            "question": "アメリカで最も高い建物は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ワン・ワールド・トレード・センター"
        },
        {
            "idx": "55",
            "question": "ディープディッシュピザで有名なアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "シカゴ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "87",
            "question": "イギリス首相の邸宅の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ダウニング街10番地"
        },
        {
            "idx": "248",
            "question": "アメリカ海軍の発祥地として知られるアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ペンシルベニア州フィラデルフィア"
        },
        {
            "idx": "288",
            "question": "イギリスで最も長い川は何ですか？",
            "answer": "セヴァーン川"
        },
        {
            "idx": "12",
            "question": "アメリカの自動車産業で重要な役割を果たすアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ミシガン州デトロイト"
        },
        {
            "idx": "31",
            "question": "「アメリカの要塞」として知られるアメリカのランドマークはどれですか？",
            "answer": "フォートノックス"
        },
        {
            "idx": "154",
            "question": "プラウマンズランチで伝統的に使われるイギリスのチーズは何ですか？",
            "answer": "チェダー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "213",
            "question": "第二次世界大戦中のブリッツで有名に爆撃されたイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ロンドン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "134",
            "question": "イギリスで午後遅くに紅茶を飲む伝統的な習慣の名前は何ですか？通常、サンドイッチやペストリーと共に楽しむものです？",
            "answer": "アフタヌーンティー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "189",
            "question": "「我々が恐れるべきは恐怖そのものだけである」という言葉と関連するアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "フランクリン・D・ルーズベルト"
        },
        {
            "idx": "129",
            "question": "乳製品の生産で知られ、しばしば「アメリカの酪農地帯」と呼ばれるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ウィスコンシン州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "35",
            "question": "ルイジアナ購入時のアメリカ大統領は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "トーマス・ジェファーソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "86",
            "question": "イギリス史の黄金時代と関連するイギリス君主は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "エリザベス1世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "105",
            "question": "ナポレオン戦争中にナポレオンに対する勝利で知られるイギリス海軍旗艦将校の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ネルソン提督"
        },
        {
            "idx": "84",
            "question": "弾劾された最初のアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "アンドリュー・ジョンソン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "88",
            "question": "「サンシャイン州」として知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "フロリダ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "91",
            "question": "1960年代にアメリカの音楽チャートのブリティッシュ・インベージョンを率いたイギリスのバンドは何ですか？",
            "answer": "ビートルズ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "218",
            "question": "1968年に暗殺されたアメリカの公民権運動指導者は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "マーティン・ルーサー・キング・ジュニア"
        },
        {
            "idx": "281",
            "question": "テキサス州の州都はどこですか？",
            "answer": "オースティン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "283",
            "question": "地下鉄システムを最初に使用したアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "マサチューセッツ州ボストン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "56",
            "question": "ニューヨーク市のニックネームは何ですか？",
            "answer": "ビッグアップル"
        },
        {
            "idx": "74",
            "question": "「マザーロード」として知られる有名なルートの名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ルート66"
        },
        {
            "idx": "199",
            "question": "北アメリカで最初の永続的なイギリス植民地は何でしたか？",
            "answer": "バージニア州ジェームズタウン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "172",
            "question": "フォークランド戦争時のイギリス君主は誰でしたか？",
            "answer": "エリザベス2世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "260",
            "question": "アメリカ南北戦争の主要な原因は何でしたか？",
            "answer": "奴隷制と州権"
        },
        {
            "idx": "136",
            "question": "「疲れた者、貧しい者、自由に呼吸することを切望する群衆をよこせ」という言葉が刻まれているアメリカのランドマークはどれですか？",
            "answer": "自由の女神"
        },
        {
            "idx": "155",
            "question": "「私には夢がある」演説を行った有名なアメリカの公民権運動指導者の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "マーティン・ルーサー・キング・ジュニア"
        },
        {
            "idx": "120",
            "question": "造船業で歴史的に知られるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "グラスゴー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "217",
            "question": "アメリカで奴隷制を正式に終了させた文書は何ですか？",
            "answer": "修正第13条"
        },
        {
            "idx": "6",
            "question": "歴史的な大学とラドクリフ・カメラの所在地として知られるイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "オックスフォード"
        },
        {
            "idx": "10",
            "question": "ジャガイモで知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "アイダホ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "22",
            "question": "アメリカで「国立公園の父」として知られるのは誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジョン・ミューア"
        },
        {
            "idx": "258",
            "question": "アザミ、リーキ、シャムロックが描かれているイギリスの硬貨は何ですか？",
            "answer": "1ポンド硬貨"
        },
        {
            "idx": "126",
            "question": "アメリカ国務長官を務めた最初のアフリカ系アメリカ人は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "コリン・パウエル"
        },
        {
            "idx": "270",
            "question": "ニューヨークにある有名なアメリカの証券取引所の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ニューヨーク証券取引所（NYSE）"
        },
        {
            "idx": "77",
            "question": "面積で最も小さいアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ロードアイランド州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "112",
            "question": "鉄鋼生産で有名なイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "シェフィールド"
        },
        {
            "idx": "156",
            "question": "重要なネイティブアメリカンの歴史と文化で知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ニューメキシコ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "66",
            "question": "風の街として知られるアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "イリノイ州シカゴ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "67",
            "question": "産業革命で重要な役割を果たしたイギリスの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "マンチェスター"
        },
        {
            "idx": "254",
            "question": "人類を初めて月に着陸させた宇宙船の名前は何ですか？",
            "answer": "アポロ11号"
        },
        {
            "idx": "121",
            "question": "イングランドで最大の湖は何ですか？",
            "answer": "ウィンダミア湖"
        },
        {
            "idx": "246",
            "question": "アメリカ合衆国の第2代大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ジョン・アダムズ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "94",
            "question": "エリザベス2世以前に最も長く統治したイギリス君主は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ヴィクトリア女王"
        },
        {
            "idx": "265",
            "question": "インターネットの創設につながるプロジェクトを開始したアメリカ大統領は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ドワイト・D・アイゼンハワー"
        },
        {
            "idx": "152",
            "question": "火山島で知られるアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ハワイ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "76",
            "question": "アメリカ合衆国の最初の首都だったアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ペンシルベニア州フィラデルフィア"
        },
        {
            "idx": "157",
            "question": "最初のイギリス人女性宇宙飛行士は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "ヘレン・シャーマン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "163",
            "question": "ヴィクトリア女王の後を継いだイギリス君主は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "エドワード7世"
        },
        {
            "idx": "24",
            "question": "ジャズ音楽の発祥地として知られるアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "ニューオーリンズ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "57",
            "question": "最も多くのトウモロコシを生産するアメリカの州はどこですか？",
            "answer": "アイオワ州"
        },
        {
            "idx": "28",
            "question": "進化論を発達させたイギリスの科学者は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "チャールズ・ダーウィン"
        },
        {
            "idx": "92",
            "question": "女王の公式ロンドン居住地は何ですか？",
            "answer": "バッキンガム宮殿"
        },
        {
            "idx": "177",
            "question": "1984年夏季オリンピックを開催したアメリカの都市はどこですか？",
            "answer": "カリフォルニア州ロサンゼルス"
        },
        {
            "idx": "4",
            "question": "ブラックホールに関する研究で知られるイギリスの物理学者は誰ですか？",
            "answer": "スティーブン・ホーキング"
        }
    ],
    "th": [
        {
            "idx": "139",
            "question": "อุทยานแห่งชาติของสหรัฐฯ แห่งใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องภูเขาไฟใต้ดิน?",
            "answer": "อุทยานแห่งชาติเยลโลว์สโตน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "5",
            "question": "เครื่องดื่มแบบดั้งเดิมของภาคใต้สหรัฐฯ ที่ทำจากเบอร์บอนคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "มินต์ จูเล็ป"
        },
        {
            "idx": "34",
            "question": "เหตุการณ์สำคัญอะไรในปี ค.ศ. 1666 ที่ทำลายลอนดอนเป็นบริเวณกว้าง?",
            "answer": "อัคคีภัยใหญ่ของลอนดอน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "182",
            "question": "อาหารแบบดั้งเดิมของสกอตแลนด์ที่ทำจากกระเพาะแกะคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "แฮกกิส"
        },
        {
            "idx": "33",
            "question": "ธีมหลักของนวนิยาย 'To Kill a Mockingbird' โดย Harper Lee คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ความอยุติธรรมทางเชื้อชาติและการเติบโตทางศีลธรรม"
        },
        {
            "idx": "252",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนใดที่เกี่ยวข้องกับนิวดีล?",
            "answer": "แฟรงคลิน ดี. รูสเวลต์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "179",
            "question": "การแก้ไขรัฐธรรมนูญสหรัฐฯ ข้อใดที่ให้สิทธิในการถือครองอาวุธ?",
            "answer": "การแก้ไขข้อที่ 2"
        },
        {
            "idx": "186",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องการเฉลิมฉลองมาร์ดิกราส?",
            "answer": "นิวออร์ลีนส์, หลุยเซียนา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "168",
            "question": "ขนมหวานแบบดั้งเดิมของอเมริกันที่เสิร์ฟในวันขอบคุณพระเจ้าคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "พายฟักทอง"
        },
        {
            "idx": "271",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องการประดิษฐ์หัวรถจักรไอน้ำ?",
            "answer": "นิวคาสเซิล"
        },
        {
            "idx": "180",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องบ่อน้ำพุร้อนที่สร้างโดยชาวโรมัน?",
            "answer": "บาธ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "45",
            "question": "เมาท์รัชมอร์ตั้งอยู่ในรัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ?",
            "answer": "เซาท์ดาโคตา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "285",
            "question": "ชื่อของสุนทรพจน์ที่มีชื่อเสียงที่อับราฮัม ลินคอล์นกล่าวในช่วงสงครามกลางเมืองอเมริกันคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "สุนทรพจน์เก็ตตีสเบิร์ก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "221",
            "question": "ชื่อของเรืออังกฤษที่มีชื่อเสียงที่นำพิลกริมไปอเมริกาในปี ค.ศ. 1620 คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เมย์ฟลาวเวอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "209",
            "question": "อาหารแบบดั้งเดิมของอังกฤษที่ทำจากปลาและแป้งทอดคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ฟิชแอนด์ชิปส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "166",
            "question": "ภูเขาที่สูงที่สุดในสหรัฐฯ ทวีป (ไม่รวมอลาสกาและฮาวาย) คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เมาท์วิทนีย์, แคลิฟอร์เนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "214",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องการสร้างไททานิก?",
            "answer": "เบลฟาสต์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "48",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เรียกว่า 'รัฐต้นไผ่'?",
            "answer": "เมน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "59",
            "question": "นักวิทยาศาสตร์อังกฤษคนใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องกฎแรงโน้มถ่วง?",
            "answer": "เซอร์ไอแซก นิวตัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "54",
            "question": "คำที่ใช้อธิบายนโยบายของรัฐบาลสหรัฐฯ ที่สนับสนุนการรวมครอบครัวสำหรับผู้อพยพคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "การอพยพแบบลูกโซ่"
        },
        {
            "idx": "103",
            "question": "ชื่อเล่นของซีแอตเทิลเนื่องจากวัฒนธรรมกาแฟคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เมืองหลวงกาแฟ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "190",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ ในช่วงการลงจอดบนดวงจันทร์ครั้งแรกในปี ค.ศ. 1969?",
            "answer": "ริชาร์ด นิกสัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "278",
            "question": "ใครเป็นผู้เขียนหลักของรัฐธรรมนูญสหรัฐฯ?",
            "answer": "เจมส์ แมดิสัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "240",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีคะแนนเลือกตั้งมากที่สุด?",
            "answer": "แคลิฟอร์เนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "61",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เรียกว่า 'ดินแดนแห่งความมหัศจรรย์'?",
            "answer": "นิวเม็กซิโก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "62",
            "question": "ชื่อของการรบอังกฤษที่มีชื่อเสียงที่พลเรือเอกลอร์ดเนลสันเสียชีวิตคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ยุทธนาวีทราฟัลการ์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "102",
            "question": "ตลาดลอนดอนใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องของเก่าและของวินเทจ?",
            "answer": "ตลาดพอร์โตเบลโล่โร้ด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "175",
            "question": "ชื่อของภูมิภาคที่เป็นที่รู้จักในฐานะบ้านเกิดของซิลิคอนวัลเลย์คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ซานตาคลาราวัลเลย์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "1",
            "question": "ชื่อของหลักคำสอนสหรัฐฯ ที่ต่อต้านการล่าอาณานิคมของยุโรปในทวีปอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "หลักคำสอนมอนโร"
        },
        {
            "idx": "269",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เป็นสถานที่จัด 'การเดินขบวนเพื่องานและเสรีภาพ' ในปี ค.ศ. 1963?",
            "answer": "วอชิงตัน ดี.ซี."
        },
        {
            "idx": "151",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เป็นเมืองหลวงแห่งแรกภายใต้รัฐธรรมนูญสหรัฐฯ?",
            "answer": "นิวยอร์กซิตี้"
        },
        {
            "idx": "93",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เป็นศูนย์กลางของการแสวงหาทองคำในปี ค.ศ. 1849?",
            "answer": "แคลิฟอร์เนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "23",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องประชากรและประวัติศาสตร์ของชาวอเมริกันพื้นเมืองที่สำคัญ?",
            "answer": "โอคลาโฮมา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "116",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องการประดิษฐ์เครื่องยนต์ไอน้ำ?",
            "answer": "เบอร์มิงแฮม"
        },
        {
            "idx": "245",
            "question": "ใครเป็นนักประดิษฐ์อเมริกันที่มีชื่อเสียงในการพัฒนาหลอดไฟฟ้า?",
            "answer": "โทมัส เอดิสัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "196",
            "question": "ชื่อของเจ้าหน้าที่บังคับใช้กฎหมายอังกฤษที่เรียกว่า 'บ็อบบี้' คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เจ้าหน้าที่ตำรวจ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "80",
            "question": "ใครเป็นนักบินอวกาศอเมริกันคนแรกที่โคจรรอบโลก?",
            "answer": "จอห์น เกล็นน์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "97",
            "question": "นักวิทยาศาสตร์อังกฤษคนใดที่ได้รับเครดิตในการประดิษฐ์เวิลด์ไวด์เว็บ?",
            "answer": "เซอร์ทิม เบอร์เนอร์ส-ลี"
        },
        {
            "idx": "148",
            "question": "สวนลอนดอนใดที่มีสปีกเกอร์ส คอร์เนอร์?",
            "answer": "ไฮด์พาร์ก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "158",
            "question": "ใครเป็นกษัตริย์อังกฤษในช่วงสงครามไครเมียน?",
            "answer": "พระราชินีวิกตอเรีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "210",
            "question": "ใครเป็นนักเขียนอเมริกันที่มีชื่อเสียงในผลงานเกี่ยวกับยุคแจ๊ส?",
            "answer": "เอฟ. สก็อตต์ ฟิตซ์เจอรัลด์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "146",
            "question": "ชื่อของเทศกาลดนตรีที่มีชื่อเสียงที่จัดขึ้นประจำปีในเทนเนสซีคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "บอนนารู"
        },
        {
            "idx": "164",
            "question": "ชื่อของศาลสูงสุดในสหราชอาณาจักรคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ศาลสูงสุดแห่งสหราชอาณาจักร"
        },
        {
            "idx": "104",
            "question": "ถนนลอนดอนใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องการรักษาพยาบาล?",
            "answer": "ฮาร์เลย์สตรีท"
        },
        {
            "idx": "15",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหราชอาณาจักรที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องบ่อน้ำพุร้อนโรมัน?",
            "answer": "บาธ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "11",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนใดที่แนะนำนโยบายที่เรียกว่า 'การทูตไม้ใหญ่'?",
            "answer": "ธีโอดอร์ รูสเวลต์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "14",
            "question": "ใครเป็นนายกรัฐมนตรีหญิงคนแรกของสหราชอาณาจักร?",
            "answer": "มาร์กาเร็ต แธตเชอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "39",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เรียกว่า 'ดินแดนแห่งทะเลสาบ 10,000 แห่ง'?",
            "answer": "มินนิโซตา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "41",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องประชากรเควกเกอร์ที่สำคัญ?",
            "answer": "เพนซิลเวเนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "44",
            "question": "นักสำรวจอังกฤษคนใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในการเดินทางรอบโลกในศตวรรษที่ 16?",
            "answer": "เซอร์ฟรานซิส เดรก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "124",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเล่นว่า 'ดินแดนสุดท้าย'?",
            "answer": "อลาสกา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "149",
            "question": "สนธิสัญญาใดที่ยอมรับเอกราชของอาณานิคมอเมริกันจากอังกฤษ?",
            "answer": "สนธิสัญญาปารีส ค.ศ. 1783"
        },
        {
            "idx": "188",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องอุตสาหกรรมเทคโนโลยีที่สำคัญ ซึ่งมักเรียกว่า 'ซิลิคอนวัลเลย์'?",
            "answer": "ซานโฮเซ, แคลิฟอร์เนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "228",
            "question": "ชื่อเล่นของดีทรอยต์เนื่องจากอุตสาหกรรมยานยนต์คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เมืองมอเตอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "284",
            "question": "กษัตริย์อังกฤษพระองค์ใดที่สืบทอดพระราชินีเอลิซาเบธที่ 1 และเป็นพระองค์แรกของราชวงศ์สจ๊วต?",
            "answer": "พระเจ้าเจมส์ที่ 1"
        },
        {
            "idx": "100",
            "question": "ชื่อของสถานที่สำคัญของอเมริกาที่เรียกอีกอย่างว่า 'เสรีภาพส่องแสงโลก' คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เทพีเสรีภาพ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "279",
            "question": "บุคคลการเมืองอังกฤษคนใดที่เรียกว่า 'สตรีเหล็ก'?",
            "answer": "มาร์กาเร็ต แธตเชอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "25",
            "question": "วันหยุดอเมริกันใดที่ฉลองในวันพฤหัสบดีที่สี่ของเดือนพฤศจิกายน?",
            "answer": "วันขอบคุณพระเจ้า"
        },
        {
            "idx": "184",
            "question": "ทะเลสาบสกอตแลนด์ใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องสัตว์ประหลาดในตำนาน?",
            "answer": "ล็อคเนส"
        },
        {
            "idx": "242",
            "question": "สภาสองสภาใดที่ประกอบเป็นรัฐสภาสหราชอาณาจักร?",
            "answer": "สภาสามัญและสภาขุนนาง"
        },
        {
            "idx": "170",
            "question": "การแก้ไขรัฐธรรมนูญสหรัฐฯ ข้อใดที่ให้สิทธิการเลือกตั้งแก่สตรี?",
            "answer": "การแก้ไขข้อที่ 19"
        },
        {
            "idx": "275",
            "question": "ชื่อของแบรนด์รถสปอร์ตอังกฤษที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องยานพาหนะหรูหราคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "แอสตัน มาร์ติน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "277",
            "question": "เหตุการณ์การเมืองสำคัญของอังกฤษอะไรที่เกิดขึ้นในปี ค.ศ. 2016?",
            "answer": "การลงประชามติเบร็กซิต"
        },
        {
            "idx": "3",
            "question": "ชื่อเล่นของฟิลาเดลเฟียคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เมืองแห่งความรักใคร่"
        },
        {
            "idx": "21",
            "question": "ขนมปังแบบดั้งเดิมของอเมริกันที่เสิร์ฟในภาคใต้คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ขนมปังข้าวโพด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "263",
            "question": "ชื่อของสนธิสัญญาที่ยุติสงครามเม็กซิกัน-อเมริกันคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "สนธิสัญญากวาดาลูเปอิดัลโก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "30",
            "question": "ชื่อของอนุสาวรีย์อเมริกันที่มีชื่อเสียงที่แกะสลักในเมาท์รัชมอร์คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "อนุสาวรีย์แห่งชาติเมาท์รัชมอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "173",
            "question": "ใครเป็นนักบุญอุปถัมภ์ของอังกฤษและวันใดที่ฉลองเพื่อเป็นเกียรติแก่ท่าน?",
            "answer": "นักบุญจอร์จ; วันนักบุญจอร์จฉลองในวันที่ 23 เมษายน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "107",
            "question": "ขนมหวานแบบดั้งเดิมของอังกฤษที่มีผลไม้และเค้กสปันจ์แช่เชอร์รี่คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ไตรเฟิล"
        },
        {
            "idx": "192",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องสโมสรฟุตบอลสองทีมที่มีชื่อเสียง คือ แมนเชสเตอร์ ยูไนเต็ด และ แมนเชสเตอร์ ซิตี้?",
            "answer": "แมนเชสเตอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "233",
            "question": "กิจกรรมทางเศรษฐกิจหลักในอาณานิคมภาคใต้ในช่วงยุคอาณานิคมคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เกษตรกรรม (โดยเฉพาะยาสูบและฝ้าย)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "78",
            "question": "ภูเขาที่สูงที่สุดในหมู่เกาะอังกฤษคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เบนเนวิส"
        },
        {
            "idx": "243",
            "question": "ใครเป็นกษัตริย์อังกฤษในช่วงสงครามโลกครั้งที่ 1?",
            "answer": "พระเจ้าจอร์จที่ 5"
        },
        {
            "idx": "273",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เข้าร่วมสหภาพเป็นรัฐสุดท้าย?",
            "answer": "ฮาวาย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "82",
            "question": "ใครเป็นผู้พิพากษาศาลสูงสุดหญิงคนแรกในสหรัฐอเมริกา?",
            "answer": "แซนดรา เดย์ โอคอนเนอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "37",
            "question": "ใครเป็นผู้พิพากษาศาลสูงสุดสหรัฐฯ ที่ดำรงตำแหน่งนานที่สุด?",
            "answer": "วิลเลียม โอ. ดักลาส"
        },
        {
            "idx": "144",
            "question": "ชื่อเล่นของลาสเวกัสคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เมืองบาป"
        },
        {
            "idx": "207",
            "question": "ใครเป็นหญิงแอฟริกัน-อเมริกันคนแรกที่ได้รับเลือกเข้าสภาคองเกรสสหรัฐฯ?",
            "answer": "เชอร์ลีย์ ชิชโฮล์ม"
        },
        {
            "idx": "191",
            "question": "กษัตริย์อังกฤษพระองค์ใดที่สละราชสมบัติในปี ค.ศ. 1936 เพื่อแต่งงานกับหญิงอเมริกันที่หย่าร้าง?",
            "answer": "พระเจ้าเอ็ดเวิร์ดที่ 8"
        },
        {
            "idx": "229",
            "question": "สงครามใดที่ต่อสู้กันระหว่างภาคเหนือและภาคใต้ในสหรัฐอเมริกา?",
            "answer": "สงครามกลางเมือง"
        },
        {
            "idx": "32",
            "question": "พื้นที่คุ้มครองที่ใหญ่ที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "อุทยานแห่งชาติและเขตอนุรักษ์แรงเกล-เซนต์อีไลแอส, อลาสกา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "250",
            "question": "หัวข้อหลักของสุนทรพจน์ที่มีชื่อเสียง 'ฉันมีความฝัน' โดยมาร์ติน ลูเธอร์ คิง จูเนียร์ คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "สิทธิพลเมืองและความเท่าเทียมทางเชื้อชาติ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "132",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่ซื้อจากรัสเซียในปี ค.ศ. 1867?",
            "answer": "อลาสกา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "244",
            "question": "เหตุการณ์สำคัญของสหรัฐฯ อะไรที่เกิดขึ้นในวันที่ 20 กรกฎาคม ค.ศ. 1969?",
            "answer": "การลงจอดบนดวงจันทร์ของอพอลโล 11"
        },
        {
            "idx": "259",
            "question": "การบินครั้งแรกที่สำเร็จของพี่น้องไรท์เกิดขึ้นในเมืองใด?",
            "answer": "คิตตี้ฮอว์ก, นอร์ทแคโรไลนา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "232",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีอุทยานแห่งชาติมากที่สุด?",
            "answer": "แคลิฟอร์เนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "117",
            "question": "ชื่อของโรงเรียนนายร้อยสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงที่ก่อตั้งในปี ค.ศ. 1802 คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เวสต์พอยต์ (โรงเรียนนายร้อยสหรัฐอเมริกา)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "46",
            "question": "ชื่อของกระบวนการที่ดินแดนอังกฤษได้รับเอกราชคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "การยกเลิกการเป็นอาณานิคม"
        },
        {
            "idx": "69",
            "question": "นักสำรวจอังกฤษคนใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในการเดินทางไปมหาสมุทรแปซิฟิก?",
            "answer": "กัปตันเจมส์ คุก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "75",
            "question": "ชื่อของแม่น้ำที่ไหลผ่านลิเวอร์พูลคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "แม่น้ำเมอร์ซีย์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "81",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนใดที่ลงนามในพระราชบัญญัติสิทธิพลเมือง ค.ศ. 1964?",
            "answer": "ลินดอน บี. จอห์นสัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "60",
            "question": "เกาะที่ใหญ่ที่สุดในสหรัฐฯ ทวีป (ไม่รวมอลาสกาและฮาวาย) คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ลองไอแลนด์, นิวยอร์ก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "147",
            "question": "ชื่อของข้อตกลงทางประวัติศาสตร์ที่ลงนามระหว่างรัฐบาลอังกฤษและชาตินิยมไอริชในปี ค.ศ. 1998 คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ข้อตกลงวันศุกร์ดี"
        },
        {
            "idx": "159",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในการผลิตเบอร์บอน?",
            "answer": "เคนตักกี้"
        },
        {
            "idx": "205",
            "question": "ใครที่มีชื่อเสียงในการโทรศัพท์ครั้งแรก?",
            "answer": "อเล็กซานเดอร์ เกรแฮม เบลล์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "235",
            "question": "ใครเป็นผู้เขียนปฏิญญาอิสรภาพ?",
            "answer": "โทมัส เจฟเฟอร์สัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "130",
            "question": "สนธิสัญญาใดที่ยุติสงครามปฏิวัติอเมริกัน?",
            "answer": "สนธิสัญญาปารีส ค.ศ. 1783"
        },
        {
            "idx": "153",
            "question": "ชื่อของคดีศาลสูงสุดสหรัฐฯ ที่ทำให้การทำแท้งถูกกฎหมายในปี ค.ศ. 1973 คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "โร เทียบ เวด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "215",
            "question": "พระราชบัญญัติของรัฐสภาใดที่ก่อตั้งโปรเตสแตนต์ในอังกฤษ?",
            "answer": "พระราชบัญญัติอำนาจสูงสุด ค.ศ. 1534"
        },
        {
            "idx": "36",
            "question": "เมืองหลวงของสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "วอชิงตัน ดี.ซี."
        },
        {
            "idx": "171",
            "question": "มหาวิหารใดของสหราชอาณาจักรที่มียอดแหลมสูงที่สุดในอังกฤษ?",
            "answer": "มหาวิหารซาลิสเบอรี"
        },
        {
            "idx": "7",
            "question": "ชื่อของเกาะที่ใหญ่ที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ฮาวาย (บิ๊กไอแลนด์)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "226",
            "question": "ชื่อของทะเลที่แยกเกรตบริเตนจากทวีปยุโรปคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ช่องแคบอังกฤษ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "220",
            "question": "กฎหมายสำคัญอะไรที่ผ่านในปี ค.ศ. 1965 เพื่อห้ามการเลือกปฏิบัติทางเชื้อชาติในการเลือกตั้ง?",
            "answer": "พระราชบัญญัติสิทธิการเลือกตั้ง ค.ศ. 1965"
        },
        {
            "idx": "140",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ ในช่วงส่วนใหญ่ของสงครามโลกครั้งที่ 2?",
            "answer": "แฟรงคลิน ดี. รูสเวลต์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "224",
            "question": "อุทยานแห่งชาติที่ใหญ่ที่สุดในอังกฤษคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "อุทยานแห่งชาติเลกดิสทริกต์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "42",
            "question": "ชื่อของสถานที่สำคัญของอเมริกาที่มีชื่อเสียงที่เป็นสัญลักษณ์ของเสรีภาพและประชาธิปไตยคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ระฆังเสรีภาพ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "8",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนใดที่ลงนามในพระราชบัญญัติสิทธิพลเมือง ค.ศ. 1964?",
            "answer": "ลินดอน บี. จอห์นสัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "90",
            "question": "ชื่อของที่พำนักหลวงอังกฤษที่ตั้งอยู่ในเบิร์กเชียร์คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ปราสาทวินด์เซอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "211",
            "question": "ชื่อของที่พำนักหลวงอย่างเป็นทางการของพระราชินีในลอนดอนคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "พระราชวังบักกิงแฮม"
        },
        {
            "idx": "239",
            "question": "เหตุการณ์สำคัญอะไรที่การล่มสลายของวอลล์สตรีทในปี ค.ศ. 1929 นำไปสู่?",
            "answer": "ภาวะเศรษฐกิจตกต่ำครั้งใหญ่"
        },
        {
            "idx": "51",
            "question": "ชื่อของรางวัลอังกฤษสำหรับความเป็นเลิศในภาพยนตร์และโทรทัศน์คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "รางวัลบาฟตา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "162",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่รู้จักกันในฐานะบ้านเกิดของดนตรีบลูส?",
            "answer": "เมมฟิส, เทนเนสซี"
        },
        {
            "idx": "137",
            "question": "ชื่อของซีรีส์โทรทัศน์อังกฤษที่อิงจากรัชสมัยของพระราชินีเอลิซาเบธที่ 2 คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เดอะคราวน์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "83",
            "question": "ใครเป็นกษัตริย์อังกฤษในช่วงการลงนามในแมกนาคาร์ตา?",
            "answer": "พระเจ้าจอห์น"
        },
        {
            "idx": "58",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในบทบาทสำคัญในการปฏิวัติอเมริกัน?",
            "answer": "บอสตัน, แมสซาชูเซตส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "286",
            "question": "สนามบินที่พลุกพล่านที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "สนามบินนานาชาติฮาร์ทส์ฟิลด์-แจ็กสัน แอตแลนตา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "123",
            "question": "ชื่อของหอศิลป์อังกฤษที่มีชื่อเสียงที่ตั้งอยู่ริมแม่น้ำเทมส์คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เทต โมเดิร์น"
        },
        {
            "idx": "202",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนใดที่ดำรงตำแหน่งสี่วาระ?",
            "answer": "แฟรงคลิน ดี. รูสเวลต์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "19",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เรียกว่า 'เมืองแห่งความรักใคร่'?",
            "answer": "ฟิลาเดลเฟีย, เพนซิลเวเนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "206",
            "question": "วันหยุดใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่ฉลองการสิ้นสุดของการเป็นทาส?",
            "answer": "จูนทีนท์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "165",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในเหตุการณ์ทางประวัติศาสตร์ของบอสตันทีปาร์ตี้?",
            "answer": "บอสตัน, แมสซาชูเซตส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "108",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่อง 'สแควร์ดีล'?",
            "answer": "ธีโอดอร์ รูสเวลต์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "16",
            "question": "นักเขียนอังกฤษคนใดที่เขียน 'ความภาคภูมิใจและอคติ'?",
            "answer": "เจน ออสเตน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "185",
            "question": "รัฐที่ใหญ่ที่สุดของสหรัฐฯ ตามพื้นที่คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "อลาสกา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "43",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องอู่ต่อเรือทางประวัติศาสตร์และเป็นบ้านเกิดของชาร์ลส์ ดิกเกนส์?",
            "answer": "พอร์ตสมัท"
        },
        {
            "idx": "289",
            "question": "เส้นลองจิจูดที่ผ่านหอดูดาวหลวงในกรีนิชคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เส้นแรกของโลก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "183",
            "question": "อุทยานแห่งชาติใดของสหราชอาณาจักรที่มีภูเขาที่สูงที่สุดในอังกฤษ?",
            "answer": "เลกดิสทริกต์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "135",
            "question": "เขตลอนดอนใดที่เป็นที่ตั้งของการแข่งขันเทนนิสวิมเบิลดัน?",
            "answer": "เมอร์ตัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "255",
            "question": "ชื่อของฐานทัพเรือสหรัฐฯ ที่เป็นสำนักงานใหญ่ของกองเรือแปซิฟิกสหรัฐฯ คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เพิร์ลฮาร์เบอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "257",
            "question": "ชื่อของทะเลสาบที่ลึกที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ทะเลสาบเครเตอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "267",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนใดที่ก่อตั้งคณะอาสาสมัครเพื่อสันติภาพ?",
            "answer": "จอห์น เอฟ. เคนเนดี"
        },
        {
            "idx": "264",
            "question": "อาหารอังกฤษใดที่ประกอบด้วยไส้กรอกในแป้งยอร์กเชียร์พุดดิ้ง?",
            "answer": "โทดอินเดอะโฮล"
        },
        {
            "idx": "113",
            "question": "ชื่อของระบบรถไฟใต้ดินในลอนดอนคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "รถไฟใต้ดินลอนดอน หรือ เดอะทิวบ์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "280",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนแรกที่เกิดในโรงพยาบาล?",
            "answer": "จิมมี่ คาร์เตอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "13",
            "question": "นักเขียนอังกฤษคนใดที่สร้างนักสืบในนิยายเชอร์ล็อค โฮล์มส์?",
            "answer": "เซอร์อาร์เธอร์ โคนัน ดอยล์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "73",
            "question": "การแสดงบรอดเวย์ที่แสดงยาวนานที่สุดในประวัติศาสตร์อเมริกันคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เดอะแฟนทอมออฟดิโอเปร่า"
        },
        {
            "idx": "96",
            "question": "มหาวิทยาลัยที่เก่าแก่ที่สุดในสหราชอาณาจักรคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "มหาวิทยาลัยออกซ์ฟอร์ด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "238",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เดิมเรียกว่า 'จังหวัดนิวเจอร์ซีย์'?",
            "answer": "นิวเจอร์ซีย์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "133",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหราชอาณาจักรที่เป็นที่ตั้งของพิพิธภัณฑ์รถไฟแห่งชาติ?",
            "answer": "ยอร์ก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "27",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ ในช่วงการซื้ออลาสกาจากรัสเซีย?",
            "answer": "แอนดรูว์ จอห์นสัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "115",
            "question": "ใครเป็นโจรในตำนานที่เกี่ยวข้องกับป่าเชอร์วูด?",
            "answer": "โรบินฮู้ด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "290",
            "question": "หน้าที่หลักของคณะผู้เลือกตั้งสหรัฐฯ คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เพื่อเลือกประธานาธิบดีและรองประธานาธิบดี"
        },
        {
            "idx": "197",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องพิซซ่าจานลึก?",
            "answer": "ชิคาโก, อิลลินอยส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "236",
            "question": "กษัตริย์อังกฤษพระองค์ใดที่ก่อตั้งศาสนจักรแห่งอังกฤษ?",
            "answer": "พระเจ้าเฮนรี่ที่ 8"
        },
        {
            "idx": "142",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เป็นผู้ผลิตบลูเบอร์รี่อันดับหนึ่งของประเทศ?",
            "answer": "เมน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "227",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนแรกที่ลาออกจากตำแหน่ง?",
            "answer": "ริชาร์ด นิกสัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "241",
            "question": "ชื่อของกฎหมายอังกฤษที่ให้การปกครองตนเองแก่แคนาดา ออสเตรเลีย นิวซีแลนด์ และแอฟริกาใต้คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "กฎหมายเวสต์มินสเตอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "110",
            "question": "ชื่อของอนุสาวรีย์ยุคก่อนประวัติศาสตร์ที่มีชื่อเสียงที่ตั้งอยู่ในวิลต์เชียร์ ประเทศอังกฤษ คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "สโตนเฮนจ์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "20",
            "question": "ยานอวกาศลำแรกที่ลงจอดบนดาวอังคารคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ไวกิ้ง 1"
        },
        {
            "idx": "223",
            "question": "ชื่อของสถาปนิกอังกฤษที่ออกแบบมหาวิหารเซนต์พอล คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เซอร์คริสโตเฟอร์ เรน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "125",
            "question": "การแข่งขันกีฬาประจำปีอะไรที่จัดขึ้นระหว่างมหาวิทยาลัยออกซ์ฟอร์ดและเคมบริดจ์?",
            "answer": "การแข่งขันเรือ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "9",
            "question": "มหาวิทยาลัยที่เก่าแก่ที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "มหาวิทยาลัยฮาร์วาร์ด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "203",
            "question": "ชื่อของสะพานแขวนที่มีชื่อเสียงในซานฟรานซิสโกคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "สะพานโกลเดนเกต"
        },
        {
            "idx": "79",
            "question": "ชื่อของกษัตริย์อังกฤษที่ครองราชย์ยาวนานที่สุดในปัจจุบันคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "พระราชินีเอลิซาเบธที่ 2"
        },
        {
            "idx": "98",
            "question": "ใครเป็นผู้หญิงคนแรกที่ลงสมัครรับเลือกตั้งเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ กับพรรคการเมืองใหญ่?",
            "answer": "ฮิลลารี คลินตัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "127",
            "question": "ชื่อของมหาวิทยาลัยไอวี่ลีกที่มีชื่อเสียงของอเมริกาในแมสซาชูเซตส์คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "มหาวิทยาลัยฮาร์วาร์ด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "141",
            "question": "ชื่อของผู้ผลิตรถยนต์หรูอังกฤษที่มีชื่อเสียงที่รู้จักจากกระจังหน้าอันเป็นเอกลักษณ์และมาสคอตสปิริตออฟเอ็กสตาซี่คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "โรลส์-รอยซ์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "225",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องความเกี่ยวข้องกับตำนานโรบินฮู้ด?",
            "answer": "น็อตติงแฮม"
        },
        {
            "idx": "38",
            "question": "สหรัฐอเมริกาประกาศเอกราชจากอังกฤษในปีใด?",
            "answer": "ค.ศ. 1776"
        },
        {
            "idx": "219",
            "question": "ชื่อของพิพิธภัณฑ์หุ่นขี้ผึ้งที่มีชื่อเสียงในลอนดอนคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "มาดามทุสโซด์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "247",
            "question": "ชื่อของรางวัลดนตรีอเมริกันที่มีชื่อเสียงที่จัดขึ้นประจำปีในลอสแองเจลิสคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "รางวัลแกรมมี่"
        },
        {
            "idx": "256",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่รู้จักในนาม 'เมืองแห่งยอดแหลมในฝัน'?",
            "answer": "ออกซ์ฟอร์ด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "198",
            "question": "ชื่อของกลุ่มตลกอังกฤษที่มีชื่อเสียงที่รู้จักจากการแสดงสเก็ตช์เหนือจริงคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "มอนตี้ไพธอน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "131",
            "question": "ชื่อของแม่น้ำที่ไหลผ่านลอนดอนคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "แม่น้ำเทมส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "29",
            "question": "ชื่อของเทศกาลดนตรีอังกฤษที่มีชื่อเสียงที่จัดขึ้นประจำปีในซอมเมอร์เซ็ตคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เทศกาลกลาสตันเบอรี่"
        },
        {
            "idx": "26",
            "question": "ใครเป็นนายกรัฐมนตรีอังกฤษในช่วงต้นศตวรรษที่ 21?",
            "answer": "โทนี่ แบลร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "85",
            "question": "ประเด็นหลักที่ศาลสูงสุดจัดการในคดีสำคัญ บราวน์ เทียบ คณะกรรมการการศึกษา คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "การแยกโรงเรียน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "195",
            "question": "เหรียญตราทหารสูงสุดที่รัฐบาลสหรัฐอเมริกามอบให้คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เหรียญเกียรติยศ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "200",
            "question": "ชื่อของหอนาฬิกาที่มีชื่อเสียงที่ตั้งอยู่ทางตอนเหนือของพระราชวังเวสต์มินสเตอร์ในลอนดอนคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "บิ๊กเบน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "65",
            "question": "มหาวิทยาลัยของรัฐที่เก่าแก่ที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "มหาวิทยาลัยนอร์ทแคโรไลนาที่แชเปลฮิลล์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "222",
            "question": "ใครเป็นกษัตริย์อังกฤษในช่วงการก่อตั้งบริษัทอินเดียตะวันออกของอังกฤษ?",
            "answer": "พระราชินีเอลิซาเบธที่ 1"
        },
        {
            "idx": "274",
            "question": "กษัตริย์อังกฤษพระองค์ใดที่ครองราชย์ในยุควิกตอเรียน?",
            "answer": "พระราชินีวิกตอเรีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "268",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ ในช่วงการก่อตั้งหน่วยงานคุ้มครองสิ่งแวดล้อม?",
            "answer": "ริชาร์ด นิกสัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "71",
            "question": "ชื่อของถนนอเมริกันที่มีชื่อเสียงที่วิ่งจากชิคาโกไปลอสแองเจลิสคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เส้นทาง 66"
        },
        {
            "idx": "143",
            "question": "เมืองที่มีประชากรมากที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "นิวยอร์กซิตี้"
        },
        {
            "idx": "17",
            "question": "นักเขียนอังกฤษคนใดที่เขียน '1984' และ 'ฟาร์มสัตว์'?",
            "answer": "จอร์จ ออร์เวลล์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "50",
            "question": "มหาวิทยาลัยใดของสหราชอาณาจักรที่เก่าแก่ที่สุดในโลกที่พูดภาษาอังกฤษ?",
            "answer": "มหาวิทยาลัยออกซ์ฟอร์ด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "237",
            "question": "ชื่อของเทศกาลศิลปะที่มีชื่อเสียงที่จัดขึ้นประจำปีในเอดินบะระคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เทศกาลฟรินจ์เอดินบะระ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "193",
            "question": "เอกสารใดที่ลงนามในปี ค.ศ. 1215 ซึ่งรู้จักกันว่าเป็นรัฐธรรมนูญที่เขียนขึ้นเป็นลายลักษณ์อักษรฉบับแรกในประวัติศาสตร์ยุโรป?",
            "answer": "แมกนาคาร์ตา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "40",
            "question": "แม่น้ำที่ยาวที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "แม่น้ำมิสซูรี"
        },
        {
            "idx": "122",
            "question": "ชื่อของตัวละครสายลับอังกฤษที่สร้างโดยเอียน เฟลมมิ่งคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เจมส์ บอนด์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "216",
            "question": "เคาน์ตี้ใดของสหราชอาณาจักรที่รู้จักในนาม 'ประเทศของพระเจ้าเอง'?",
            "answer": "ยอร์กเชียร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "234",
            "question": "ใครเป็นวีรบุรุษพื้นบ้านอเมริกันในตำนานที่มีชื่อเสียงในการปลูกต้นแอปเปิ้ล?",
            "answer": "จอห์นนี่ แอปเปิ้ลซีด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "64",
            "question": "ใครเป็นนายกรัฐมนตรีอังกฤษในช่วงส่วนใหญ่ของสงครามโลกครั้งที่ 2?",
            "answer": "วินสตัน เชอร์ชิลล์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "266",
            "question": "เทศกาลอเมริกันใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในการแสดงภาพยนตร์อิสระ?",
            "answer": "เทศกาลภาพยนตร์ซันแดนซ์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "272",
            "question": "อาหารแบบดั้งเดิมของภาคใต้สหรัฐฯ ในวันปีใหม่เพื่อความโชคดีคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ถั่วตาดำ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "167",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ เพียงรัฐเดียวที่มีพระราชวัง?",
            "answer": "ฮาวาย (พระราชวังอิโอลานี)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "231",
            "question": "แกรนด์แคนยอนตั้งอยู่ในรัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ?",
            "answer": "อาริโซนา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "2",
            "question": "อาหารแบบดั้งเดิมของอังกฤษที่ทำจากเนื้อบดและมันฝรั่งบดคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "พายเชพเพิร์ด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "262",
            "question": "การแก้ไขรัฐธรรมนูญข้อใดที่ยกเลิกการห้ามเหล้าในสหรัฐอเมริกา?",
            "answer": "การแก้ไขข้อที่ 21"
        },
        {
            "idx": "99",
            "question": "ทะเลสาบน้ำจืดที่ใหญ่ที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ทะเลสาบซูพีเรียร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "276",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนใดที่รู้จักในนาม 'นักสื่อสารผู้ยิ่งใหญ่'?",
            "answer": "โรนัลด์ เรแกน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "204",
            "question": "กษัตริย์อังกฤษพระองค์ใดที่ก่อตั้งศาสนจักรแห่งอังกฤษ?",
            "answer": "พระเจ้าเฮนรี่ที่ 8"
        },
        {
            "idx": "181",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่รู้จักในนาม 'รัฐแรก'?",
            "answer": "เดลาแวร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "72",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ ในช่วงการลงนามข้อตกลงนาฟตา?",
            "answer": "บิล คลินตัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "119",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ ในช่วงวิกฤตตัวประกันอิหร่าน?",
            "answer": "จิมมี่ คาร์เตอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "106",
            "question": "ชื่อของระบบแม่น้ำที่ใหญ่ที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ระบบแม่น้ำมิสซิสซิปปี"
        },
        {
            "idx": "101",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหราชอาณาจักรที่เป็นบ้านเกิดของวงเดอะบีทเทิลส์?",
            "answer": "ลิเวอร์พูล"
        },
        {
            "idx": "49",
            "question": "ชื่อของสุสานทหารสหรัฐฯ ในเวอร์จิเนียคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "สุสานแห่งชาติอาร์ลิงตัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "169",
            "question": "ชื่อของพิธีอังกฤษที่เป็นเครื่องหมายวันเกิดอย่างเป็นทางการของกษัตริย์อังกฤษคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ทรูปปิ้งเดอะคัลเลอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "89",
            "question": "การรบในปี ค.ศ. 1066 ใดที่นำไปสู่การพิชิตนอร์มันของอังกฤษ?",
            "answer": "ยุทธการเฮสติงส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "118",
            "question": "นักเขียนอังกฤษคนใดที่เขียนซีรีส์ 'แฮร์รี่ พอตเตอร์'?",
            "answer": "เจ.เค. โรว์ลิ่ง"
        },
        {
            "idx": "63",
            "question": "ศาลสูงสุดสหรัฐฯ ตัดสินใจสำคัญอะไรในคดี บราวน์ เทียบ คณะกรรมการการศึกษา?",
            "answer": "ประกาศว่ากฎหมายของรัฐที่จัดตั้งโรงเรียนรัฐแยกสำหรับนักเรียนผิวดำและผิวขาวนั้นขัดต่อรัฐธรรมนูญ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "95",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในบทบาทสำคัญในสงครามกลางเมืองอังกฤษ?",
            "answer": "ยอร์ก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "249",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในบทบาทของเขาในวิกฤตขีปนาวุธคิวบา?",
            "answer": "จอห์น เอฟ. เคนเนดี"
        },
        {
            "idx": "253",
            "question": "ชื่อของศาลอุทธรณ์สูงสุดในสหราชอาณาจักรสำหรับคดีแพ่ง และสำหรับคดีอาญาจากอังกฤษ เวลส์ และไอร์แลนด์เหนือคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ศาลสูงสุดแห่งสหราชอาณาจักร"
        },
        {
            "idx": "212",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่รู้จักในนาม 'เมืองแห่งยอดแหลมในฝัน'?",
            "answer": "ออกซ์ฟอร์ด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "145",
            "question": "สถานที่สำคัญที่มีชื่อเสียงใดที่เป็นของขวัญจากฝรั่งเศสให้แก่สหรัฐอเมริกา?",
            "answer": "เทพีเสรีภาพ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "176",
            "question": "ชื่อของแคนยอนที่มีชื่อเสียงของอเมริกาในอาริโซนาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "แกรนด์แคนยอน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "287",
            "question": "ขนมหวานอังกฤษใดที่เสิร์ฟแบบดั้งเดิมกับคัสตาร์ด?",
            "answer": "สปอตเต็ดดิก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "52",
            "question": "สะพานลอนดอนใดที่นักท่องเที่ยวมักเรียกผิดว่าลอนดอนบริดจ์?",
            "answer": "ทาวเวอร์บริดจ์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "261",
            "question": "ชื่อของฐานทัพเรือสหรัฐฯ ที่ถูกโจมตีในปี ค.ศ. 1941 ซึ่งนำไปสู่การเข้าร่วมสงครามโลกครั้งที่ 2 ของอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เพิร์ลฮาร์เบอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "194",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนแรกที่แต่งตั้งผู้หญิงเข้าศาลสูงสุด?",
            "answer": "โรนัลด์ เรแกน (แซนดรา เดย์ โอคอนเนอร์)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "160",
            "question": "การรบสำคัญของการปฏิวัติอเมริกันที่ต่อสู้ในปี ค.ศ. 1775 คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ยุทธการบังเกอร์ฮิลล์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "47",
            "question": "ชื่อของเพลงชาติสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เดอะสตาร์-สแปงเกิลด์แบนเนอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "230",
            "question": "ชื่อของทะเลทรายที่ใหญ่ที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ทะเลทรายโมฮาเว"
        },
        {
            "idx": "201",
            "question": "ใครเป็นพระราชินีอังกฤษในช่วงการก่อตั้งอาณานิคมอังกฤษในอเมริกา?",
            "answer": "พระราชินีเอลิซาเบธที่ 1"
        },
        {
            "idx": "114",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เป็นรัฐแรกที่ทำให้การแต่งงานเพศเดียวกันถูกกฎหมาย?",
            "answer": "แมสซาชูเซตส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "70",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เป็นรัฐแรกที่ให้สัตยาบันรัฐธรรมนูญ?",
            "answer": "เดลาแวร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "187",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีคนใดที่ได้รับเครดิตในการประกาศปลดปล่อยทาส?",
            "answer": "อับราฮัม ลินคอล์น"
        },
        {
            "idx": "251",
            "question": "อาหารแบบดั้งเดิมของอังกฤษที่ทำจากเลือดหมู ข้าวโอ๊ต และเครื่องเทศคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "แบล็กพุดดิ้ง"
        },
        {
            "idx": "111",
            "question": "กษัตริย์อังกฤษพระองค์ใดที่พ่ายแพ้ในยุทธการเฮสติงส์?",
            "answer": "พระเจ้าแฮโรลด์ที่ 2"
        },
        {
            "idx": "282",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนแรกที่อาศัยในทำเนียบขาว?",
            "answer": "จอห์น อดัมส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "18",
            "question": "ชื่อของสนธิสัญญาที่ยุติสงครามปฏิวัติอเมริกันคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "สนธิสัญญาปารีส ค.ศ. 1783"
        },
        {
            "idx": "53",
            "question": "อนุสาวรีย์สหรัฐฯ ใดที่เป็นเกียรติแก่ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ สี่คนที่แกะสลักในภูเขา?",
            "answer": "เมาท์รัชมอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "109",
            "question": "รัฐที่ใหญ่ที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาตามพื้นที่คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "อลาสกา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "174",
            "question": "ชื่อของพายอังกฤษแบบดั้งเดิมที่ไส้ด้วยเนื้อบดและมันฝรั่งบดคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "คอตเทจพาย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "128",
            "question": "สหรัฐอเมริกาเข้าร่วมเหตุการณ์สำคัญระดับโลกใดในปี ค.ศ. 1941?",
            "answer": "สงครามโลกครั้งที่ 2"
        },
        {
            "idx": "150",
            "question": "ชื่อของอาณานิคมอเมริกันแห่งแรกที่ประกาศเอกราชจากอังกฤษคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "โรดไอแลนด์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "161",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่รู้จักในฐานะบ้านเกิดของการบิน?",
            "answer": "โอไฮโอ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "178",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องรถเคเบิลทางประวัติศาสตร์?",
            "answer": "ซานฟรานซิสโก, แคลิฟอร์เนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "208",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องประชากรอามิชจำนวนมาก?",
            "answer": "เพนซิลเวเนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "68",
            "question": "ชื่อของอุทยานแห่งชาติอเมริกันที่มีชื่อเสียงที่มีน้ำพุร้อนในไวโอมิงคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "อุทยานแห่งชาติเยลโลว์สโตน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "138",
            "question": "อาคารที่สูงที่สุดในสหรัฐอเมริกาคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "วันเวิลด์เทรดเซ็นเตอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "55",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องพิซซ่าจานลึก?",
            "answer": "ชิคาโก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "87",
            "question": "ชื่อของที่พำนักของนายกรัฐมนตรีอังกฤษคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "10 ดาวนิ่งสตรีท"
        },
        {
            "idx": "248",
            "question": "เมืองอเมริกันใดที่รู้จักในฐานะบ้านเกิดของกองทัพเรือสหรัฐอเมริกา?",
            "answer": "ฟิลาเดลเฟีย, เพนซิลเวเนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "288",
            "question": "แม่น้ำที่ยาวที่สุดในสหราชอาณาจักรคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "แม่น้ำเซเวิร์น"
        },
        {
            "idx": "12",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในบทบาทสำคัญในอุตสาหกรรมยานยนต์อเมริกัน?",
            "answer": "ดีทรอยต์, มิชิแกน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "31",
            "question": "สถานที่สำคัญใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่รู้จักในนาม 'ป้อมปราการของอเมริกา'?",
            "answer": "ฟอร์ตน็อกซ์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "154",
            "question": "ชีสอังกฤษใดที่ใช้แบบดั้งเดิมในอาหารกลางวันของชาวนา?",
            "answer": "เชดดาร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "213",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่ถูกระเบิดอย่างมีชื่อเสียงในช่วงบลิตซ์ในสงครามโลกครั้งที่ 2?",
            "answer": "ลอนดอน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "134",
            "question": "ชื่อของประเพณีอังกฤษในการดื่มชาในช่วงบ่ายสาย ซึ่งมักจะมาพร้อมกับแซนด์วิชหรือขนมหวานคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "อาฟเตอร์นูนที"
        },
        {
            "idx": "189",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนใดที่เกี่ยวข้องกับวลี 'สิ่งเดียวที่เราต้องกลัวคือความกลัวนั่นเอง'?",
            "answer": "แฟรงคลิน ดี. รูสเวลต์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "129",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในการผลิตนมและมักเรียกว่า 'ดินแดนโคนมของอเมริกา'?",
            "answer": "วิสคอนซิน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "35",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ ในช่วงการซื้อหลุยเซียนา?",
            "answer": "โทมัส เจฟเฟอร์สัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "86",
            "question": "กษัตริย์อังกฤษพระองค์ใดที่เกี่ยวข้องกับยุคทองของประวัติศาสตร์อังกฤษ?",
            "answer": "พระราชินีเอลิซาเบธที่ 1"
        },
        {
            "idx": "105",
            "question": "ชื่อของนายทหารเรืออังกฤษที่มีชื่อเสียงในชัยชนะต่อนโปเลียนในช่วงสงครามนโปเลียนคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "พลเรือเอกลอร์ดเนลสัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "84",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนแรกที่ถูกฟ้องร้อง?",
            "answer": "แอนดรูว์ จอห์นสัน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "88",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่รู้จักในนาม 'รัฐแสงแดด'?",
            "answer": "ฟลอริดา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "91",
            "question": "วงดนตรีอังกฤษใดที่นำการบุกรุกของอังกฤษในชาร์ตเพลงสหรัฐฯ ในทศวรรษ 1960?",
            "answer": "เดอะบีทเทิลส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "218",
            "question": "ใครเป็นผู้นำสิทธิพลเมืองอเมริกันที่ถูกลอบสังหารในปี ค.ศ. 1968?",
            "answer": "มาร์ติน ลูเธอร์ คิง จูเนียร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "281",
            "question": "เมืองหลวงของเท็กซัสคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ออสติน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "283",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เป็นเมืองแรกที่ใช้ระบบรถไฟใต้ดิน?",
            "answer": "บอสตัน, แมสซาชูเซตส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "56",
            "question": "ชื่อเล่นของนิวยอร์กซิตี้คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "บิ๊กแอปเปิ้ล"
        },
        {
            "idx": "74",
            "question": "ชื่อของเส้นทางที่มีชื่อเสียงที่รู้จักในนาม 'ถนนแม่'คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เส้นทาง 66"
        },
        {
            "idx": "199",
            "question": "การตั้งถิ่นฐานถาวรของอังกฤษแห่งแรกในอเมริกาเหนือคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "เจมส์ทาวน์, เวอร์จิเนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "172",
            "question": "ใครเป็นกษัตริย์อังกฤษในช่วงสงครามฟอล์กแลนด์?",
            "answer": "พระราชินีเอลิซาเบธที่ 2"
        },
        {
            "idx": "260",
            "question": "สาเหตุหลักของสงครามกลางเมืองอเมริกันคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "การเป็นทาสและสิทธิของรัฐ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "136",
            "question": "สถานที่สำคัญใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่จารึกด้วยคำว่า 'ให้ฉันได้คนเหนื่อยล้าของเจ้า คนยากจนของเจ้า ฝูงชนที่แออัดที่ปรารถนาจะหายใจอย่างเสรี'?",
            "answer": "เทพีเสรีภาพ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "155",
            "question": "ชื่อของผู้นำสิทธิพลเมืองอเมริกันที่มีชื่อเสียงที่กล่าวสุนทรพจน์ 'ฉันมีความฝัน' คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "มาร์ติน ลูเธอร์ คิง จูเนียร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "120",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่มีชื่อเสียงทางประวัติศาสตร์ในอุตสาหกรรมต่อเรือ?",
            "answer": "กลาสโกว์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "217",
            "question": "เอกสารใดที่ยุติการเป็นทาสในสหรัฐอเมริกาอย่างเป็นทางการ?",
            "answer": "การแก้ไขรัฐธรรมนูญข้อที่ 13"
        },
        {
            "idx": "6",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องมหาวิทยาลัยทางประวัติศาสตร์และเป็นที่ตั้งของแรดคลิฟฟ์คาเมรา?",
            "answer": "ออกซ์ฟอร์ด"
        },
        {
            "idx": "10",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องมันฝรั่ง?",
            "answer": "ไอดาโฮ"
        },
        {
            "idx": "22",
            "question": "ใครที่รู้จักในนาม 'บิดาแห่งอุทยานแห่งชาติ' ในอเมริกา?",
            "answer": "จอห์น มูเออร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "258",
            "question": "เหรียญอังกฤษใดที่มีภาพดอกผักบุ้ง หอยแครง และแชมร็อค?",
            "answer": "เหรียญหนึ่งปอนด์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "126",
            "question": "ใครเป็นชาวแอฟริกัน-อเมริกันคนแรกที่ดำรงตำแหน่งรัฐมนตรีต่างประเทศสหรัฐฯ?",
            "answer": "โคลิน พาวเวลล์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "270",
            "question": "ชื่อของตลาดหุ้นอเมริกันที่มีชื่อเสียงในนิวยอร์กคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "ตลาดหุ้นนิวยอร์ก (NYSE)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "77",
            "question": "รัฐที่เล็กที่สุดของสหรัฐฯ ตามพื้นที่คืออะไร?",
            "answer": "โรดไอแลนด์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "112",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหราชอาณาจักรที่มีชื่อเสียงในการผลิตเหล็ก?",
            "answer": "เชฟฟิลด์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "156",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในประวัติศาสตร์และวัฒนธรรมชาวอเมริกันพื้นเมืองที่สำคัญ?",
            "answer": "นิวเม็กซิโก"
        },
        {
            "idx": "66",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่รู้จักในนาม เมืองลมแรง?",
            "answer": "ชิคาโก, อิลลินอยส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "67",
            "question": "เมืองอังกฤษใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในบทบาทสำคัญในการปฏิวัติอุตสาหกรรม?",
            "answer": "แมนเชสเตอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "254",
            "question": "ชื่อของยานอวกาศที่นำมนุษย์ลงจอดบนดวงจันทร์เป็นครั้งแรกคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "อพอลโล 11"
        },
        {
            "idx": "121",
            "question": "ทะเลสาบที่ใหญ่ที่สุดในอังกฤษคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "วินเดอร์เมียร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "246",
            "question": "ใครเป็นประธานาธิบดีคนที่สองของสหรัฐอเมริกา?",
            "answer": "จอห์น อดัมส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "94",
            "question": "กษัตริย์อังกฤษพระองค์ใดที่ครองราชย์ยาวนานที่สุดก่อนพระราชินีเอลิซาเบธที่ 2?",
            "answer": "พระราชินีวิกตอเรีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "265",
            "question": "ประธานาธิบดีสหรัฐฯ คนใดที่เริ่มโครงการที่นำไปสู่การสร้างอินเทอร์เน็ต?",
            "answer": "ดไวท์ ดี. ไอเซนฮาวเวอร์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "152",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในเรื่องเกาะภูเขาไฟ?",
            "answer": "ฮาวาย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "76",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เป็นเมืองหลวงแห่งแรกของสหรัฐอเมริกา?",
            "answer": "ฟิลาเดลเฟีย, เพนซิลเวเนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "157",
            "question": "ใครเป็นนักบินอวกาศหญิงอังกฤษคนแรก?",
            "answer": "เฮเลน ชาร์แมน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "163",
            "question": "กษัตริย์อังกฤษพระองค์ใดที่สืบทอดพระราชินีวิกตอเรีย?",
            "answer": "พระเจ้าเอ็ดเวิร์ดที่ 7"
        },
        {
            "idx": "24",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่รู้จักในฐานะบ้านเกิดของดนตรีแจ๊ส?",
            "answer": "นิวออร์ลีนส์"
        },
        {
            "idx": "57",
            "question": "รัฐใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่มีชื่อเสียงในการผลิตข้าวโพดมากที่สุด?",
            "answer": "ไอโอวา"
        },
        {
            "idx": "28",
            "question": "นักวิทยาศาสตร์อังกฤษคนใดที่พัฒนาทฤษฎีวิวัฒนาการ?",
            "answer": "ชาร์ลส์ ดาร์วิน"
        },
        {
            "idx": "92",
            "question": "ที่พำนักหลวงอย่างเป็นทางการของพระราชินีในลอนดอนคืออะไร?",
            "answer": "พระราชวังบักกิงแฮม"
        },
        {
            "idx": "177",
            "question": "เมืองใดของสหรัฐฯ ที่เป็นเจ้าภาพโอลิมปิกฤดูร้อน 1984?",
            "answer": "ลอสแองเจลิส, แคลิฟอร์เนีย"
        },
        {
            "idx": "4",
            "question": "นักฟิสิกส์อังกฤษคนใดที่มีชื่อเสียงในงานเกี่ยวกับหลุมดำ?",
            "answer": "สตีเฟน ฮอว์กิง"
        }
    ],
    "fr": [
        {
            "idx": "139",
            "question": "Quel parc national américain est célèbre pour avoir un supervolcan ?",
            "answer": "Parc national de Yellowstone"
        },
        {
            "idx": "5",
            "question": "Quelle est la boisson traditionnelle du Sud des États-Unis à base de bourbon ?",
            "answer": "Mint julep"
        },
        {
            "idx": "34",
            "question": "Quel événement majeur de 1666 a dévasté de grandes parties de Londres ?",
            "answer": "Le Grand Incendie de Londres"
        },
        {
            "idx": "182",
            "question": "Quel est le plat écossais traditionnel fait à partir d'estomac de mouton ?",
            "answer": "Haggis"
        },
        {
            "idx": "33",
            "question": "Quel est le thème principal du roman 'Ne tirez pas sur l'oiseau moqueur' de Harper Lee ?",
            "answer": "L'injustice raciale et la croissance morale"
        },
        {
            "idx": "252",
            "question": "Quel président américain est associé au New Deal ?",
            "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "179",
            "question": "Quel amendement américain prévoit le droit de porter des armes ?",
            "answer": "Le 2e amendement"
        },
        {
            "idx": "186",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est célèbre pour sa célébration du Mardi Gras ?",
            "answer": "La Nouvelle-Orléans, Louisiane"
        },
        {
            "idx": "168",
            "question": "Quel est le dessert américain traditionnel servi à Thanksgiving ?",
            "answer": "Tarte à la citrouille"
        },
        {
            "idx": "271",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est connue pour l'invention de la locomotive à vapeur ?",
            "answer": "Newcastle"
        },
        {
            "idx": "180",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est connue pour ses thermes construits par les Romains ?",
            "answer": "Bath"
        },
        {
            "idx": "45",
            "question": "Dans quel État américain se trouve le mont Rushmore ?",
            "answer": "Dakota du Sud"
        },
        {
            "idx": "285",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre discours prononcé par Abraham Lincoln pendant la guerre civile américaine ?",
            "answer": "Le Discours de Gettysburg"
        },
        {
            "idx": "221",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre navire britannique qui a transporté les Pèlerins en Amérique en 1620 ?",
            "answer": "Le Mayflower"
        },
        {
            "idx": "209",
            "question": "Quel est le plat britannique traditionnel fait de poisson et de pâte frite ?",
            "answer": "Fish and Chips"
        },
        {
            "idx": "166",
            "question": "Quelle est la plus haute montagne des États-Unis continentaux ?",
            "answer": "Mont Whitney, Californie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "214",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est connue pour avoir créé le Titanic ?",
            "answer": "Belfast"
        },
        {
            "idx": "48",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu sous le nom d'« État du pin » ?",
            "answer": "Maine"
        },
        {
            "idx": "59",
            "question": "Quel scientifique britannique est connu pour sa loi de la gravitation ?",
            "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton"
        },
        {
            "idx": "54",
            "question": "Quel est le terme utilisé pour décrire la politique du gouvernement américain favorisant la réunification familiale pour les immigrants ?",
            "answer": "Migration en chaîne"
        },
        {
            "idx": "103",
            "question": "Quel est le surnom de Seattle en raison de sa culture du café ?",
            "answer": "Capitale du café"
        },
        {
            "idx": "190",
            "question": "Qui était le président américain lors du premier alunissage en 1969 ?",
            "answer": "Richard Nixon"
        },
        {
            "idx": "278",
            "question": "Qui était l'auteur principal de la Constitution américaine ?",
            "answer": "James Madison"
        },
        {
            "idx": "240",
            "question": "Quel État américain a le plus de votes électoraux ?",
            "answer": "Californie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "61",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu sous le nom de « Terre d'enchantement » ?",
            "answer": "Nouveau-Mexique"
        },
        {
            "idx": "62",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la célèbre bataille britannique au cours de laquelle l'amiral Lord Nelson est mort ?",
            "answer": "La bataille de Trafalgar"
        },
        {
            "idx": "102",
            "question": "Quel marché londonien est célèbre pour ses antiquités et objets vintage ?",
            "answer": "Marché de Portobello Road"
        },
        {
            "idx": "175",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la région connue pour être le berceau de la Silicon Valley ?",
            "answer": "Vallée de Santa Clara"
        },
        {
            "idx": "1",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la doctrine américaine qui s'opposait au colonialisme européen dans les Amériques ?",
            "answer": "La Doctrine Monroe"
        },
        {
            "idx": "269",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine a été le site de la « Marche sur Washington pour l'emploi et la liberté » de 1963 ?",
            "answer": "Washington D.C."
        },
        {
            "idx": "151",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine a été la première capitale sous la Constitution américaine ?",
            "answer": "New York"
        },
        {
            "idx": "93",
            "question": "Quel État américain était le centre de la ruée vers l'or en 1849 ?",
            "answer": "Californie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "23",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu pour sa population et son histoire amérindiennes importantes ?",
            "answer": "Oklahoma"
        },
        {
            "idx": "116",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est connue pour l'invention de la machine à vapeur ?",
            "answer": "Birmingham"
        },
        {
            "idx": "245",
            "question": "Qui était l'inventeur américain connu pour avoir développé l'ampoule électrique ?",
            "answer": "Thomas Edison"
        },
        {
            "idx": "196",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du responsable de l'application de la loi britannique connu sous le nom de « Bobby » ?",
            "answer": "Agent de police"
        },
        {
            "idx": "80",
            "question": "Qui était le premier astronaute américain à orbiter autour de la Terre ?",
            "answer": "John Glenn"
        },
        {
            "idx": "97",
            "question": "Quel scientifique britannique est crédité de l'invention du World Wide Web ?",
            "answer": "Sir Tim Berners-Lee"
        },
        {
            "idx": "148",
            "question": "Quel parc londonien contient Speakers' Corner ?",
            "answer": "Hyde Park"
        },
        {
            "idx": "158",
            "question": "Qui était le monarque britannique pendant la guerre de Crimée ?",
            "answer": "Reine Victoria"
        },
        {
            "idx": "210",
            "question": "Qui était l'auteur américain connu pour ses œuvres sur l'Âge du jazz ?",
            "answer": "F. Scott Fitzgerald"
        },
        {
            "idx": "146",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre festival de musique organisé chaque année au Tennessee ?",
            "answer": "Bonnaroo"
        },
        {
            "idx": "164",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la plus haute cour du Royaume-Uni ?",
            "answer": "La Cour suprême du Royaume-Uni"
        },
        {
            "idx": "104",
            "question": "Quelle rue londonienne est célèbre pour ses cabinets médicaux ?",
            "answer": "Harley Street"
        },
        {
            "idx": "15",
            "question": "Quelle ville du Royaume-Uni est célèbre pour ses thermes romains ?",
            "answer": "Bath"
        },
        {
            "idx": "11",
            "question": "Quel président américain a introduit la politique connue sous le nom de « Diplomatie du gros bâton » ?",
            "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "14",
            "question": "Qui était la première femme Premier ministre du Royaume-Uni ?",
            "answer": "Margaret Thatcher"
        },
        {
            "idx": "39",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu sous le nom de « Terre des 10 000 lacs » ?",
            "answer": "Minnesota"
        },
        {
            "idx": "41",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu pour sa population quaker importante ?",
            "answer": "Pennsylvanie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "44",
            "question": "Quel explorateur britannique est connu pour sa circumnavigation du globe au XVIe siècle ?",
            "answer": "Sir Francis Drake"
        },
        {
            "idx": "124",
            "question": "Quel État américain a le surnom de « La dernière frontière » ?",
            "answer": "Alaska"
        },
        {
            "idx": "149",
            "question": "Quel traité a reconnu l'indépendance des colonies américaines de la Grande-Bretagne ?",
            "answer": "Le Traité de Paris, 1783"
        },
        {
            "idx": "188",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est connue pour son industrie technologique importante, souvent appelée « Silicon Valley » ?",
            "answer": "San José, Californie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "228",
            "question": "Quel est le surnom de Detroit en raison de son industrie automobile ?",
            "answer": "Motor City"
        },
        {
            "idx": "284",
            "question": "Quel monarque britannique a succédé à la reine Élisabeth Ire et était le premier de la lignée Stuart ?",
            "answer": "Roi Jacques Ier"
        },
        {
            "idx": "100",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre monument américain également connu sous le nom de « La Liberté éclairant le monde » ?",
            "answer": "La Statue de la Liberté"
        },
        {
            "idx": "279",
            "question": "Quelle personnalité politique britannique est connue sous le nom de « Dame de fer » ?",
            "answer": "Margaret Thatcher"
        },
        {
            "idx": "25",
            "question": "Quelle fête américaine est célébrée le quatrième jeudi de novembre ?",
            "answer": "Thanksgiving"
        },
        {
            "idx": "184",
            "question": "Quel lac écossais est célèbre pour son monstre mythique ?",
            "answer": "Loch Ness"
        },
        {
            "idx": "242",
            "question": "Quelles sont les deux chambres qui composent le Parlement britannique ?",
            "answer": "La Chambre des communes et la Chambre des lords"
        },
        {
            "idx": "170",
            "question": "Quel amendement à la Constitution américaine a accordé aux femmes le droit de vote ?",
            "answer": "19e amendement"
        },
        {
            "idx": "275",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la célèbre marque britannique de voitures de sport connue pour ses véhicules de luxe ?",
            "answer": "Aston Martin"
        },
        {
            "idx": "277",
            "question": "Quel événement politique britannique majeur s'est produit en 2016 ?",
            "answer": "Référendum sur le Brexit"
        },
        {
            "idx": "3",
            "question": "Quel est le surnom de Philadelphie ?",
            "answer": "La Ville de l'amour fraternel"
        },
        {
            "idx": "21",
            "question": "Quel est le pain américain traditionnel servi dans le Sud ?",
            "answer": "Pain de maïs"
        },
        {
            "idx": "263",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du traité qui a mis fin à la guerre américano-mexicaine ?",
            "answer": "Le Traité de Guadalupe Hidalgo"
        },
        {
            "idx": "30",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre monument américain sculpté dans le mont Rushmore ?",
            "answer": "Mémorial national du mont Rushmore"
        },
        {
            "idx": "173",
            "question": "Qui est le saint patron de l'Angleterre et quel jour est célébré en son honneur ?",
            "answer": "Saint Georges ; la Saint-Georges est célébrée le 23 avril"
        },
        {
            "idx": "107",
            "question": "Quel est le dessert anglais traditionnel impliquant des fruits et un gâteau éponge imbibé de xérès ?",
            "answer": "Trifle"
        },
        {
            "idx": "192",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est connue pour ses deux célèbres clubs de football, Manchester United et Manchester City ?",
            "answer": "Manchester"
        },
        {
            "idx": "233",
            "question": "Quelle était la principale activité économique dans les colonies du Sud pendant l'époque coloniale ?",
            "answer": "Agriculture (particulièrement le tabac et le coton)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "78",
            "question": "Quelle est la plus haute montagne des îles britanniques ?",
            "answer": "Ben Nevis"
        },
        {
            "idx": "243",
            "question": "Qui était le monarque britannique pendant la Première Guerre mondiale ?",
            "answer": "Roi George V"
        },
        {
            "idx": "273",
            "question": "Quel État américain a été le dernier à rejoindre l'Union ?",
            "answer": "Hawaï"
        },
        {
            "idx": "82",
            "question": "Qui était la première femme juge à la Cour suprême des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Sandra Day O'Connor"
        },
        {
            "idx": "37",
            "question": "Qui était le juge de la Cour suprême américaine ayant servi le plus longtemps ?",
            "answer": "William O. Douglas"
        },
        {
            "idx": "144",
            "question": "Quel est le surnom de Las Vegas ?",
            "answer": "Sin City"
        },
        {
            "idx": "207",
            "question": "Qui était la première femme afro-américaine élue au Congrès américain ?",
            "answer": "Shirley Chisholm"
        },
        {
            "idx": "191",
            "question": "Quel roi britannique a abdiqué le trône en 1936 pour épouser une divorcée américaine ?",
            "answer": "Roi Édouard VIII"
        },
        {
            "idx": "229",
            "question": "Quelle guerre a été menée par les régions Nord et Sud des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "La Guerre civile"
        },
        {
            "idx": "32",
            "question": "Quelle est la plus grande zone protégée des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Parc national et réserve Wrangell-St. Elias, Alaska"
        },
        {
            "idx": "250",
            "question": "Quel est le sujet principal du célèbre discours « J'ai un rêve » de Martin Luther King Jr. ?",
            "answer": "Les droits civiques et l'égalité raciale"
        },
        {
            "idx": "132",
            "question": "Quel État américain a été acheté à la Russie en 1867 ?",
            "answer": "Alaska"
        },
        {
            "idx": "244",
            "question": "Quel événement majeur américain a eu lieu le 20 juillet 1969 ?",
            "answer": "L'alunissage d'Apollo 11"
        },
        {
            "idx": "259",
            "question": "Dans quelle ville le premier vol d'avion réussi par les frères Wright a-t-il été effectué ?",
            "answer": "Kitty Hawk, Caroline du Nord"
        },
        {
            "idx": "232",
            "question": "Quel État américain a le plus de parcs nationaux ?",
            "answer": "Californie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "117",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la célèbre académie militaire américaine établie en 1802 ?",
            "answer": "West Point (Académie militaire des États-Unis)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "46",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du processus par lequel les territoires britanniques ont obtenu leur indépendance ?",
            "answer": "Décolonisation"
        },
        {
            "idx": "69",
            "question": "Quel explorateur britannique est connu pour ses voyages dans l'océan Pacifique ?",
            "answer": "Capitaine James Cook"
        },
        {
            "idx": "75",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la rivière qui traverse Liverpool ?",
            "answer": "La rivière Mersey"
        },
        {
            "idx": "81",
            "question": "Quel président américain a signé le Civil Rights Act de 1964 ?",
            "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "60",
            "question": "Quelle est la plus grande île des États-Unis continentaux ?",
            "answer": "Long Island, New York"
        },
        {
            "idx": "147",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de l'accord historique signé entre le gouvernement britannique et les nationalistes irlandais en 1998 ?",
            "answer": "L'Accord du Vendredi saint"
        },
        {
            "idx": "159",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu pour sa production de bourbon ?",
            "answer": "Kentucky"
        },
        {
            "idx": "205",
            "question": "Qui est connu pour avoir passé le premier appel téléphonique ?",
            "answer": "Alexander Graham Bell"
        },
        {
            "idx": "235",
            "question": "Qui a écrit la Déclaration d'indépendance ?",
            "answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "130",
            "question": "Quel traité a mis fin à la guerre d'indépendance américaine ?",
            "answer": "Le Traité de Paris, 1783"
        },
        {
            "idx": "153",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de l'affaire de la Cour suprême américaine qui a légalisé l'avortement en 1973 ?",
            "answer": "Roe v. Wade"
        },
        {
            "idx": "215",
            "question": "Quel acte du Parlement a établi le protestantisme en Angleterre ?",
            "answer": "L'Acte de suprématie, 1534"
        },
        {
            "idx": "36",
            "question": "Quelle est la capitale des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Washington D.C."
        },
        {
            "idx": "171",
            "question": "Quelle cathédrale britannique a la plus haute flèche de Grande-Bretagne ?",
            "answer": "Cathédrale de Salisbury"
        },
        {
            "idx": "7",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la plus grande île des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Hawaï (Grande Île)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "226",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la mer qui sépare la Grande-Bretagne de l'Europe continentale ?",
            "answer": "La Manche"
        },
        {
            "idx": "220",
            "question": "Quelle législation historique a été adoptée en 1965 pour interdire la discrimination raciale dans le vote ?",
            "answer": "Le Voting Rights Act de 1965"
        },
        {
            "idx": "140",
            "question": "Qui était le président américain pendant la majeure partie de la Seconde Guerre mondiale ?",
            "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "224",
            "question": "Quel est le plus grand parc national d'Angleterre ?",
            "answer": "Le parc national du Lake District"
        },
        {
            "idx": "42",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre monument américain qui est un symbole de liberté et de démocratie ?",
            "answer": "La Cloche de la Liberté"
        },
        {
            "idx": "8",
            "question": "Quel président américain a signé le Civil Rights Act de 1964 ?",
            "answer": "Lyndon B. Johnson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "90",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la résidence royale britannique située dans le Berkshire ?",
            "answer": "Château de Windsor"
        },
        {
            "idx": "211",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la résidence officielle londonienne de la Reine ?",
            "answer": "Palais de Buckingham"
        },
        {
            "idx": "239",
            "question": "À quel événement majeur le krach de Wall Street de 1929 a-t-il mené ?",
            "answer": "La Grande Dépression"
        },
        {
            "idx": "51",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la série britannique de prix d'excellence pour le cinéma et la télévision ?",
            "answer": "Les prix BAFTA"
        },
        {
            "idx": "162",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est connue comme le berceau de la musique blues ?",
            "answer": "Memphis, Tennessee"
        },
        {
            "idx": "137",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la série télévisée britannique basée sur le règne de la reine Élisabeth II ?",
            "answer": "The Crown"
        },
        {
            "idx": "83",
            "question": "Qui était le monarque britannique lors de la signature de la Magna Carta ?",
            "answer": "Roi Jean"
        },
        {
            "idx": "58",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est connue pour son rôle central dans la Révolution américaine ?",
            "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts"
        },
        {
            "idx": "286",
            "question": "Quel est l'aéroport le plus fréquenté des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Aéroport international Hartsfield-Jackson d'Atlanta"
        },
        {
            "idx": "123",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la célèbre galerie d'art britannique située sur la Tamise ?",
            "answer": "Tate Modern"
        },
        {
            "idx": "202",
            "question": "Quel président américain a servi quatre mandats ?",
            "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "19",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est connue sous le nom de « Ville de l'amour fraternel » ?",
            "answer": "Philadelphie, Pennsylvanie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "206",
            "question": "Quelle fête américaine célèbre la fin de l'esclavage ?",
            "answer": "Juneteenth"
        },
        {
            "idx": "165",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est connue pour l'événement historique de la Boston Tea Party ?",
            "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts"
        },
        {
            "idx": "108",
            "question": "Quel président américain est connu pour le « Square Deal » ?",
            "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "16",
            "question": "Quel auteur britannique a écrit « Orgueil et Préjugés » ?",
            "answer": "Jane Austen"
        },
        {
            "idx": "185",
            "question": "Quel est le plus grand État américain par superficie ?",
            "answer": "Alaska"
        },
        {
            "idx": "43",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est connue pour ses chantiers navals historiques et comme lieu de naissance de Charles Dickens ?",
            "answer": "Portsmouth"
        },
        {
            "idx": "289",
            "question": "Quelle est la ligne de longitude qui passe par l'Observatoire royal de Greenwich ?",
            "answer": "Le méridien de Greenwich"
        },
        {
            "idx": "183",
            "question": "Quel parc national britannique contient la plus haute montagne d'Angleterre ?",
            "answer": "Lake District"
        },
        {
            "idx": "135",
            "question": "Quel arrondissement londonien abrite les championnats de tennis de Wimbledon ?",
            "answer": "Merton"
        },
        {
            "idx": "255",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la base navale américaine qui est le quartier général de la flotte du Pacifique américaine ?",
            "answer": "Pearl Harbor"
        },
        {
            "idx": "257",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du lac le plus profond des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Crater Lake"
        },
        {
            "idx": "267",
            "question": "Quel président américain a établi le Peace Corps ?",
            "answer": "John F. Kennedy"
        },
        {
            "idx": "264",
            "question": "Quel plat britannique consiste en des saucisses dans une pâte de Yorkshire pudding ?",
            "answer": "Toad in the Hole"
        },
        {
            "idx": "113",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du système ferroviaire souterrain de Londres ?",
            "answer": "Le métro de Londres ou The Tube"
        },
        {
            "idx": "280",
            "question": "Qui était le premier président américain à naître dans un hôpital ?",
            "answer": "Jimmy Carter"
        },
        {
            "idx": "13",
            "question": "Quel auteur britannique a créé le détective fictif Sherlock Holmes ?",
            "answer": "Sir Arthur Conan Doyle"
        },
        {
            "idx": "73",
            "question": "Quel est le spectacle de Broadway le plus long de l'histoire américaine ?",
            "answer": "Le Fantôme de l'Opéra"
        },
        {
            "idx": "96",
            "question": "Quelle est la plus ancienne université du Royaume-Uni ?",
            "answer": "L'Université d'Oxford"
        },
        {
            "idx": "238",
            "question": "Quel État américain était à l'origine connu sous le nom de « Province du New Jersey » ?",
            "answer": "New Jersey"
        },
        {
            "idx": "133",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique abrite le Musée national du chemin de fer ?",
            "answer": "York"
        },
        {
            "idx": "27",
            "question": "Qui était le président américain lors de l'achat de l'Alaska à la Russie ?",
            "answer": "Andrew Johnson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "115",
            "question": "Qui était le hors-la-loi légendaire associé à la forêt de Sherwood ?",
            "answer": "Robin des Bois"
        },
        {
            "idx": "290",
            "question": "Quelle est la fonction principale du Collège électoral américain ?",
            "answer": "Élire le président et le vice-président"
        },
        {
            "idx": "197",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est célèbre pour sa pizza deep-dish ?",
            "answer": "Chicago, Illinois"
        },
        {
            "idx": "236",
            "question": "Quel monarque britannique a établi l'Église d'Angleterre ?",
            "answer": "Henri VIII"
        },
        {
            "idx": "142",
            "question": "Quel État américain est le principal producteur de myrtilles du pays ?",
            "answer": "Maine"
        },
        {
            "idx": "227",
            "question": "Qui était le premier président américain à démissionner de ses fonctions ?",
            "answer": "Richard Nixon"
        },
        {
            "idx": "241",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la loi britannique qui a accordé l'autonomie gouvernementale au Canada, à l'Australie, à la Nouvelle-Zélande et à l'Afrique du Sud ?",
            "answer": "Statut de Westminster"
        },
        {
            "idx": "110",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre monument préhistorique situé dans le Wiltshire, en Angleterre ?",
            "answer": "Stonehenge"
        },
        {
            "idx": "20",
            "question": "Quel était le premier vaisseau spatial à atterrir sur Mars ?",
            "answer": "Viking 1"
        },
        {
            "idx": "223",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de l'architecte britannique qui a conçu la cathédrale Saint-Paul ?",
            "answer": "Sir Christopher Wren"
        },
        {
            "idx": "125",
            "question": "Quel événement sportif annuel a lieu entre les universités d'Oxford et de Cambridge ?",
            "answer": "La Course d'aviron"
        },
        {
            "idx": "9",
            "question": "Quelle est la plus ancienne université des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Université Harvard"
        },
        {
            "idx": "203",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre pont suspendu de San Francisco ?",
            "answer": "Pont du Golden Gate"
        },
        {
            "idx": "79",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du monarque britannique ayant régné le plus longtemps actuellement ?",
            "answer": "Reine Élisabeth II"
        },
        {
            "idx": "98",
            "question": "Qui était la première femme à se présenter à la présidence américaine avec un grand parti politique ?",
            "answer": "Hillary Clinton"
        },
        {
            "idx": "127",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la célèbre université américaine de l'Ivy League dans le Massachusetts ?",
            "answer": "Université Harvard"
        },
        {
            "idx": "141",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre constructeur automobile britannique de luxe connu pour sa calandre emblématique et sa mascotte Spirit of Ecstasy ?",
            "answer": "Rolls-Royce"
        },
        {
            "idx": "225",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est connue pour son association avec la légende de Robin des Bois ?",
            "answer": "Nottingham"
        },
        {
            "idx": "38",
            "question": "En quelle année les États-Unis ont-ils déclaré leur indépendance de la Grande-Bretagne ?",
            "answer": "1776"
        },
        {
            "idx": "219",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre musée de cire de Londres ?",
            "answer": "Madame Tussauds"
        },
        {
            "idx": "247",
            "question": "Quel est le nom des célèbres prix musicaux américains organisés chaque année à Los Angeles ?",
            "answer": "Grammy Awards"
        },
        {
            "idx": "256",
            "question": "Quelle ville anglaise est connue sous le nom de « Ville aux flèches de rêve » ?",
            "answer": "Oxford"
        },
        {
            "idx": "198",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre groupe de comédie britannique connu pour ses spectacles de sketches surréalistes ?",
            "answer": "Monty Python"
        },
        {
            "idx": "131",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la rivière qui traverse Londres ?",
            "answer": "La Tamise"
        },
        {
            "idx": "29",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre festival de musique britannique organisé chaque année dans le Somerset ?",
            "answer": "Festival de Glastonbury"
        },
        {
            "idx": "26",
            "question": "Qui était le Premier ministre britannique au début du XXIe siècle ?",
            "answer": "Tony Blair"
        },
        {
            "idx": "85",
            "question": "Quelle était la question principale abordée par la Cour suprême dans l'affaire historique Brown v. Board of Education ?",
            "answer": "La ségrégation scolaire"
        },
        {
            "idx": "195",
            "question": "Quelle est la plus haute décoration militaire décernée par le gouvernement américain ?",
            "answer": "La Médaille d'honneur"
        },
        {
            "idx": "200",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la célèbre tour d'horloge située à l'extrémité nord du palais de Westminster à Londres ?",
            "answer": "Big Ben"
        },
        {
            "idx": "65",
            "question": "Quelle est la plus ancienne université publique des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "L'Université de Caroline du Nord à Chapel Hill"
        },
        {
            "idx": "222",
            "question": "Qui était le monarque britannique lors de l'établissement de la Compagnie britannique des Indes orientales ?",
            "answer": "Reine Élisabeth Ire"
        },
        {
            "idx": "274",
            "question": "Quel monarque britannique a régné pendant l'ère victorienne ?",
            "answer": "Reine Victoria"
        },
        {
            "idx": "268",
            "question": "Qui était le président américain lors de l'établissement de l'Agence de protection de l'environnement ?",
            "answer": "Richard Nixon"
        },
        {
            "idx": "71",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la célèbre route américaine qui va de Chicago à Los Angeles ?",
            "answer": "Route 66"
        },
        {
            "idx": "143",
            "question": "Quelle est la ville la plus peuplée des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "New York"
        },
        {
            "idx": "17",
            "question": "Quel auteur britannique a écrit « 1984 » et « La Ferme des animaux » ?",
            "answer": "George Orwell"
        },
        {
            "idx": "50",
            "question": "Quelle université britannique est la plus ancienne du monde anglophone ?",
            "answer": "Université d'Oxford"
        },
        {
            "idx": "237",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre festival artistique organisé chaque année à Édimbourg ?",
            "answer": "Le Festival Fringe d'Édimbourg"
        },
        {
            "idx": "193",
            "question": "Quel document, signé en 1215, est connu comme la première constitution écrite de l'histoire européenne ?",
            "answer": "La Magna Carta"
        },
        {
            "idx": "40",
            "question": "Quelle est la plus longue rivière des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Rivière Missouri"
        },
        {
            "idx": "122",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du personnage d'espion britannique créé par Ian Fleming ?",
            "answer": "James Bond"
        },
        {
            "idx": "216",
            "question": "Quel comté britannique est connu sous le nom de « Propre pays de Dieu » ?",
            "answer": "Yorkshire"
        },
        {
            "idx": "234",
            "question": "Qui était le héros folklorique américain légendaire connu pour planter des pommiers ?",
            "answer": "Johnny Appleseed"
        },
        {
            "idx": "64",
            "question": "Qui était le Premier ministre britannique pendant la majeure partie de la Seconde Guerre mondiale ?",
            "answer": "Winston Churchill"
        },
        {
            "idx": "266",
            "question": "Quel festival américain est connu pour présenter des films indépendants ?",
            "answer": "Festival du film de Sundance"
        },
        {
            "idx": "272",
            "question": "Quel est le plat traditionnel du Sud des États-Unis du jour de l'An pour porter bonheur ?",
            "answer": "Haricots à œil noir"
        },
        {
            "idx": "167",
            "question": "Quel est le seul État américain à avoir un palais royal ?",
            "answer": "Hawaï (Palais ʻIolani)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "231",
            "question": "Dans quel État américain se trouve le Grand Canyon ?",
            "answer": "Arizona"
        },
        {
            "idx": "2",
            "question": "Quel est le plat traditionnel anglais impliquant de la viande hachée et de la purée de pommes de terre ?",
            "answer": "Hachis Parmentier"
        },
        {
            "idx": "262",
            "question": "Quel amendement a aboli la Prohibition aux États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Le 21e amendement"
        },
        {
            "idx": "99",
            "question": "Quel est le plus grand lac d'eau douce des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Lac Supérieur"
        },
        {
            "idx": "276",
            "question": "Quel président américain était connu sous le nom de « Grand Communicateur » ?",
            "answer": "Ronald Reagan"
        },
        {
            "idx": "204",
            "question": "Quel monarque britannique a établi l'Église d'Angleterre ?",
            "answer": "Roi Henri VIII"
        },
        {
            "idx": "181",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu sous le nom de « Premier État » ?",
            "answer": "Delaware"
        },
        {
            "idx": "72",
            "question": "Qui était le président américain lors de la signature de l'accord ALÉNA ?",
            "answer": "Bill Clinton"
        },
        {
            "idx": "119",
            "question": "Qui était le président américain pendant la crise des otages en Iran ?",
            "answer": "Jimmy Carter"
        },
        {
            "idx": "106",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du plus grand système fluvial des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Le système fluvial du Mississippi"
        },
        {
            "idx": "101",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est le berceau des Beatles ?",
            "answer": "Liverpool"
        },
        {
            "idx": "49",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du cimetière militaire américain en Virginie ?",
            "answer": "Cimetière national d'Arlington"
        },
        {
            "idx": "169",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la cérémonie britannique qui marque l'anniversaire officiel du souverain britannique ?",
            "answer": "Trooping the Colour"
        },
        {
            "idx": "89",
            "question": "Quelle bataille de 1066 a mené à la conquête normande de l'Angleterre ?",
            "answer": "La bataille de Hastings"
        },
        {
            "idx": "118",
            "question": "Quel auteur britannique a écrit la série « Harry Potter » ?",
            "answer": "J.K. Rowling"
        },
        {
            "idx": "63",
            "question": "Quelle décision historique la Cour suprême américaine a-t-elle prise dans Brown v. Board of Education ?",
            "answer": "Elle a déclaré inconstitutionnelles les lois d'État établissant des écoles publiques séparées pour les élèves noirs et blancs"
        },
        {
            "idx": "95",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est connue pour son rôle central dans la guerre civile anglaise ?",
            "answer": "York"
        },
        {
            "idx": "249",
            "question": "Quel président américain était connu pour son rôle dans la crise des missiles de Cuba ?",
            "answer": "John F. Kennedy"
        },
        {
            "idx": "253",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la plus haute cour d'appel du Royaume-Uni pour les affaires civiles, et pour les affaires pénales d'Angleterre, du pays de Galles et d'Irlande du Nord ?",
            "answer": "La Cour suprême du Royaume-Uni"
        },
        {
            "idx": "212",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est connue sous le nom de « Ville aux flèches de rêve » ?",
            "answer": "Oxford"
        },
        {
            "idx": "145",
            "question": "Quel célèbre monument était un cadeau des États-Unis de la France ?",
            "answer": "La Statue de la Liberté"
        },
        {
            "idx": "176",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre canyon américain en Arizona ?",
            "answer": "Grand Canyon"
        },
        {
            "idx": "287",
            "question": "Quel dessert britannique est traditionnellement servi avec de la crème anglaise ?",
            "answer": "Spotted dick"
        },
        {
            "idx": "52",
            "question": "Quel pont londonien est souvent confondu avec London Bridge par les touristes ?",
            "answer": "Tower Bridge"
        },
        {
            "idx": "261",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la base navale américaine attaquée en 1941, menant à l'implication américaine dans la Seconde Guerre mondiale ?",
            "answer": "Pearl Harbor"
        },
        {
            "idx": "194",
            "question": "Qui était le premier président américain à nommer une femme à la Cour suprême ?",
            "answer": "Ronald Reagan (Sandra Day O'Connor)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "160",
            "question": "Quelle était la bataille importante de la Révolution américaine menée en 1775 ?",
            "answer": "La bataille de Bunker Hill"
        },
        {
            "idx": "47",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de l'hymne national des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "The Star-Spangled Banner"
        },
        {
            "idx": "230",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du plus grand désert des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Le désert de Mojave"
        },
        {
            "idx": "201",
            "question": "Qui était la reine d'Angleterre lors de l'établissement des colonies anglaises en Amérique ?",
            "answer": "Reine Élisabeth Ire"
        },
        {
            "idx": "114",
            "question": "Quel État américain a été le premier à légaliser le mariage homosexuel ?",
            "answer": "Massachusetts"
        },
        {
            "idx": "70",
            "question": "Quel État américain a été le premier à ratifier la Constitution ?",
            "answer": "Delaware"
        },
        {
            "idx": "187",
            "question": "Quel président est crédité de la Proclamation d'émancipation ?",
            "answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
        },
        {
            "idx": "251",
            "question": "Quel est le plat britannique traditionnel fait de sang de porc, d'avoine et d'épices ?",
            "answer": "Boudin noir"
        },
        {
            "idx": "111",
            "question": "Quel roi anglais a été vaincu à la bataille de Hastings ?",
            "answer": "Roi Harold II"
        },
        {
            "idx": "282",
            "question": "Qui était le premier président américain à vivre à la Maison Blanche ?",
            "answer": "John Adams"
        },
        {
            "idx": "18",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du traité qui a mis fin à la guerre d'indépendance américaine ?",
            "answer": "Le Traité de Paris, 1783"
        },
        {
            "idx": "53",
            "question": "Quel monument américain honore quatre présidents américains sculptés dans une montagne ?",
            "answer": "Mont Rushmore"
        },
        {
            "idx": "109",
            "question": "Quel est le plus grand État des États-Unis par superficie ?",
            "answer": "Alaska"
        },
        {
            "idx": "174",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la tourte britannique traditionnelle garnie de viande hachée et de purée de pommes de terre ?",
            "answer": "Cottage Pie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "128",
            "question": "Quel événement mondial majeur les États-Unis ont-ils rejoint en 1941 ?",
            "answer": "Seconde Guerre mondiale"
        },
        {
            "idx": "150",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la première colonie américaine à déclarer son indépendance de la Grande-Bretagne ?",
            "answer": "Rhode Island"
        },
        {
            "idx": "161",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu comme le berceau de l'aviation ?",
            "answer": "Ohio"
        },
        {
            "idx": "178",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est célèbre pour ses tramways historiques ?",
            "answer": "San Francisco, Californie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "208",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu pour sa grande population amish ?",
            "answer": "Pennsylvanie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "68",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre parc national américain avec des geysers dans le Wyoming ?",
            "answer": "Parc national de Yellowstone"
        },
        {
            "idx": "138",
            "question": "Quel est le plus haut bâtiment des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "One World Trade Center"
        },
        {
            "idx": "55",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est célèbre pour sa pizza deep-dish ?",
            "answer": "Chicago"
        },
        {
            "idx": "87",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la résidence du Premier ministre britannique ?",
            "answer": "10 Downing Street"
        },
        {
            "idx": "248",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est connue comme le berceau de la marine américaine ?",
            "answer": "Philadelphie, Pennsylvanie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "288",
            "question": "Quelle est la plus longue rivière du Royaume-Uni ?",
            "answer": "La rivière Severn"
        },
        {
            "idx": "12",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est connue pour son rôle important dans l'industrie automobile américaine ?",
            "answer": "Detroit, Michigan"
        },
        {
            "idx": "31",
            "question": "Quel monument américain est connu sous le nom de « Forteresse de l'Amérique » ?",
            "answer": "Fort Knox"
        },
        {
            "idx": "154",
            "question": "Quel fromage britannique est traditionnellement utilisé dans un ploughman's lunch ?",
            "answer": "Cheddar"
        },
        {
            "idx": "213",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique a été célèbrement bombardée pendant le Blitz de la Seconde Guerre mondiale ?",
            "answer": "Londres"
        },
        {
            "idx": "134",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la tradition britannique de boire du thé en fin d'après-midi, généralement accompagné de sandwichs ou de pâtisseries ?",
            "answer": "Thé de l'après-midi"
        },
        {
            "idx": "189",
            "question": "Quel président américain est associé à la phrase « La seule chose que nous ayons à craindre est la peur elle-même » ?",
            "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "idx": "129",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu pour sa production laitière et est souvent appelé « Laiterie de l'Amérique » ?",
            "answer": "Wisconsin"
        },
        {
            "idx": "35",
            "question": "Qui était le président américain lors de l'achat de la Louisiane ?",
            "answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "86",
            "question": "Quel monarque britannique est associé à l'Âge d'or de l'histoire anglaise ?",
            "answer": "Reine Élisabeth Ire"
        },
        {
            "idx": "105",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de l'officier de marine britannique connu pour ses victoires contre Napoléon pendant les guerres napoléoniennes ?",
            "answer": "Amiral Lord Nelson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "84",
            "question": "Qui était le premier président américain à être mis en accusation ?",
            "answer": "Andrew Johnson"
        },
        {
            "idx": "88",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu sous le nom d'« État du soleil » ?",
            "answer": "Floride"
        },
        {
            "idx": "91",
            "question": "Quel groupe britannique a mené l'invasion britannique des hit-parades musicaux américains dans les années 1960 ?",
            "answer": "Les Beatles"
        },
        {
            "idx": "218",
            "question": "Qui était le leader des droits civiques américain assassiné en 1968 ?",
            "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
        },
        {
            "idx": "281",
            "question": "Quelle est la capitale du Texas ?",
            "answer": "Austin"
        },
        {
            "idx": "283",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine a été la première à utiliser un système de métro ?",
            "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts"
        },
        {
            "idx": "56",
            "question": "Quel est le surnom de New York ?",
            "answer": "La Grosse Pomme"
        },
        {
            "idx": "74",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la célèbre route connue sous le nom de « Route mère » ?",
            "answer": "Route 66"
        },
        {
            "idx": "199",
            "question": "Quelle était la première colonie anglaise permanente en Amérique du Nord ?",
            "answer": "Jamestown, Virginie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "172",
            "question": "Qui était le monarque britannique pendant la guerre des Malouines ?",
            "answer": "Reine Élisabeth II"
        },
        {
            "idx": "260",
            "question": "Quelle était la cause principale de la guerre civile américaine ?",
            "answer": "L'esclavage et les droits des États"
        },
        {
            "idx": "136",
            "question": "Quel monument américain porte l'inscription « Donnez-moi vos fatigués, vos pauvres, vos masses entassées aspirant à respirer librement » ?",
            "answer": "La Statue de la Liberté"
        },
        {
            "idx": "155",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du célèbre leader des droits civiques américain qui a prononcé le discours « J'ai un rêve » ?",
            "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
        },
        {
            "idx": "120",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est historiquement connue pour son industrie de construction navale ?",
            "answer": "Glasgow"
        },
        {
            "idx": "217",
            "question": "Quel document a officiellement mis fin à l'esclavage aux États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Le 13e amendement"
        },
        {
            "idx": "6",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est connue pour son université historique et comme emplacement de la Radcliffe Camera ?",
            "answer": "Oxford"
        },
        {
            "idx": "10",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu pour ses pommes de terre ?",
            "answer": "Idaho"
        },
        {
            "idx": "22",
            "question": "Qui est connu comme le « Père des parcs nationaux » en Amérique ?",
            "answer": "John Muir"
        },
        {
            "idx": "258",
            "question": "Quelle pièce britannique présente un chardon, un poireau et un trèfle ?",
            "answer": "Pièce d'une livre"
        },
        {
            "idx": "126",
            "question": "Qui était le premier Afro-Américain à servir comme secrétaire d'État américain ?",
            "answer": "Colin Powell"
        },
        {
            "idx": "270",
            "question": "Quel est le nom de la célèbre bourse américaine de New York ?",
            "answer": "Bourse de New York (NYSE)"
        },
        {
            "idx": "77",
            "question": "Quel est le plus petit État américain par superficie ?",
            "answer": "Rhode Island"
        },
        {
            "idx": "112",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est célèbre pour sa production d'acier ?",
            "answer": "Sheffield"
        },
        {
            "idx": "156",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu pour son histoire et sa culture amérindiennes importantes ?",
            "answer": "Nouveau-Mexique"
        },
        {
            "idx": "66",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est connue sous le nom de Ville venteuse ?",
            "answer": "Chicago, Illinois"
        },
        {
            "idx": "67",
            "question": "Quelle ville britannique est connue pour son rôle central dans la révolution industrielle ?",
            "answer": "Manchester"
        },
        {
            "idx": "254",
            "question": "Quel est le nom du vaisseau spatial qui a d'abord fait atterrir des humains sur la Lune ?",
            "answer": "Apollo 11"
        },
        {
            "idx": "121",
            "question": "Quel est le plus grand lac d'Angleterre ?",
            "answer": "Windermere"
        },
        {
            "idx": "246",
            "question": "Qui était le deuxième président des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "John Adams"
        },
        {
            "idx": "94",
            "question": "Quel monarque britannique avait le plus long règne avant la reine Élisabeth II ?",
            "answer": "Reine Victoria"
        },
        {
            "idx": "265",
            "question": "Quel président américain a initié le projet qui a mené à la création d'Internet ?",
            "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower"
        },
        {
            "idx": "152",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu pour ses îles volcaniques ?",
            "answer": "Hawaï"
        },
        {
            "idx": "76",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine était la première capitale des États-Unis ?",
            "answer": "Philadelphie, Pennsylvanie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "157",
            "question": "Qui était la première femme astronaute britannique ?",
            "answer": "Helen Sharman"
        },
        {
            "idx": "163",
            "question": "Quel monarque britannique a succédé à la reine Victoria ?",
            "answer": "Roi Édouard VII"
        },
        {
            "idx": "24",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine est connue comme le berceau de la musique jazz ?",
            "answer": "La Nouvelle-Orléans"
        },
        {
            "idx": "57",
            "question": "Quel État américain est connu pour produire le plus de maïs ?",
            "answer": "Iowa"
        },
        {
            "idx": "28",
            "question": "Quel scientifique britannique a développé la théorie de l'évolution ?",
            "answer": "Charles Darwin"
        },
        {
            "idx": "92",
            "question": "Quelle est la résidence officielle londonienne de la Reine ?",
            "answer": "Palais de Buckingham"
        },
        {
            "idx": "177",
            "question": "Quelle ville américaine a accueilli les Jeux olympiques d'été de 1984 ?",
            "answer": "Los Angeles, Californie"
        },
        {
            "idx": "4",
            "question": "Quel physicien britannique est connu pour son travail sur les trous noirs ?",
            "answer": "Stephen Hawking"
        }
    ]
}